<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<string_table>

<!--meet guide second time -->
<!-- follow guide -->

	<string id="dam_guide_before_route_1">
		<text>Strelok, you seem well. Never a moment's rest I see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_before_route_11">
		<text>It's good to see you again, I am glad you decided to lend a hand!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_before_route_111">
		<text>Yes... well, Ghost was convincing enough... I assume you were informed about the Military blockade around Pripyat? Even though I can survive the harshest conditions the Zone can unleash without worries, I must concede that being laden with lead will end me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_before_route_1111">
		<text>But you know a way past the surface, through the underground tunnels?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_before_route_11111">
		<text>Yes. It is a route that we used to travel North to the ghost city... but the psy-emissions of the Scorcher boosted after our third trip. The tunnels were then flooded with deadly psy-emissions where no normal man can survive. But now, I sense it is clear of such dangers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_before_route_111111">
		<text>I don't remember any of this clearly. My memories are still slowly coming back to me, one by one. Nothing is really clear... Anyhow, what's the plan?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_before_route_1111111">
		<text>There is a system of natural and unnatural tunnels that will lead you from here to the center of Pripyat. They have long been unused. Many mutants nest in the darkness, waiting for a easy prey.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_before_route_11111111">
		<text>You'll take me there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_before_route_111111111">
		<text>Alas I can only take you to the entrance of the tunnel system, that's where I will depart. There are many stalkers that require my help navigating the Zone. I won't let them be victims of foolish deaths due to inexperience. Stay close brother, there are strange anomalies everywhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_before_route_1111111111">
		<text>Let's not waste any time then.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- move to pripyat -->
	
	<string id="dam_guide_cave_entrance_1">
		<text>This is the place, the entrance to the tunnels. This is where I get off; the way forward is for you to figure out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_cave_entrance_11">
		<text>I appreciate the help. What can you tell me about the tunnels?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_cave_entrance_111">
		<text>The tunnel system is vast - Daedalus' labyrinth. Keep track of your surroundings, move wisely, and reach the underground railway. Once you see the tracks, you're on the right path.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_cave_entrance_1111">
		<text>Won't be a walk in the park, but I'll do it. There's no other way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_cave_entrance_11111">
		<text>Indeed there isn't. Remember to trust your instincts; they are your closest friend.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_cave_entrance_111111">
		<text>Thanks again Guide.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_cave_entrance_3">
		<text>My pleasure. But be careful Strelok, I feel as if a great horror awaits in your near future. Be safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_guide_cave_entrance_31">
		<text>I will.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>