	<!--Generic-->	
	
	<string id="trader_message_header">
		<text>Message from Sidorovich:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_message_header">
        <text>Message from Barkeep:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="veronin_message_header">
		<text>Message from Voronin:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petrenko_message_header">
		<text>Message from Petrenko:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_message_header">
		<text>Message from Doc:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ghost_message_header">
		<text>Message from Ghost:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_message_header">
		<text>Message from military:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mercs_message_header">
		<text>Message from Mercs:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_message_header">
		<text>Message from scientists:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_message_header">
		<text>Message from a stalker:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_header">
		<text>Info from the found PDA:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientist_dead_header">
		<text>Info from the scientist's PDA:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hijacked_message">
		<text>Message intercepted:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unknown_message_header">
		<text>Message from unknown:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sos_signal_header">
		<text>SOS signal received:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_af_merger_caption">
		<text>Artifact merger:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_af_merger_succeed">
		<text>Artifact spawned!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_af_merger_failed">
		<text>Half product spawned!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_af_merger_worn_out">
		<text>Artifact worn out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_af_merger_recharged">
		<text>Fully recharged, ready for next transmutation!</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Military checkpoints aka blockposts-->
	
	<string id="cordon_gar_military_blokpost_warning">
		<text>Stalker, you are in military territory, keep on the road and you will be safe, wander off the path and you will meet your maker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_gar_military_blokpost_warning_been">
		<text>You remember the rules stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_military_blokpost_warning">
		<text>You have no business here stalker! This is military territory, keep on the road and move along quickly and you will live!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_military_blokpost_warning_been">
		<text>Remember the rules stalker, and stick to them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_military_blokpost_ending">
		<text>You chose wisely stalker, good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_military_blokpost_warning">
		<text>You are in military territory stalker, stick to the road and all will be fine, you have ten seconds to comply!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_military_blokpost_warning_been">
		<text>You know the drill stalker, stick to the road!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_military_blokpost_fight">
		<text>You were warned stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_military_blokpost_warning">
		<text>You are in military territory stalker, stick to the road and all will be fine, you have thirty seconds to comply!</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Escape aka Cordon-->
	
	<string id="esc_madog_stuff_help">
		<text>And now try to find the second contact and retrieve his possessions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_anomaly_warning">
		<text>Be extremely careful near anomalies. As soon as you see something unusual, grab your bolts and toss them in front of you. Now, go get me that artifact!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_clear_factory_message">
		<text>Guys, I heard gunshots from the factory, seems there is a big mess, it's better to stay away from this place for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_factory_tip">
		<text>It's time to kick some asses! Marked One, go go go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sin_message_header">
		<text>Message from a Sin member:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sin_warning1">
		<text>Be careful stalker. You are about to enter a world of the unknown!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sin_warning2">
		<text>Whoever you are out there, tread lightly and you might just survive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sin_warning3">
		<text>Who dare approach this area without invitation? You better come and have a chat!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sin_warning4">
		<text>This is not a place for the squeamish, if so then piss off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_to_sid">
		<text>And now let's talk about where to start.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kill_zombies_tip">
		<text>I need you to kill those zombies in the tunnel, Marked One. They cause problems for my trade network.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_trader_send_to_garb">
		<text>It was your lucky day Fox... Okay, Marked One, listen, I found out some more info about this Strelok character, so you have a choice. I'm waiting for you here in my hole, with your reward, and I have one more serious task for you, so you'd better come and talk to me. But if you are too lazy to return back to me, feel free to move towards the Garbage. I will send you more details when you arrive there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_trader_talk_to_fox">
		<text>It's me, your fellow trader. I've been told you dealt with these Sin freaks... tough but it's all right. Go speak to your new friend Fox - I bet he needs it badly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_blue_silhouette">
		<text>Blue Silhouette, if you are reading this, the zone has taken me. It is up to you to get back to our hiding place and take care of the stash. I changed the combination lock on the door, but I remember how much you like puzzles, so I updated the PDA's GPS tracker to play an audio message once you get close to 3 areas.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_red_fox1">
		<text>First number is 4.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_red_fox2">
		<text>Second number is 7.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_red_fox3">
		<text>Third number is 1.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_quest_header">
		<text>Part of the riddle is solved:</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="esc_sid_first_anomaly">
        <text>Just think about it man: next time it could be you in its place. Don't forget to use the bolts to locate anomalies, alrighty? Talk to you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_sid_heli_msg">
        <text>Don't go around dancing in front of the choppers. Sometimes choppers will shoot on site, stay in the the bushes and reeds, if you value your life.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="wolf_message_header">
        <text>Message from Wolf:</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_tip">
        <text>No need to fight here. Stay calm and try to talk with them.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_fail_tip">
        <text>It seems they won't let you pass. Try to find another way - or if you're really crazy, put 'em on ice. Rambo wannabe.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_trader_tip">
        <text>I suggest you stay away from this bridge, Marked One, at least until you help one of my mates. These guys don't welcome anyone here.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_trader_fail_tip">
        <text>You heard what I said, right!? Ok, deal with consequences on your own.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="cordon_case_task_day">
        <text>Marked One, why did you go there during the daytime? Quick, get out of there!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_case_task_return">
        <text>Marked One, you got away from the route, you can get spotted! Go along the fence, then get through the barracks window. Do it quick but without any noise.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_case_task_good">
        <text>Excellent! Now get through the window and use it on you way out too. Remember: don't make any noise!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_case_task_fail_day">
		<text>Why didn't you leave before the daylight? It's all on you now; consider me stranger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_case_task_fail">
        <text>I told you that you had to sneak in during nighttime without getting spotted! Now you are knee deep in the shit, deal with this yourself! Bye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_case_task_fail2">
        <text>Why in the world are you walking around the blockpost as if it was a park? You had to sneak in and out, and what have you done? Now deal with this crap yourself! Bye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_case_task_atack">
        <text>Attention everyone! We have a hostile on the territory of the outpost!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_case_task_return2">
        <text>Marked One, you got away from the route and can be spotted! Go back to same route we talked about.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cordon_case_task_torch">
        <text>Your flashlight is seen even from the village! Turn it off, unless you want them to see you.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Garbage-->	
	
	<string id="gar_trader_message">
		<text>So you chose the easy way... Lazy One, not Marked! Anyway, listen: there is a stalker out there that goes by that name; some say he found a way to the North - which we, traders, have been seeking ever since we arrived here. I'd like to find out how he got there myself - along with Barkeep and others. Not sure if you will find your Strelok, but there still is a chance... try your best, Marked One! And yeah, I promised to give you some info on how to find him; meet Seriy at the Garbage - he might happen to tell you more in this regard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bes_call_for_help">
		<text>Hey, stalker! Need your assistance with an urgent problem. Help and I'll return the favor. Get to the abandoned cranes and let's talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bes_msg_header">
		<text>Message from Bes:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bes_message">
		<text>Wow, you had some major balls working for ya! I won't forget this. Come and see me as soon as possible. I got a reward for you. It's no slice of cake, but it will do. Bes, out.</text>  <!--later in the green house nearby,-->
	</string>
	<string id="gar_kill_boars_header">
		<text>Message from the Duty checkpoint:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_kill_boars_message">
		<text>Hello, the Duty faction is speaking from the Garbage. There's a wave of mutants going from the Dark Valley towards the bar. We guarantee our gratitude to all who will help kill off the scum. On the word of the Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dm_sos_message">
        <text>SOS!!! Stalkers!!! I am on the road near the landfill on the left from the pump station. Life and death situation!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_sos_message">
        <text>We need help to get control of the hangar. Please, if you're reading this message, help us!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_sos_header">
		<text>Message from Seriy:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_assault_message">
		<text>MOVE IN!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seriy_could_fail">
		<text>Don't be stupid, stalker! You will ruin the surprise attack!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_sniper_done">
        <text>Wow, you got balls stalker! I won't forget this. Come and see me later, I have something for you as a sign of my appreciation. Bes, out.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_sin_veronin_text">
		<text>Voronin here. The negotiations failed? Did he bring the discs with him? Wait, he had only one? Damn it, there are two! Both discs contained important information about our bases, stashes and tactical plans. They can't stay in the hands of Sin, we need to strike back and quick! Talk to my agent, I'll mark him on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_sin_veronin_text_fail">
		<text>Voronin here. The negotiations failed? Did he bring the discs with him? Check his body, there are two discs that contained important information about our bases, stashes and tactical plans. They can't stay in the hands of Sin. If he doesn't have both discs, we need to strike back and quick! Talk to my agent, I'll mark him on your map.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Agroprom-->
	
	<string id="agr_mole_invitation">
		<text>Hey, Marked One, this is Mole. We have made camp in the railroad tunnel here in Agroprom. Feel free to drop in anytime. Mole out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mole_message_header">
		<text>Message from Mole:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_tip">
		<text>Eliminate all military, it's still not safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_mole_dead_info">
		<text>There's a stash underground that once belonged to Strelok. I couldn't recover it because of the mutants down there, but I've written it down...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mole_dead_header">
		<text>Info from Mole's PDA:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_gunslinger_flash_doc">
		<text>The flash drive has the name "DOC" inscribed on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_agr_krot_sos">
		<text>Help! If anyone can hear me! The military got us pinned at the factory!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_agr_krot_sos1">
		<text>The pigs have got me cornered in the yard. Help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_agr_krot_sos2">
		<text>All my men are down!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_agr_trader_documents">
		<text>Ratcatcher told me you were heading to the base for the documents, bring them to me... and I will grant you access to the bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_docs_task_start_tip">
		<text>Marked One, since you're already at the Agroprom, look for some papers: I have a feeling military didn't put all of the documents into the case you brought. And don't forget to pay me a visit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_ratcatcher_message">
		<text>Marked One, Mole told me that you were looking for information about Strelok. Seeing as you are in Agroprom, please can you help a friend of mine - and I'll see what I can dig up for you. I will send you his last known coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Darkdolina aka Dark Valley-->
	
	<string id="dol_bandit_header">
		<text>Message from bandits:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_actor_stole_items">
		<text>What the hell are you doing? Little chief... Stay where you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_actor_dynamit">
		<text>Put the dynamite where you took it, asshole.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_actor_re_rob">
		<text>Now I will rob your ass blind, asshole. Come here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_actor_attacked_guard">
		<text>We were robbed guys, take this bitch down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_actor_key_stole">
		<text>He stole the cell key, take him down!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_actor_key_stole1">
		<text>He stolen the key from the cell!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_actor_trader_stole_items">
		<text>Here some insolent fucker trying to steal my meal, take him down!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_trader_bastards_steal">
		<text>Some kind of bitch stole my meal again, i will catch you one day, imbecile parasite.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_drunken_dead_key">
		<text>Borov doesn't let us to write down the word... I need to stop drinking... "pizdec"! Right! Now I won't have any troubles with these crazy guys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_drunken_dead_key_header">
		<text>Info from a bandit's PDA:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_gusarov_message">
		<text>Marked One, Gusarov here. Since you know the pass to the Monolith base, they will let you in, maybe pretend you are a little drunk! You should go there now and meet my contact as soon as possible. He personally owes me. I'll mark it on your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_gusarov_message_header">
		<text>Message from Oleg Gusarov:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_gusarov_message_fail">
		<text>Since you were uncovered I guess the only way for you to get docs is to rely on my own intel, I will mark their location in your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_army_gus_msg">
		<text>Dang! The Army decided to wipe out the Monolithians from the factory! You should get the hell out of there now! Try to steal some means of transportation! And head to Darkscape, there's gotta be a place to hide there!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_borov_code">
		<text>Note to self: code to the safe is 2-9-5.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_prisoner_message">
		<text>Marked One, Petrenko here, I had an operative of mine disappear. He hasn't contacted us for a very long time and rumor is he is being held captive by bandits. I can still pick up his PDA on my tracker so please, I will give you the PDA signal and see if you can track it and find him. But beware, helping him may make the locals hostile towards you.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Rostok Factory-->
	
	<string id="rosf_meet_duty">
		<text>Marked One, go and meet the Duty guys in the village, they need help with a mutant problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_safe_code">
		<text>Code to the safe in Rostok factory is 4-3-7.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_find_pda2">
		<text>Try looking in the gas-filled building if you're struggling to find the PDAs. Don't forget to wear your gas mask!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dima_message_header">
		<text>Message from Dima:</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Secret Lab aka X-14-->
	
	<string id="secret_pda_message">
		<text>Code to the door is 4526.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Darklab aka X-18-->
		
	<string id="dar_petrenko_documents">
		<text>So you finally got there, Marked One. Look around, maybe you will find some useful documents in this lab for me and Barman. Petrenko, out.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Darkscape-->
	
	<string id="ds_to_darklab_code_message">
		<text>Marked One, it's Voronin. Thanks for your help. I have good news: in our archives, we found the code to the underground lab which probably you wanna visit - 5271. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_veronin_jantar_message">
		<text>Hey, it's Voronin. The Ecologists on Yantar need some professional help, and I thought you'd be interested. Go and talk to Sakharov, he can give you some work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_petrenko_advice">
		<text>Marked One, Petrenko here. I don't recommend you go deeper into the mines. You pissed off Sin really bad by killing their comrades in Cordon. Voronin can help you with that if you join Duty, or alternatively go speak to Barkeep, he has a way of easing such situations... for a price of course. Visit one of them as soon as you can before you get yourself killed. While you are still in the area, try to get to the lab as originally planned.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_not_safe">
		<text>It is not safe in the open, find a route through the mines.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="veles_message_header">
		<text>Message from Veles:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dark_sin_pc_undegrounds_info">
		<text>Looks like the Bandits found you out, haha! While you are there, go and find us more interesting data in the underground lab. Try to find the admin's PC - it should have the most interesting information. If it has a password then look around for any bodies and check their PDA's, you might get lucky. To get in you'll need a code - 5271. Oh, and try not to screw it up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dark_sin_v_pc_undegrounds_info">
		<text>Not bad, stalker. Seems like you figured this task out just fine and didn't even reveal yourself! While you are there, go and find us more interesting data in the underground lab. Try to find the admin's PC - it should have the most interesting information. If it has a password then look around for any bodies and check their PDA's, you might get lucky. To get in you'll need a code - 5271. And yes, get out of the base now, while you aren't burned.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Yantar-->
	
	<string id="yan_eco_warn">
		<text>This area is off limits, if you want to enter you have to convince me first!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_sakh_pda_message">
		<text>Strelok, I've finished with your PDA, come and see me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_sakharov_talk_message">
		<text>Marked One, the Ecologists in Yantar need someone who is good enough to help them with a problem and I thought of you. Go and talk to Sakharov, you will be rewarded for this, plus maybe they can help you to fix your PDA, which will might help you to remember more about your past.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_fort_warn">
		<text>This area is off limits stalker, you have no business being here and I suggest you leave immediately!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_fort_second_warn">
		<text>I told you this area is off limits stalker, so buzz off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_help_bar_duty">
		<text>Duty at bar have been attacked by Mercs, we request your assistance!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_talk_to_rifle_dude_tip">
		<text>Hey dude, could you help me with something? I'm nearby - I've marked my location on your map.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Bar-Rostok-->
	
	<string id="bar_rpg_tip">
		<text>Marked One, if you run out of rockets search around the area: I know Arnie had quite a few with him. If you are really desperate, come and see me and I will see what the boys can dig up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_hunter_message">
		<text>Hi Marked One. I was lucky enough to escape to the bar in Pripyat's outskirts. Come and see me there, if you still want to do me that favor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_message_header">
		<text>Message from Hunter:</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Forgotten aka Construction Site-->	
	
	<string id="forg_merc_message">
		<text>This is Merc territory, stranger. Report immediately to one of the sentries to verify your pass. Do not enter the compound without authorization or you will be shot on sight!</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Arena-->
	
	<string id="bar_arena_actor_afraid">
		<text>The fight is off! The challenger got cold feet and didn't come out to fight at all!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_10">
		<text>10 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_20">
		<text>20 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_30">
		<text>30 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_40">
		<text>40 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_50">
		<text>50 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_60">
		<text>1 minute into the fight!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_70">
		<text>1 minute and 10 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_80">
		<text>1 minute and 20 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_90">
		<text>1 minute and 30 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_begin">
		<text>The fight has started!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_bloodsucker">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena! In the left corner - the Zone's most dreaded nightmare, the ever-hungry Bloodsucker! And in the right corner... A man? Yes, it's a man! Your applause please for the Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_burer">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena! In the left corner - the spoon-bending kung-fu master himself - the Burer! And in the right corner - the man constantly on the lookout! They call him the Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_dead">
		<text>So, the challenger has been killed! Now there's a surprise!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_lose">
		<text>Well, the challenger killed his opponent, but he didn't do it in time. He loses the fight!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_dogs">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena. In the left corner - they're angry, skinned and smells disgusting... Blind dogs! And in the right corner - he came from nowhere and that's precisely where he's headed. They call him the Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_pseudodog">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena. In the left corner - it's white, it's fluffy and it's pissed off like hell... The Pseudodog! And in the right corner - quite ragged, but still alive and mature, a man who calls himself a Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_savage">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena. In the left corner - you know him, you love him, and he hates you right back! It's the Beast! And in the right corner - alive and kicking, at least for the moment - the Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_snork">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena! In the left corner - the martial arts guru and health specialist - the Snork! And in the right corner - the man with no past and no future. They call him the Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_timeout">
		<text>The time's up! The challenger lost, but he's still fighting for his life!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_victory">
		<text>Ho! The challenger killed his opponent in time! He wins!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arena_message_header">
		<text>Arena:</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Basement aka X-7-->
	
	<string id="tips_bas_dont_shoot_holo">
		<text>Don't try to shoot holograms: they send neuro-impulses directly to your brain, and cutting this stream will kill you. Run away!</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Deadcity-->
	
	<string id="cit_mercs_message">
		<text>Stalker, one false move on a Merc's turf will get you a bullet in the head real quick; remember that. If you've got business with us, come by... slowly.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Military-->	
	
	<string id="st_mil_ghost_contacts_actor">
		<text>Hey. I'm near the east side, in the basement near the abandoned village. Try to get there alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_meet_fang_msg">
        <text>Message from Fang:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_meet_fang_msg_text">
        <text>Hi, I am at the secret hideout at the Military Warehouses. Meet me here urgently!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_base_down_bm_msg_text">
        <text>Hurry up: the military forces are going to drop their troops on this base. Get out of there!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_stalk_camp_msg_text">
        <text>Help anyone! Brothers! Our stalker camp in the village is under attack from bandits, anyone who can hear this!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_contact_msg_text">
        <text>Hi, I am on my way, meet me at the broken Moskvich!</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Forest-->	
	
	<string id="fore_killer_tip1">
        <text>What's that noise?! Take a quick look guys: there's someone nearby...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fore_killer_tip2">
        <text>Shoot him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fore_found_flash">
		<text>I believe there should also be a flash drive somewhere...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fore_sos_signal">
		<text>Guys, I need help here! I'm wounded! I can see some buildings here... find them and you'll find me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fore_sos_signal2">
		<text>Help, man, I'm dying here!..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fore_v_piz">
        <text>I need to find a way out of here...</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Radar-->
	
	<string id="rad_monolith_msg">
		<text>In the name of the Monolith, STOP! And approach slowly!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_heli_approaching">
		<text>Outpost two requesting help... Outpost two requesting help... The military are ready to clean this area, and their bitch is flying too high!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_nomad_run_away">
		<text>Hey, why are you still standing there?! Blowout approaching! You cannot hide from the blowout with the Monolith! In the small wooden house where my stolen belongings are, you will be safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nomad_message_header">
		<text>Message from Nomad:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_help_monolith_defend_front_line">
		<text>Outpost to Tango Zero... wave of mutants are approaching... requesting backup... I repeat, requesting backup.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_meet_veronin">
		<text>Good job Marked One! The guys are very pleased. Come and see me, we need to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_ghost_dead">
		<text>Strelok, it's Ghost. Pripyat is under military blockade, they are trying to smoke out the hiding Monolithians, so no one can enter the city at the moment. You need to find another way in. I'll wait for you in the hotel room. Go and see Guide, I convinced him to help us... he knows the Zone better than anyone else, you can find him near Radar in the dilapidated old hospital.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Bunker-->
		
	<string id="bun_scientist_code_msg">
		<text>The situation is getting worse here and things are uncertain. I've changed the code to the door, it is now 3823.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--North Hills, ex Country-->	
	
	<string id="count_major_poka">
        <text>I see you have your own road. Well, we'll manage without you. Now get out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_message_header">
		<text>Message from Griboyedov:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_find_lost_hermit">
		<text>You got lost stalker. I have marked myself on the map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hermit_message_header">
		<text>Message from Hermit:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_mutants">
        <text>Attention! The checkpoint is being attacked by a horde of wild boars!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_wave">
        <text>A huge wave of mutants on the horizon! Take your defensive positions! Stalker, help us to fight back!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_mutant2_tip">
		<text>That's not all, the rest of them are to the west.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_back">
        <text>Stalker! Get back in the position! We need cover.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Lost Factory-->
	
	<string id="lost_scan_message">
		<text>Stand in front of the camera for face recognition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lost_scanning_message">
		<text>Scanning DNA...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lost_scanned_clear">
		<text>Genetic sequence is confirmed, proceed to decontamination.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lab_hermit_meet">
		<text>Strelok, go and meet up with a Nomad at radar, he will help you with the situation there, I will mark his position on your map.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Lab X-16-->
	
	<string id="labx16_disable_get_out">
		<text>Good job Strelok... but get out of there now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="labx16_main_switcher">
		<text>Good job Gordon! Now all that is left is the primary switch in the control room.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Damned aka Pripyat Underground-->	
	
	<string id="dam_code">
		<text>Message to all personnel: the station entrance locking mechanism has been replaced, and the new code is 4134.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dam_code_header">
		<text>Info from the found documents:</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Pripyat-->
	
	<string id="pripyat_under_attack">
		<text>There is a big conflict between Military and Monolith here, keep your eyes and ears open for any danger!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_secret_trader_msg">
        <text>Message from a secret trader:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_secret_trader_msg_text">
        <text>I will be in the area for a short while!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_help_military">
		<text>Marked One, the Military is under attack from Monolith forces not far from your position. Hurry please, they are outnumbered and I fear the worst will happen!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_mil_contacts_actor">
		<text>Hey Marked One, this is Lieutenant Vasilev. Come and see me, I want to personally thank you for helping me and my men.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--ChNPP aka AES-->
	
	<string id="aes_dolg1_sar_details">
		<text>We found the entrance to the Sarcophagus. Follow the center road due West and hang a left after the second tall crane, here you will find a door. The code is 4237.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg_message_header">
		<text>Message from the Duty squad:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dudaev_mono_rpgs_msg">
		<text>Someone from these Monolithians who ambushed our helis has survived the attack! We need to get rid of the bastards to move on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dudaev_message_header">
		<text>Message from Dudaev:</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Sarcophagus aka Sarkofag-->
	
	<string id="zones_mystery_text">
		<text>You made it after all, stalker. You turned out to be much stronger than we initially thought. Well, the time for us to talk has come. Head towards the signal. We'll be waiting for you.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Generators-->
	
	<string id="gen_distraction">
		<text>Please hurry: I can't distract them forever, they will kill me!</text>
	</string>