<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- meet with merc guard -->
    
    <string id="cit_entrance_guard_0">
        <text>Halt, stalker! What's your business here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_entrance_guard_1">
        <text>Sakharov sent me. Here's the pass he gave me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_entrance_guard_2">
        <text>Hm, gimme that... Yeah, checks out. Move along.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_entrance_guard_3">
        <text>Good day then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_entrance_guard_4">
        <text>Hey, wait a sec. C'mere for a moment. Haven't I heard your voice before? Do I know you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_entrance_guard_5">
        <text>I... I certainly don't remember. Probably dejà vu on your part.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_entrance_guard_6">
        <text>Right. Whatever, move along, move along... The Captain has the package, go see him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_entrance_guard_7">
        <text>OK, sure.</text>
    </string>
    
<!-- meet with merc guard without yantar task -->
    
    <string id="cit_mercs_harsh_0">
        <text>What the hell are you snooping around for? Buzz off, idiot!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_mercs_harsh_1">
        <text>I'll be going now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_stairs_guard_dialog_0">
        <text>What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_stairs_guard_dialog_1">
        <text>Can I go through?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_stairs_guard_dialog_2">
        <text>This area is off-limits unless you've got business there. Be lucky you're still standing there in one piece, stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_stairs_guard_dialog_3">
        <text>I'll keep in mind.</text>
    </string>
    
<!-- meet sakharov informer -->
    
    <string id="cit_informer_dialog_0">
        <text>So you're the scientists' erand boy, huh?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_informer_dialog_1">
        <text>That's right. I don't fancy it, but I've got my reasons. Now, let's get down to business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_informer_dialog_2">
        <text>Hold on... Wait, you're - oh god, you're...! But you were gone for months!? Even that damn Doctor thought you were dead!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_informer_dialog_3">
        <text>What - what are you saying?</text>
    </string>
    
<!-- meet doc in prison -->
    
    <string id="cit_doctor_wait_0">
        <text>We've got to wait until the cavalry arrives and busts us out. Maybe you can fiddle around with your PDA while we wait. Read up about your old mates that you can't remember.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_doctor_wait_1">
        <text>Uhm, there's no info on here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_doctor_wait_2">
        <text>What are you saying? Give me that, I'll show you... Wait a minute, your PDA is broken. No wonder you're missing that information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_doctor_wait_3">
        <text>Oh right, how can we fix it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_doctor_wait_4">
        <text>Actually, Ghost was tipped off that some Merc named Mad Dog had a special Crystal artifact, so he was going to try to lift it from the Mercs. This special crystal can be used to fix up broken electronics, like your PDA. We can get to that when we're out of here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_doctor_wait_5">
        <text>I won't forget about it.</text>
    </string>
    
<!-- meet army soldier after military raid -->

    <string id="cit_army_harsh_0">
        <text>Don't think we're doing this because we want to stalker! Get out before we bury you along with the mercs!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_army_harsh_1">
        <text>Thanks for the advice.</text>
    </string>
    
<!-- meet colonel -->

    <string id="cit_colonel_help_0">
        <text>Strelok, things are a mess, but listen to me: the eggheads at Yantar were wondering what happened to you, but no worries, I'll send them a message to tell them everything is dandy. Do what you must, be careful out there and go back to them when you're done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_colonel_help_1">
        <text>Yeah, I'll get to that.</text>
    </string>
    
<!-- freedom -->

	<string id="cit_freedom_dlg_0">
        <text>Move along stalker, nothing to see here!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="cit_freedom_dlg_1">
        <text>Right, I`ll be on my way then...</text>
    </string>
	
</string_table>
