<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- yantar bunker guard -->

	<string id="yantar_gate_guard_talk_0">
		<text>What's your business here stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_gate_guard_talk_1">
		<text>I've been sent to help the scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_gate_guard_talk_11">
		<text>They sent you? Well, you don't look much like a trained professional! Oh well, you may pass, but watch your step stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_gate_guard_talk_111">
		<text>Thanks for the tip.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_gate_guard_talk_2">
		<text>Just wandering around, seeing the sights.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_gate_guard_talk_21">
		<text>Well piss off, this isn't a tourist destination. You're lucky we're told to be lax with you people near the eggheads.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_gate_guard_talk_211">
		<text>Alright then, see you.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Sakharov first meet -->
<!-- get package from merc in deadcity -->
	
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_1">	
		<text>Yes stalker, can I help you with anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_11">
		<text>Sidorovich sent me. He said you needed some work done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_111">
		<text>Ah yes, we have been expecting you Marked One. This assignment is very sensitive in nature, something I want to keep low profile if possible. I... made a deal with mercenaries so that they would acquire a certain package for me. I need you to go to their base in Deadcity and recover the package. You only have to pick it up and bring it back to me in one piece; they have already received their payment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_1111">
		<text>If I may, what sort of package is it? I'm not in the mood to deal with some brain-sucking parasite or anything of the like.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_11111">
		<text>No need to worry, it isn't a live specimen or organic at all. It's research material dug up from an old laboratory in the North. I can't say anything else. Bring it to me, and I will reward you well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_111111">
		<text>OK then, I'll be back with the package.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_0">
		<text>I am here about your package.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_2">
		<text>Do you have the package for me yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_21">
		<text>No, I'm still working on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_22">
		<text>Yes, here it is.</text>
	</string>

<!--Return the bad helmet to Sakharov-->

    <string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_return_0">
        <text>Hello, professor. I no longer need your prototype helmet, you can take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_return_1">
        <text>Even so... Are you sure you don't need it anymore?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_return_21">
        <text>Yes, I'm sure. Take it, and thank you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_return_22">
        <text>Although you know... I changed my mind. Maybe I'll need it later. I'll give it back later.</text>
    </string>
	
<!-- get wiring to fix your the pda -->

	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_221">
		<text>Thank you, this means a lot to us. With what the mercenaries did, I won't ever make any deals with them again. Even if the package was worth the trouble. I don't think the Army will appreciate any transactions with them anymore. Not to mention they took the Doctor prisoner... And from what I've heard, you're a friend of his. Lucky coincidence I guess? Anyhow, I've heard that your PDA is damaged. I can repair it for you, but I'll need a few things to get it going again. First is new wiring. There is an entrance to an underground lab nearby; try looking around there for some in the storerooms. That's your best bet. Bring some back to me and then I'll tell you what else I need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_2211">
		<text>OK, I will go right away!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_30">
		<text>About the new wiring you asked for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_3">
		<text>Do you have the new wiring for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_31">
		<text>No, not yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_311">
		<text>Do remember, I can't fix this PDA without it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_3111">
		<text>Alright, I'm on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_32">
		<text>Yes, here it is.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Nimble: find SSP-100M (talk to Sakharov) -->

	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_sugar_0">
		<text>Could you tell me, professor, have you heard about the suits that were designed before the first blowout in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_sugar_1">
		<text>Indeed, I've already been gathering info on that for quite a time. The ecolog suits that we use now were developed on the base of blueprints that I found in some "secret" archives. But I haven't seen a single one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_sugar_2">
		<text>But there is a probability that these suits can be found here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_sugar_3">
		<text>There is, but I doubt that. I think that everything was already moved out. Maybe they left something over in a rush, but that probability is small.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_sugar_4">
		<text>I'd try to find it, if I knew where to start.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_sugar_5">
		<text>Have you been in the underground facilities, the ones under the lake? There's so much there laying around, but nobody have the guts to go there. A creepy place, you know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_sugar_6">
		<text>I'll push my luck. Well, thanks a lot.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Sakharov: working brain -->

	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_brain_0">
		<text>Professor, I urgently need your help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_brain_1">
		<text>What happened?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_brain_2">
		<text>The brain in the laboratory! It's still working... my head hurts so much!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_brain_3">
		<text>So, calm down and tell me everything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_brain_4">
		<text>I was in the lake underground and in one room I saw a huge brain in a tank. As I came closer to it my head was pierced with pain, then I passed out and couldn't even remember how I got out of that room.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_brain_5">
		<text>Yes... Psi-emitters. I know much of it. I can help you to protect yourself from the psi-rays, if you're interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_brain_6">
		<text>Yeah, of course I am: I have to get through, but that brain blocks the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_brain_7">
		<text>Then take this helm and this measurement device. The helm help you to hold for sometime around the brain to measure the wave frequency of a psi rays. After the measurement I can configure the helm to provide full protection from rays.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_brain_8a">
		<text>Thank you for help, professor!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_brain_8b">
		<text>Well, I already have such device, so yours is not needed. Thank you for help anyway, professor!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_helm_0">
		<text>Done all the measurements. Wasn't easy and I was hit by the psi attack again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_helm_1">
		<text>Emissions of each brain are individual, so you can't design a helm that would protect from every psi emitter. This is why the first version of the helm didn't help much. Let me tweak the parameters...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_helm_2">
		<text>Will it help me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_helm_3">
		<text>Sure: you've done the measurements, didn't you? Here, it's ready. Now the protection should suffice to get you through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_helm_4">
		<text>Thanks a bunch, professor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_helm_5">
		<text>You're welcome.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Sakharov: about the old documents -->

    <string id="yan_saharov_about_0">
		<text>Professor, I'm looking for something here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_about_1">
		<text>Yeah, I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_about_2">
		<text>The old docs which the Yantar facility workers may have left here. Is it possible to find anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_about_3">
		<text>Well, probably: they ran a lot of experiment here. And I already have some docs: I look for such documentation, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_about_4">
		<text>Any thoughts on the search direction? And could you show me your part of these?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_about_5">
		<text>You can look anywhere: there were lots of facilities and laboratories here. Actually, let's do it that way: I'll send a group of researchers with you to explore the places where the documents may have been left. You'll also need to bring all the electronics you find: recorders, measurement devices and other tiny things. And when you return, I'll make a copy of the documents I have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_about_6">
		<text>Well, sounds like a good deal. Let's get to it then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_about_7">
		<text>Discuss it with professor Pirozhenko: he'll be the expedition leader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_about_8">
		<text>Alright. I shall go now. Thank you for the help!</text>
	</string>

<!-- meet with doc on swamp -->
<!-- get circuit boards to fix your pda -->
<!-- get artefact to fix your pda -->
<!-- after task finished bar attacked by merc -->

	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_321">
		<text>Ah, very good, not even a scratch on them. OK then, the next thing we need is new circuit boards, and I know where we can get some in mint condition. I was just in contact with Doc, and it appears he has some for us. He would also like to discuss other matters with you too. He told me that he would be waiting for you in his house in the Great Swamp. You'll have to be careful though, there is a Military helicopter on patrol at the moment, and they are quite trigger happy. They'll shoot anything that moves. Just move through the reeds so they won't see you. I'll try to contact the helicopter to tell them of your arrival and not to shoot, good luck stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_3211">
		<text>I'll go right away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_40">
		<text>Here is my PDA, can you fix it now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_4">
		<text>Do you have the circuit boards for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_41">
		<text>Yes, here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_411">
		<text>OK good, we can begin repairs on the PDA. Did Doc mention that we needed a special Crystal artifact too?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_4111">
		<text>Yes, feels like I've been to hell and back trying to find it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_41111">
		<text>Excellent, now I have the last piece of the puzzle to repair your PDA, ohhh this is a nice Crystal! It will only take a few minutes. Why don't you go and talk to Kruglov in the shed while you're waiting. He could use some company. I'll have it fixed up when you return.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_411111">
		<text>OK, great, see you shortly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_4112">
		<text>He did tell me about it, but I didn't get it yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_41121">
		<text>Well, best you do. We cannot complete the fix without it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_411211">
		<text>OK, OK, I'll get it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_5">
		<text>Doc said it was pretty urgent that you meet him. Best be on your way; we old people get cranky when we're left hanging.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_51">
		<text>OK, OK I'm going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_6">
		<text>I told you it will take a while, go see Kruglov in the shed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_61">
		<text>OK, OK, I'm going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_7">
		<text>Ah... Marked One, unfortunately, I was not able to bring full functionality back to your PDA... I recovered some corrupted data though, it wasn't much, here, take a look. I apologize I was not able to completely fix it. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_71">
		<text>Thanks professor, I appreciate your help regardless.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_711">
		<text>Sure, no problem. Don't be a stranger; you're welcome here anytime stalker. We might have work for you if you ever need a little cash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_7111">
		<text>OK, I'll see you around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_80">
		<text>About this special artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_8">
		<text>Have you found the artifact yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_start_talk_82">
		<text>No, I haven't.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- meet kruglov -->

	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_1">
		<text>Hmm, haven't seen your face around here before. Report to Professor Sakharov in the bunker and make your intentions known.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_11">
		<text>Will do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_2">
		<text>So you've gotten acquainted with Sakharov? Good. Now you won't get funny looks from the others.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_111">
		<text>Hmm, haven't seen your face around here before. You've gotten acquainted with Sakharov? Good. Now you won't get funny looks from the others.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_112">
		<text>Nice to meet you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_21">
		<text>What do you do here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_211">
		<text>A bit of this and a lot of that. I manage expeditions and oversee field tests from time to time. Tell you what, I'll tell you more later when you're not so busy with the professor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_2111">
		<text>See you around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_3">
		<text>I told you to come back later when you've complete Sakharov's assignment!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_31">
		<text>OK, OK, see you later.</text>
	</string>
<!-- kruglov second talk -->
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_5">
		<text>Hello again, what are you up to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_50">
		<text>Professor sent me to you. He said we have something to discuss.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_51">
		<text>Yes, there are several questions, though i didn't know how to ask them in delicate way... there are rumors in camp. Can you dispel all this fog?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_511">
		<text>Sure, ask me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_52">
		<text>You are the one, Strelok... correct? There are legends about your adventures. As far as i heard, this isn't your first attempt to reach the center of the Zone and the last one "misfortunes" drove you right up to the Generators. I am interested in a specific moment: how you got out alive from this place? The scale of radiation contamination there.. enormous, sarcofagus of Chernobyl NPP is completely deadly, also psi-emitters, which directly affect the mind, cerebellum and intelligence, in general the average man faced with such energy frequency drops combined with radioactive isotopes, couldn't survive at this area, even in the exoskeleton, or well, become a mutant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_53">
		<text>I lost my memory, completely, now I gather the remains of it as a grain of salt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_54">
		<text>Well, there were probably some pop-up moments from the subconscious or you totaly do not remember anything at all?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_55">
		<text>I remember only a bright flash during blowout and falling into the abyss... then I was carried somewhere, in an almost unconscious state, I was in some kind of... capsule, and the silhouettes around in white coats; it felt like they observed me and tried to say something, but I do not remember what, only then pain and total darkness. I woke up in Sidorovich's bunker, like a blank sheet of paper: no friends, no relatives... I felt lost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_56">
		<text>Thanks for the info. I appreciate this frankness. As soon as all this will be over or you remember something else, come back to me, we will have something to discuss. From the science point of view, your experience is priceless. I hope one day you will join us in our difficult matter of studying the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_4">
		<text>Hi, Strelok. How I deserved this new meeting?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_41">
		<text>Well, you said you would tell me in details what it is that you do here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_411">
		<text>Like I said, I'm a sort of manager and assistant for the Ecologist operations in Yantar. But mainly I'm known around here for training wild dogs. They're no German Shepherds, but they do one heck of a job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_4111">
		<text>Interesting. It must be time consuming though.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Kruglov: find music sheet -->

	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_0">
        <text>You have any special tasks?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_2">
        <text>I have a personal task for you if you're interested?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_21">
        <text>Sure, what is it?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_211">
        <text>A very famous composer lived in the forest not far from the bar. He has long passed but it is rumored that there could still be some of his music sheets lying around his house. Please go and check for me and I will give you a just reward.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_2111">
        <text>Sure thing, I`ll bring anything I find.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_22">
        <text>Sorry, I have too much on my plate now.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_finish_0">
        <text>About the composers house.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_finish_2">
        <text>Did you find anything at the house yet?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_finish_21">
        <text>Yes, I found this music sheet there.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_finish_211">
        <text>Splendid, good job, I`m a huge fan, this is so big for me you have no idea. Here is a token of my appreciation.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_finish_2111">
        <text>Thanks doc, anytime.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_music_task_finish_22">
        <text>No doc, still working on that.</text>
    </string>
	
<!-- The expedition -->
	
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_start_0">
		<text>Hello. It looks like I'm going with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_start_1">
		<text>Now listen here, stalker: I'm no Sakharov, and I won't coddle around with you; the lives of my crew are my top priority.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_start_2">
		<text>I can handle myself, don't you worry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_start_3">
		<text>Believe me: I don't. If you seem suspicious or run away in a tough situation - I'll kill you: I know how to hold a gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_start_4">
		<text>Yeah, and stalkers call ecologs sissies...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_start_5">
		<text>Two more guys will come with us: my assistant, stalker Kalmyk, and professor Kuleshov. We'll set off immediately, go tell the others.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_start_6">
		<text>Alright, I'll be quick.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_start_0">
		<text>So, it seems like you're the one to assist us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_start_1">
		<text>Yes, Sakharov sent me on the mission with you. Could you tell me what exactly are we doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_start_2">
		<text>Well, as far as I know, we'll revisit all the "mysterious" rooms around and under the lake Yantar, and we'll get everything that's left, like docs and tools; we'll also need to do some measurements. But what can we do? We have to. I'm not a good shooter, so I'll be doing the measurements.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_start_3">
		<text>Yeah, that's alright. Good luck to us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_start_4">
		<text>Yeah, we could use some luck. And what do you think? Nothing we can do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_start_5">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_start_0">
		<text>Hello, stalker. Have you joined the expedition as well? And what do you actually do here in general?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_start_1">
		<text>Yes, I have. I work as an assistant here: escort them most of the time, get 'em the artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_start_2">
		<text>Do you like it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_start_3">
		<text>The job is cushy; besides, I've got an offical pass to the Zone - but the military sometimes doesn't care, so I have to get in here the old-fashioned way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_start_4">
		<text>Yeah, there surely are some benefits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_start_5">
		<text>So, aren't you afraid to go with us? The Zone itself is a terrible place, but Yantar is one of the worst: either the brains are boiling or zombies are coming from every hole. And there's a shitload of monsters - it seems like they're coming here from all over the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_start_6">
		<text>Well, I'm not new to the Zone, so I'm not afraid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_start_7">
		<text>That's good, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_start_go_0">
		<text>Alright, everybody's ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_start_go_1">
		<text>Here's a last piece of advice: stick together, I'll lead the way; don't get too far from us, but not too close either; you've got to let us pass and bring up the rear. And strictly follow my orders - I don't stand objections in case of emergency.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_start_go_2">
		<text>I got it, let's move.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1_0">
		<text>So, that's the first place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1_1">
		<text>Yes. Strange place: stalkers always refuse to get in here. Ask Kuleshov about the situation and we'll go in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1_0">
		<text>What can you say, profesor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1_1">
		<text>The readings are going off-scale. But what can we do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1_2">
		<text>Well, we have to go forward. Let's get inside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1_3">
		<text>Like we have a choice. Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1v_0">
		<text>Creepy place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1v_1">
		<text>Damn, how many of these assholes are there? My head hurts... hard to think...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1v_2">
		<text>What's the plan now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1v_3">
		<text>There's something on the shelf - can you see it? We got to get it. Go take it while we're covering you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1v_4">
		<text>Yeah, but keep your eyes peeled: it's gonna be tough for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1v_0">
		<text>What can you say, professor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1v_1">
		<text>What do you think? The readings are really going crazy now. But what can we do...?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1v_2">
		<text>Are you staying here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1v_3">
		<text>I don't like zombies: these things always frighten me, make me nervous. You'd better ask our assistant: he faced them many times, he'll help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka1v_0">
		<text>Are you staying here too?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka1v_1">
		<text>No, we'll go together: it'll be smoothier this way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka1v_2">
		<text>Alright, let's go then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1k_0">
		<text>Phew, what a mess... although it could be worse in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1k_1">
		<text>Well, we knew the risk we take. And we've got off pretty easily. So what? Two dozens of zombies are not the worst thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1k_2">
		<text>What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1k_3">
		<text>We're going forward. Next stop is the abandoned hangar. We'll do it the same way: you go the last.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka1k_4">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka1k_0">
		<text>What can you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka1k_1">
		<text>What's there to say? We've got out and that's good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka1k_2">
		<text>That's right. Better not jinx it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1k_0">
		<text>What's next, professor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1k_1">
		<text>What do you think? Go to our leader for orders - he's the one deciding. But what can we do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka1k_2">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_0">
		<text>We'd be lucky to get to the place - not even find something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_1">
		<text>That's right. Now go check that house - there may be something interesting inside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_2">
		<text>Alright, I'll go check it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka2_0">
		<text>What are the readings, professor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka2_1">
		<text>Nothing here. What did you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka2_2">
		<text>And what do we do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka2_3">
		<text>Well, we've got to check the hangar inside. But what can we do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka2_4">
		<text>If we got to - we'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka2_0">
		<text>What do we have here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka2_1">
		<text>God damn it, dead scientist! I've never seen him at our base. Wears a labcoat without a suit... he even looks strange.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka2_2">
		<text>Well, you can encounter even stranger things here. He's a shadow of the past.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka2_3">
		<text>You think he was one of the scientists doing all those experiments? Then his body couldn't last so long.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka2_4">
		<text>You never know. It could be irradiated by something, so it never rot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kalmyk_exped_tochka2_5">
		<text>Yeah, that's possible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_posmotrel_0">
		<text>No, there's nothing in the house.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_posmotrel_1">
		<text>Are you sure? Nothing at all?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_posmotrel_2">
		<text>Yes. There's no furniture, no stuff, nothing related to the Zone experiments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_posmotrel_3">
		<text>Then we should check the hangar. Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_posmotrel_4">
		<text>Already been there. No idea what's there: only some scientist's corpse. But I've brought all the devices I could find.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_posmotrel_40">
		<text>Yeah, I'll go check it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_0">
		<text>I've searched the hangar. No idea what's there: only some scientist's corpse. But I've brought all the devices I could find.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_1">
		<text>Let's move then. Do you see the gates? They're locked, no way to get in there from here. Behind them there is a small room and stairs. It leads to a hangar connected the other Yantar underground facilities. This hangar is never being paid attention to, so we should search it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_2">
		<text>Will we go through the tunnels?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_3">
		<text>No - too far from here and also dangerous. We'll go through the military base, I'll make the passes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_4">
		<text>Like real IDs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_5">
		<text>No, Sakharov have already contacted them. You are allowed to go through with us, and we are always welcome there, as you know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_6">
		<text>How do we go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_7">
		<text>The bridge collapsed a long time ago and we won't get around it. We'll go down, there's a breach in the fence - that's how.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_8">
		<text>Am I going the last again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_9">
		<text>Yup, that's right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka2_done_10">
		<text>Let's go then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_0">
		<text>What's that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_1">
		<text>Change of plan: you shouldn't go through a narrow tunnel with a bunch of people, so we've decided to send you alone - as the most experienced. I took care of everything already: military will let you through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_2">
		<text>Great, but explain the task again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_3">
		<text>You can get to the basement from the second floor; then you'll be able to get to the tunnels. Look around there and get every device there is. There's no point in taking measurements there, it's too deep underground, so there's nothing interesting. Just get all the electronics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_4">
		<text>Understood. Stroll in a basement is an ordinary thing for me already. I'll get it done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_5">
		<text>Good luck. We'll wait for you at the base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_done_0">
		<text>Done, I've looked all over the place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_done_1">
		<text>And what was there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_done_2">
		<text>Nothing of interest: just zombies and burers. Found a couple of things, most likely to be useful for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_done_3">
		<text>I'm glad that you've got out. We haven't been out for quite a time, there's some point in such missions. That's not sitting on the ass in the labs! Go back to Sakharov, I think he'll like all the things you've found. And here's a little present from me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pirozhenko_exped_tochka3_done_4">
		<text>Thanks, see you next time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka3_done_0">
		<text>So, professor, how did you like our little venture?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka3_done_1">
		<text>Well, it was good to get some fresh air! What do you think? We were lucky to stay alive, but what can we do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka3_done_2">
		<text>What about the next expedition?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka3_done_3">
		<text>Oh no, enough expeditions - for a month at least. What can I do? There's more than enough research info for now. We've also got to decrypt the devices.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kulesh_exped_tochka3_done_4">
		<text>Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_0">
		<text>Hello professor, I'm here about the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_1">
		<text>Yes, I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_2a">
		<text>Everything went smoothly: we've got to every checkpoint and taken everything we need.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_2n">
		<text>I'm still in the process.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_3a">
		<text>Great news! I'm very pleased! Quick, give me everything please! And what about the measurements? Have you done them?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_3n">
		<text>Bring me good news! I'm hoping you'll get it done soon.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_4a">
		<text>Yeah, professor Kuleshov was doing them all the time, but I don't know much. You'd better ask him yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_5a">
		<text>Indeed I will! Here's a humble reward for such a great work done! And, of course, here's my part of the documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_6a">
		<text>I'm glad to help you, especially for a reward! Thanks, professor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_7a">
		<text>Thanks again!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_2b">
		<text>I've got bad news for you: we've lost a crew member. We had to call off the operation and get back to the base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_3b">
		<text>Such sad news... well, I shouldn't have sent you on such a hard job without any practice. The Yantar area is very dangerous - especially for a newbie team.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_4b">
		<text>My condolences.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_5b">
		<text>That's not your fault: this is the Zone. But I won't mind if you still want to help us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_6b">
		<text>That depends.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_7b">
		<text>It would be a shame to leave the operation without any results, so I propose you to do it on your own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_8c">
		<text>Yes, I don't mind. I'll take the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_8d">
		<text>We've already managed to do something, done a part of the job. We've been at the first checkpoint, and I'd found something there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_8e">
		<text>We've already managed to do something, done a part of the job. We've been at two checkpoints, I'd found many interesting things there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_8f">
		<text>I've already been at every checkpoint and had taken everythig I could. There's no point in going somewhere else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_9c">
		<text>Great! Then go to professor Pirozhenko: he'll mark the locations and explain the task.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_10c">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_10n">
		<text>No, I'm sorry professor: too risky. This job doesn't make any sense, I think it's pointless.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_9d">
		<text>Good, let's see what we have here. Yes, very interesting! Well, will you get the job done? We need data from the remaining checkpoints.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_10d">
		<text>Yes, I want to finish the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_8n">
		<text>No, I'm sorry professor: too risky. This job doesn't make any sense, I think it's pointless.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_9n">
		<text>Well, then here it is - my part of the documents. Like I promised.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_pribor_task_done_talk_9f">
		<text>Great, Marked One! You've made my day. Quick, give me everything. And here's your reward!</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Crack a PDA from Major -->

	<string id="yan_major_hacker_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello there, professor! It's me again, with a PDA I want to be cracked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_major_hacker_dialog_1">
		<text>Hello. I can already call hacking my hobby, so give it here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_major_hacker_dialog_2">
		<text>Alright. It's from the Major, though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_major_hacker_dialog_3">
		<text>Well... cracking password... we got it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_major_hacker_dialog_4">
		<text>Thank you! Well, I hope Major will pay you himself.</text>
	</string>

<!-- buy a dog -->
	
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_41111">
		<text>Well yeah, it keeps me busy, but I'm using it as a base for cognitive research on the breeds of dogs in the Zone. Would you be interested in buying one of my trained dogs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_411111">
		<text>Next time, though thanks for offer.</text>
	</string>
	<!--string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_411111">
		<text>Not at the moment, but I'll keep it in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_411112">
		<text>Maybe. How much do they cost?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_4111121">
		<text>5000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_41111211">
		<text>OK, sure, I'll have one please.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_411112111">
		<text>OK, it will be delivered at your place shortly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_4111121111">
		<text>Thanks..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_41111212">
		<text>Sorry, I don't have the money at the moment. Maybe later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_6">
		<text>So, can I interest you in a dog yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_61">
		<text>How much are they again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_7">
		<text>Hey stalker, are you happy with your dog?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_71">
		<text>Yes, very happy. He's well-behaved. Just thought I'd stop by and say thanks. See you around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_72">
		<text>Tragically, he died. I was wondering if you had another one for sale?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_721">
		<text>Damn, sorry to hear that stalker... Sure, I have one for you, it will be delivered to your place in a bit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_7211">
		<text>Brilliant thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_73">
		<text>You wanted to ask something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_731">
		<text>So when can i see the dog?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_kruglov_start_talk_7311">
		<text>Soon... go for a walk for now, i will get it from cage and prepare it for you.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- get good psy hemlet at lost factory -->
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_talk_2">
		<text>I am on a mission from General Voronin. We want to shut down the Brain Scorcher and X16 for good and open up the path to the center. He said you have a psy-helmet that will protect me from the psy-emissions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_talk_21">
		<text>Oh, well... we had a fine-tuned psy-helmet that could've protected you from such strong psy-emissions, but I already sent it with one of our men to the science bunker at the concrete factory. You can go there and ask my colleague Deedee for it on my behalf. I do have an experimental prototype here with me which you can take.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_talk_211">
		<text>Is it any good? You're not just offloading a useless piece of junk on me are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_talk_2111">
		<text>It will help you reach the old road that leads to the concrete factory at least. You will have to be quick though. But beggars can't be choosers, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_talk_21111">
		<text>I suppose so. I'll take it then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_talk_211111">
		<text>Here it is. Good luck out there stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_talk_2111111">
		<text>I'll need it for sure. Thanks for the help professor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_sakharov_helmet_talk_21111111">
		<text>Don't mention it.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- get rifle side task -->
	
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_2">
		<text>Hey! I need some help please brother... I was out searching for artifacts and all of a sudden realized I stumbled right into the middle of a Bloodsucker den! Holy shit was I scared.\nThey started chasing me! I dropped my shooter and ran; I never want to go back there. Can you help me and go into the underground and get my shooter back brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_21">
		<text>Bloodsuckers you say? How many were there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_211">
		<text>Oh... about six, I think...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_2111">
		<text>Damn, OK, but if I am going to risk my neck like that, you are going to have to cough up a very nice payment!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_21111">
		<text>For sure brother! Oh hey, one other thing... I got this off the dead body of some scientist in that area. It looks like some kind of scent blocker! Maybe if you put this on, the bloodsuckers won't attack you, unless you shoot one I guess.\nI didn't have time to try it, but I am way too scared to even go back there, even with this stuff! Not sure how long this stuff will last so its best to run.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_211111">
		<text>Sure man, give me that vial and I'll go get your shooter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_211112">
		<text>Sure man, no problem, I don't need that vial! I can take care of this without it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_211113">
		<text>No thanks, sounds too risky.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_22">
        <text>Wait... Are you talking about this gun?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_31">
        <text>Yes! It's her! Look, can you give it back? I'll give you a reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_32">
        <text>Take it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_3">
		<text>Hey brother, please tell me you changed your mind?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_4">
		<text>Hey brother, did you get it for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_41">
		<text>Not yet, work in progress.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_42">
		<text>No dude, and you can forget me getting it too, that place is crawling with them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_43">
		<text>Yeah, here it is. That place is crawling with them, I wouldn't venture down there again if I were you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_431">
		<text>Thank you so much stalker, here, take this suit as a sign of my gratitude.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_rifle_dude_dialog_4311">
		<text>Thanks man, be careful out there, don't let the Bloodsuckers bite!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_bloodsucker_den_done_text">
		<text>Thanks again stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_bloodsucker_den_done_text_2">
		<text>Don't mention it.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- duty task -->
	
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_0">
		<text>Hey brother, are you our reinforcement? We have been waiting for you for 2 days now and totally lost control over the situation!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_11">
		<text>Yes, I was sent by Voronin to figure out what the current situation is. What's going on here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_12">
		<text>Nope, I am just walking around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_121">
		<text>Then get lost! We are busy if you haven't noticed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_111">
		<text>We have big problems man. The messenger that Voronin sent was killed by bandits and they also attacked our position! So now we have a bunch of wounded men here. We need to retake control of this high ground, can you help us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_1112">
		<text>Of course, I will take care of them. Where are they located?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_1113">
		<text>I'll mark their position on your PDA, let them have it for all they did to us. I think they deserve to burn in hell! I recommend caution though, there are plenty of mutants around too, lake yantar is not a place for newbies to be wondering around. By the way, I have additional work here for you.. want it? It's not a big job but needed..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_111311">
		<text>Not interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_111312">
		<text>Of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_1113121">
		<text>When these bastards attacked our position, they not only sprayed us with lead, but those buggers from the village stole my favourite guitar!! Bastards, I can't forgive them for that. We also had a case with some stuff to...you know...make the days easier...if you understand what I mean! Bastards from the gas station group took it! Can you try and find these things in their respective camps, please?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_11131211">
		<text>You can count on me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_1114">
		<text>Thank you, thank you man! I had already lost all hope of dealing with these bastards. I will put in a good report about what you did for us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_11140">
		<text>No problem. All for one and one for all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_111401">
		<text>Did you manage to find all my stuff yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_1114011">
		<text>No not yet, but soon!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_11140111">
		<text>Yes, both of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_11141">
		<text>Well then, I have a present for you. Here it is, light as can be, we found it in an anomaly nearby.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_111411">
		<text>Hey thanks, I really appreciate it. See you boys around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_11151">
		<text>About your stolen stuff. Here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_11152">
		<text>Hey brother, thank you for helping us recover the stolen items, I have a present for you. Here it is, light as can be, we found it in an anomaly nearby.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_11111">
		<text>Bandits dead?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_11112">
		<text>Not yet. Working on it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dolg_recon_help_11113">
		<text>Yes. I killed them all.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Upgrades by the local technician -->

	<string id="father_diodor_repair_intro_dialog_0">
		<text>Hi, are you a repairman?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_intro_dialog_1">
		<text>Hello, son. Yes, I'm trying to help stalkers like you every way I can.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_intro_dialog_2">
		<text>So that means that you can upgrade my suit and weapons too?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_intro_dialog_3">
		<text>I don't think I have the proper equipment for that, son.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_intro_dialog_4">
		<text>I could bring some tools. If you upgrade my things afterwards. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_intro_dialog_5">
		<text>I don't mind that. It would be great if you get them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_intro_dialog_6">
		<text>Alright, I'll do that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm here about the tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_1">
		<text>What do you got there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_2a">
		<text>Brought you something, a tools for rough work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_2b">
		<text>Brought you something, a tools for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_2c">
		<text>Got you a calibration toolkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_3a">
		<text>Good job. Well, now I need tools for rough work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_3b">
		<text>Good job. Well, now I need tools for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_3c">
		<text>Good job. Well, now I need calibration toolkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_3ab">
		<text>Good job. Well, now I need tools for rough and fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_3ac">
		<text>Good job. Well, now I need tools for rough work and calibrations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_3bc">
		<text>Good job. Well, now I need tools for fine work and calibrations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="father_diodor_repair_bring_dialog_3abc">
		<text>That's all! Now I have a complete set. I can upgrade whatever you want!</text>
	</string>
</string_table>