	<string id="meet_gusarov_text">
		<text>Petrenko from Duty is looking for some documents from that Lab X-18. He said I'll need to meet his men at Dark Valley and talk to one of them - Oleg Gusarov. Things I do to find that damned Strelok...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="get_bandit_suit_text">
		<text>Gusarov sent me to the bandit base and advised to find a jacket or whatever which can make me look like one of the gopniks. Let's hope I won't get shot by some blind stalkers because of that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="get_password_text">
		<text>So here I am - wearing some stinky stupid jacket just to get some password from bandits, which is probably something like "Blin" or "Suka"... You better be worth it, Mr. Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_mono_informer_text">
		<text>Okay, the password is learned; the next stop is the Monolith base - I'll need to try to gain knowledge about the underground lab from Gusarov's undercover informer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="get_x18_docs_text">
		<text>The informer told me that there's some encrypted text about Lab X-18, which lies beyond this factory, in the head's desk. While he's distracted, I should grab the document - and not to let anyone see me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reach_dscape_text">
		<text>The military are assaulting the base. The hell do they need here?! Gusarov told me to find a vehicle and high-tail it to Darkscape - it's in the South.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="free_prisoner_text">
		<text>One of Petrenko's guys is being held in prison at the bandit base, and I need to find a way to save the captive. I wonder why these Duty fellows can't rescue their own soldiers themselves...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_find_bandit_text">
		<text>Some military officer from the gas station at Dark Valley wants some bandit called Borziy dead. I'll need to visit Dead City, find and take the bastard out, take his PDA, then bring it back - along with the good news.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="dol_safe_combination">
		<text>Borov's safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_safe_combination_text">
		<text>The combination opening Borov's safe is 2-9-5.</text>
	</string>