<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<!-- Gusarov task -->

	<string id="dolina_gusarov_about_0">
		<text>I wanted to ask...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_about_1">
		<text>Yes, what is it that you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_about_21">
		<text>Where can I find a bandit suit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_about_32">
		<text>I guess you could get one from Barkeep, or perhaps you can find one at the old entrance to a small cave near here where the bandits used to conduct business. I heard many died there in an explosion, maybe one of their suits is still usable. I'll mark the place on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_about_41">
		<text>How can I get the password from the bandits?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_about_42">
		<text>Find a gullible one, do some supply-and-demand, and there you go.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_1">
		<text>Who the hell are you and what do you want from us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_2">
		<text>Marked One. Petrenko and Barkeep sent me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_22">
		<text>Eh? I guess traders might have'em. Perhaps you can find one stashed somewhere for free. Ask around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_3">
		<text>Oh, THAT guy. Right, here's the plan buddy. The Monolith have a base at that factory up ahead, at the center of this valley. X18 is below it, sealed off long ago after the '06 disaster. I'm not sure, but it's likely that they don't even know how to access it themselves.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_31">
		<text>How can I get the password from the bandits?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_32">
		<text>Find a gullible one, do some supply-and-demand, and there you go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_4">
		<text>Then how do we get in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_5">
		<text>Well... We gotta get in there and gather intelligence on those fanatics. The only ones that might have the know-how necessary to bust that lab open are...those Sin bastards... Short story, we can doubt they will help us though, so we are on our own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_6">
		<text>Sounds like a hopeless case then. Infiltrating the Monolith doesn't sound very easy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_7">
		<text>True, but I've got a plan. The Monolith have a truce setup with the bandits, and they have a special code they use so they can enter the Monolith base. They change it regularly though, so we can't pussyfoot around too long. My plan is that you find one of those black leather jackets the bandits wear, and obtain the password from one of them to get in. Sounds simple enough, yes? After you get the password from the bandits, go to the Monolith base. Then bullshit your way past the entrance gaurds, meet the informant we have set up in there, he owes me one, I saved his life once. Then find a way down to X18 - I've got something planned when you get in. The bandits don't check faces, but remember, try to act like them and walk with a swagger, talk like you're uneducated, you know, blend in. It doesn't matter how well you're dressed approaching the bandits, might as well be a tutu and pink slippers. The most important thing is to not shoot anybody and keep a low profile.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_gusarov_dialog_8">
		<text>OK, thanks, I'll see what I can do.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Drunken bandit -->

	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey brother, how goes it this fine evening?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_1">
		<text>All good here man. And with you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_10">
		<text>Ha-ha, come, let us drink to your forgetfulness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_11">
		<text>Sure, pour it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_12">
		<text>Man, I can't believe you could forget a funny password like "pizdec."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_13">
		<text>Ha-ha yes, that's it! Thanks brother, I'll catch you later mate!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_2">
		<text>You know how it is, one vodka, two vodka... ya just lose count y'know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_3">
		<text>Yeah, do you have any more? Let's have a drink brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_4">
		<text>Do I have more? DO I HAVE MORE?! Hell yeah bro! Here, let's drink to those loopy Monolithians! Heh-heh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_5">
		<text>Yes, to the Monolith and all their crazy ideas.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_6">
		<text>Crazy? I'll tell you what's crazy! Why do those Monolith guys have to change the password every week? Bunch of paranoids, but it's not like comrade Borov is gonna break our alliance over that shit. I mean, I have a few vodka shots and my memory gets all fuzzy. It would be easier if it was one password, we all write it down, and we'd be done with it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_7">
		<text>Yeah, I have the same problem. I have a few vodkas and can't remember a thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_8">
		<text>Yeah, but this week's one I just can't forget, no matter how much vodka I drown in. It's so funny! Heh-heh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_dialog_9">
		<text>Heh-heh-heh! Yeah, it was a funny one this week... Damn, I must've had too much vodka! I can't remember a thing!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_no_dialog_0">
		<text>Hi brother, can you help me with something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_no_dialog_1">
		<text>Hey, leave me alone, my mother told me not to talk to strangers!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_drunken_bandit_no_dialog_2">
		<text>Eh, ok, as you were...</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Borov dialog -->

	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_0">
		<text>Sir... can such a low life as myself ask you one little thing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_1">
		<text>How many times do I have to tell that drunken bastard - stop recruiting newbies! We've got enough rats on our necks as it is! You take pity on the poor imbecile and let him in ... but who says that the next imbecile isn't actually another clan's spy? Okay, since you're here, let me put you through a little test. Fail the test and you're dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_21">
		<text>Try me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_22">
		<text>Just die.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_3">
		<text>Alright ... so there are these different folks gathered in the Duty bar: there's the Duty old-timer with many battles under his belt; there's some crazy Monolith idiot; and there's your ordinary quiet-sort-of bandit. A question comes up: does human morality still work inside the Zone and how would you apply that? The Duty fighter immediately barks: “Of course it still works in here! Are we not still humans then? These surroundings don't just convert us into wild animals, we still feel the need to protect the innocent and fight the evil of the Zone!” The Monolith cultist interrupts: “What are you talking about, man? Whose morale? The Monolith is sacred! That's the only thing that matters - we pray instead of listening to the infidels talk. We take what we need and don't haggle with the nonbelievers. We kill for our cause if we have to. We convert those who disagree so that they can see the light too!” Once these two had spoken, the bandit took a deep breath and paused to think. Then he opened his mouth to say: ... And this is your test: what would the bandit say? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_41">
		<text>People need protection, no matter how hard the times. Even bandits can't survive long without some support from their mates. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_42">
		<text>I will just try to be myself and pay everyone back with their own coin. Better be the grey wolf amongst canines than a dead monkey.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_43">
		<text>People prey upon people. If you don't want to get killed or robbed, better be the one who strikes first. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_44">
		<text>I don't know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_5">
		<text>And the winner is... NOT YOU! You chose the wrong one. It's execution time, loser!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_6">
		<text>...you sure?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_7">
		<text>Of course, I just simply don't know!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_71">
		<text>Please, give me another chance!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_72">
		<text>Nope.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_73">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_8">
		<text>You passed the test newbie! Not many do, you know. What a lucky day this is - we won't have to scrub your brains and bowels off the floor! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_9">
		<text>But why? Why is that the correct answer? I don't understand!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_10">
		<text>It is quite simple, really. If you chose the first one, it would mean you're one of the softies from Ecologist camp or that you were sent by Duty - we sure don't want any of that trash here. If you chose the second and said you'd rather be yourself, it would mean you only follow your own interests and won't comply with the rules; you would probably double-cross us and rob us blind. If you chose the third one, it would mean you are a Monolith spy or a serial killer or some other maniac. Sure, we all have some blood on our hands, but that's only because we fight to survive. Now, the correct answer means that you really are the dumb idiot you appear to be and that our drunken mastermind has brought in another fellow bar-dweller. Get it now? So, what's the favor you wanted to ask me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_11">
		<text>I just need to check our plans and documents to figure out which positions need more guards and where I should go myself. May I take a look?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_12">
		<text>Sure, just don't forget to put them back. This is valuable stuff after all - if I see something missing or messed up, I'll personally blow your head off. You go ahead and study the papers, I'll go have some coffee. The docs are in that safe - the code is 295. And don't touch anything else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_borov_dialog_61111121">
		<text>Thank you Sir!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_1">
		<text>Lost something, smart ass? Come on, get out of here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_2">
		<text>Is this some kind of warehouse? Can mortals like I get inside?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_3">
		<text>This stash is only for the elite faggots, so you can't use it. But for a certain amount of cash...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_4">
		<text>Now we're talking! What's the price list?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_5">
		<text>5000 rubles for 2 guns, 7 thousand for all the same along with 2 ammo packs and 2 grenades, and for 10 thousand as bonus to all this habar you'll get the opportunity to choose any 12 items from the stash, just don't be a greedy asshole. Got it? And do not touch the dynamite.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_6">
		<text>I'm giving you 5 thousand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_7">
		<text>I'm giving you 7 thousand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_8">
		<text>I'm giving you ten.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_9">
		<text>I don't need anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_10">
		<text>Go on kid, don't stay there for long, or Borov will fuck up both of us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_11">
		<text>As you wish. Don't be annoying then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_dialog_12">
		<text>Nothing to take anymore. Get out!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolina_guard_take_0">
		<text>Can we... handle this the peaceful way?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_take_1">
		<text>Are you fucking lost, you scum? Shake your backpack out - and fast!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_take_2">
		<text>Okay, alright... here, take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_take_3">
		<text>You're lucky today... and now - shoo!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_take_4">
		<text>You can go and f...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_guard_take_5">
		<text>You'll die now!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dolina_trader_steal_1">
		<text>I became a trader not for that any dickhead like you could clean me up. Return the key now, bitch!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_trader_steal_2">
		<text>Are you fucking crazy, fraer? Return me the key and everything you stole there! You can't rob the main dealer, you goddamn idiot!</text>
	</string>

	<!-- monolith informer dialog -->

	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_0">
		<text>Greetings willing neighbor. What can this brother help you with?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_1">
		<text>You're that guy, are you not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_101">
		<text>Well then... I must "get at it". Farewell.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_1011">
		<text>OK, thanks, see you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_102">
		<text>OK, farewell</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_2">
		<text>I'm sorry, I didn't get that. Care to repeat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_3">
		<text>That really bad situation you got into a while ago, apparently you almost caused a disaster. My mate told me about you. Relax, I know you are not one of those zealots.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_4">
		<text>Oh, since you know it...let us not waste time. I am undercover and I get paid a lot for doing my job. But why would you bring this up, good sir?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_5">
		<text>I'm seeking information about X18.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_6">
		<text>That is classified to the members of the Monolith. But... that guy saved my life... and I care for my honor. Very well, I know were you can find such knowledge. In the leader's office, on a shelf, in an encrypted journal. 
		They have only managed to decrypt some parts, and some of them honestly think that this is just a waste of time. They say they need "convert, evangelize, not dwell on bottomless matters". So if it were to disappear... you would get away with it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_7">
		<text>But it's not like I can waltz in and get it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_8">
		<text>I will keep the leader occupied so you may get the journal. But I'll be risking my cover so I need insurance. 10000 rubles should be enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_91">
		<text>Pricey, but it's worth it to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_dialog_92">
		<text>I don't have enough at the moment. I'll get the money and return.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_rubles_0">
		<text>So, have you got the money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_rubles_1">
		<text>Yes I do. It's pricey but worth it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolina_monolith_informer_rubles_2">
		<text>No, not yet. I'm still working on it.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- prisoner -->

	<string id="val_prisoner_dialog_1">
		<text>Ah stalker, thank goodness, a kind face, help me please.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_dialog_11">
		<text>Hi, i'm on a mission for duty and was asked to rescue you. The question now is how do we open the gate?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_dialog_111">
		<text>We need the key. I'm not really sure where to look for it but i can tell you that the guy who has it must have a radio nearby because he is always on about the latest tunes he hears.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_dialog_1111">
		<text>Ok, you hang tight, I'll go and see if I can find it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_dialog_2">
		<text>Hey, do you have the key yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_dialog_21">
		<text>Not yet, don't worry I'm still searching for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_dialog_22">
		<text>Yes, hang on I'll open the gate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_dialog_3">
		<text>I can't thank you enough for what you have done. Duty will surely reward you well for your actions! I must run, if we ever meet again I`ll make it up to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_dialog_31">
		<text>It's no problem really, good luck.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- monolith password -->

	<string id="dol_monolith_password_dialog_2">
		<text>What's the password?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_monolith_password_dialog_21">
		<text>Pizdec.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_monolith_password_dialog_211">
		<text>You may proceed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_monolith_password_dialog_2111">
		<text>Thank you brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_monolith_password_dialog_22">
		<text>Blin?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_monolith_password_dialog_221">
		<text>You better not go any further or it will be the last thing you do!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_monolith_password_dialog_2211">
		<text>Right, I'll be on my way then...</text>
	</string>

	<!-- military specnaz dialog -->

	<string id="dol_specnaz_dialog_0">
		<text>What do you want stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_dialog_1">
		<text>What are you guys doing skulking here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_dialog_11">
		<text>Go speak to the leader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_dialog_111">
		<text>Ok, will do.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_0">
		<text>Yes stalker, what is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_1">
		<text>What are you guys doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_11">
		<text>Hmm, well, there's no harm in telling you I suppose, unless you decide to mess with my plans. We are watching the bandits. Looking for one particular bandit leader "Borziy" who is number one on our wanted list for various reasons I won't go into.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_111">
		<text>And, how is the stakeout going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_1111">
		<text>Actually, we have reason to believe he has fled to Deadcity, but I can't risk leaving the area in case the intel is incorrect. I don't' suppose you want to go and check if he is there and deal with it and bring back his PDA as evidence for a tidy sum do you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_11111">
		<text>No thanks, I have others things i need to be doing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_11112">
		<text>Sure, but how do I know where to find him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_111121">
		<text>We bugged the PDA of the guy we suspect to be our target. Don't ask how, we have ways. Anyway, I've marked it's position on your PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_1111211">
		<text>Ok I'm on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_2">
		<text>Just checking in with you guys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_21">
		<text>Is the target neutralised and you have the PDA?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_211">
		<text>No not yet, I'm still on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_212">
		<text>Yes, but damn, I forgot the pda, I`ll be back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_213">
		<text>Yes, all is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_2131">
		<text>Hmm, yes! It is his pda for sure. Good job stalker, you're a good soldier. Here is the promised fee.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dol_specnaz_leader_dialog_21311">
		<text>Wow thanks, pleasure doing business with you.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
