<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- ghost meet -->
<!-- get artefact from mercs task -->	
	
	<string id="mil_ghost_start_1">
		<text>Strelok. Came back from the netherworld I see. Heh, sorry for sounding so mundane about it - being shot in the gut and taking some of Doc's heavy stuff does that to you... I heard everything from Doc, so no need to explain. Are your memories back in order at least?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_start_11">
		<text>I am a little better; I vaguely remember you, so we've got that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_start_111">
		<text>Well that's good... Listen man, I was taking up some vigilante work to pay for several months of vodka and other little pleasures. Here is the story: A few Mercs slaughtered some stalker mates of mine for no reason, turns out, it's the same Mercs that have that rare artifact your looking for! My mates are dead now, so I thought, "Why don't I teach them a thing or two about karmic justice?" Thing is, I didn't think they were affiliated to an entire bloody garrison. I was going to kill them and steal the artifact... As discreet as I was that night, they saw me, so I ran back to this hole in the ground. They're probably still laughing about it, the bastards. Do me a favor and go blow their brains out, will you? With that rare Crystal artifact they have, the eggheads in Yantar can fix up your PDA. If you're lucky, perhaps some information will be restored along with it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_start_1111">
		<text>Give me the coordinates and I'll go check their pockets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_start_11111">
		<text>Right, here they are. There's also a Freedom guy that wanted to help out 'cause his friends were the ones killed, but I haven't heard from him. Oh, before I forget: take this sniper rifle - it should work just fine for taking the pigs down. You used to like this particular shooter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_start_111111">
		<text>All right, this needs to be done now. I'm on my way!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_start_1111111">
		<text>Good. Come back when you are done, and don't forget the artefact!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_start_11111111">
		<text>Sure! I ll contact you as soon as I get it!</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- meet freedom contact -->
	
	<string id="mil_contact_st1">
		<text>Hey man, sorry for the delay - car was being a bitch. I hope I'm not too late to the party, 'cause I want a piece of 'em too! What's the situation? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_contact_st2">
		<text>The Mercs that murdered your friends and have the Crystal artifact are in the warehouses up ahead. An entire garrison unit from the looks of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_contact_st3">
		<text>That won't be easy. As I see it, we need to get past the snipers in the towers and several patrols of mercs. There is a blowout expected soon, the mutants in this area are all freaked out, a whole shit load of them are heading this way! So the blowout and mutants should help create a distraction among them. Follow me in, and I'll personally find the motherfucker who did this! As payment, I'll let you keep the artifact in question. It doesn't matter to me now that the gang is dead... You take out the first sniper at the base entrance, and then we will storm in! Have some tact - use your sniper rifle and keep the noise level low.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_contact_st4">
		<text>Alright, I'm right behind you.</text>
	</string>
		
<!-- get artefact from mercs task done -->

	<string id="mil_ghost_0">
		<text>So did you finally get it? I hope that asshole is dead!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_1">
		<text>Not yet. I'll be back as soon as possible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_2">
		<text>I've killed Mad Dog and got the Crystal. Contact's dead though - blowout got the best of him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_21">
		<text>Then there's no time to lose. Bring that thing to Yantar! I'm in no condition to come with you with these meds acting up, Godspeed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_ghost_211">
		<text>On my way!</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- military trader chitchat -->	
	
	<string id="mil_basement_trader_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey stalker! Welcome to the basement camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_basement_trader_dialog_3">
		<text>Anything else?</text>
	</string>
		<string id="mil_basement_trader_dialog_4">
		<text>See you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_basement_trader_dialog_1">
		<text>What do you sell?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_basement_trader_dialog_11">
		<text>Nothing special, actually. Medkits and bandages mostly. I'm not a gun-dealer, but I also have basic ammunition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_basement_trader_dialog_2">
		<text>Why are you in such a place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_basement_trader_dialog_21">
		<text>This deep in the Zone, the price for basic supplies sky rockets. Not many traders want to set up a shop in these parts. Indeed, getting supplies is a royal pain... But, I recuperate those costs with ease, plus make a nice margin. </text>
	</string>
	
<!-- crazy stalker side task -->	
	
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_1">
		<text>Huh? Stand back or I'll shoot!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_2">
		<text>Whoa, calm down! I'm not a mutant... at least not yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_3">
		<text>A normal? Good! Can you help me out, mate? I'm in a sticky situation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_4">
		<text>That depends on what's in it for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_5">
		<text>Stuff! Yeah, yeah... artifacts and sorts. I have those if you can get back my dear rifle. You see, I made the mistake of getting out of this shack... big mistake. I dropped it while escaping some critters. Please get it back! It's somewhere at the abandoned village nearby.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_6">
		<text>Alright, I'll try to find your precious rifle.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_7">
		<text>No, sorry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_8">
		<text>Thanks! And good luck... "mate".</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- crazy stalker chitchat -->

	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_dialog_1">
		<text>Tell me about...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_dialog_2">
		<text>What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_dialog_21">
		<text>Surviving. How do you expect me to live near others? They'll stab you in the back and dump you on a moment's notice!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_dialog_3">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_dialog_31">
		<text>A nobody abortion of society like most around here. Just because I have a shack doesn't make me Mr. Special.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_dialog_4">
		<text>You know anything interesting?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_dialog_41">
		<text>Look around you. That should keep you interested for the next millennia.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- crazy stalker side task done -->	
	
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_done_0">
		<text>I wanna talk about your weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_done_1">
		<text>Did you get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_done_2">
		<text>Not yet.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_done_3">
		<text>I have it right here. But I want to see my reward before I hand it over.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_done_4">
		<text>Damn, you managed to survive that...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_done_5">
		<text>What are you saying? You wanted me to die?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_done_6">
		<text>My friends just wanted a meal. Fresh juicy skin off a little scavenger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_done_7">
		<text>What is that supposed to mean?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_stalker_job_done_8">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- meet fang -->
<!-- let's move to pripyat through radar -->
	
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_2">
		<text>You sure took your time Strelok. Just decided to reappear after all these months, did you? Well, whatever happened to you is your own business. Anyhow, it's good to see you again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_21">
		<text>Fang? I seem to remember your face... I heard you were dead, but Doc cleared that up for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_211">
		<text>Yup, I'm Fang alright. I see the amnesia is still present to a degree. Well, your noggin will settle down in due time. But enough with that - we've got serious matters to attend to. Strelok, do you remember what we were planning back a few months ago?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_2111">
		<text>Doc told me the gist of it. You were to build a decoder to open up the lab beneath the Generators.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_2112">
		<text>I... I... can't remember much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_21121">
		<text>We were going to try to get into the lab beneath the Generators! We thought whatever caused the Zone: blowouts, mutants, everything... was created in this lab and it still contains the key to bring everything down! I was working on assembling a decoder. I was using old technical notes I wrote way back when, to open up the lab, but couldn't find all the parts. Then a shit storm happened... you went missing and we got all split up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_21111">
		<text>Possibly in this lab is the key to turn off what is the main cause of these energy blowouts and all the madness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_211111">
		<text>I see... Yes, it's slowly coming back to me. So what do we do next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_2111111">
		<text>Well, I just found the last part for this decoder device - I'll take it to Yantar, to let the Eco's look over everything. Until then, you should go and meet Ghost, who is already in the Pripyat hotel, room 26. But don't wait for my return: we don't have much time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_21111111">
		<text>I see. I will go and meet Ghost then. Godspeed, brother!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_3">
		<text>Hurry brother, time is of the essence!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_31">
		<text>Yes, I'm on my way.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- fang chitchat -->
	
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_4">
		<text>Was there something else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_41">
		<text>Where did you learn all of your mechanical skills?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_411">
		<text>Self-taught - all of it. I guess it helps I know mathematics better than most of the drop outs in this cesspool. As long as you got the will and the time, anything is possible. Newton invented calculus without a stinkin' computer, right? Well, I created the ecologists' vaunted psi-helmets with just pen and paper.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_4111">
		<text>You invented the psi-helmet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_41111">
		<text>Yeah, not that long ago. Sold off the blueprints to them since I didn't have the precision tools to do it myself. Asses can't be bothered to at least mention my name when they brag about it. To hell with 'em! Their payment still sits in a bank account somewhere in the Bahamas. Hah, taxpayer money at work. Y'know, when we're done with all this madness, we could bail out and live the big life. You, me, Ghost, Doc - hell, if he wants, we'll bring Guide along. Yeah, that'd be sweet...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_411111">
		<text>Yeah sounds good. Watch out I just might hold you to that. OK, I must run.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_42">
		<text>How exactly did we meet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_421">
		<text>Nothing spectacular - unlike how you met good ol' Ghost. I helped out Doc when some Merc assholes tried to claim his little swamp house for themselves. Had to crush a skull and dislocate a shoulder, but they got the message. Doc introduced us and we had a good time with drinks and such. After that, we had to deal with the pompous Merc bastards again. It was quite a spectacle. Never underestimate a modded PKM loaded with incendiary rounds... God I miss that sweet beast of a gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_4211">
		<text>Where was Ghost around that time?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_42111">
		<text>Ghost wasn't with us back then though - he came into the picture a little later. Ask him, I'm sure he'll tell you the whole thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_fang_dialog_421111">
		<text>OK, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--freeplay-->
<!--mad guy freeplay task -->

	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_2">
		<text>Hey stalker, I need some help man! I was playing poker with the boys when these rats came in and the guys ran away all scared... little bitches! I don't have anything to kill the rats with though , can you help me get rid of them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_21">
		<text>What's in it for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_211">
		<text>Oh man, I don't have much... well I do know a place where a friend of mine hid a nice stash; I can give you the coordinates if you kill all of them for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_2111">
		<text>Sure, I'll take care of them, back in a few!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_2112">
		<text>I don't have time right now, sorry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_3">
		<text>Please I'm begging you, can you help me with the rat problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_31">
		<text>I'm just too busy for this, sorry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_4">
		<text>Are all the bastards dead?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_41">
		<text>Not yet, still working on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_42">
		<text>Yep, all done and dusted!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_421">
		<text>Wow, thanks man, I really appreciate it. Here are the coordinates of the stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_4211">
		<text>Pleasure doing business with you, see you around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_5">
		<text>Are all the bastards dead?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_51">
		<text>Not yet... there are a few problems...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_52">
		<text>Yep, all done and dusted. Now if you just give me the coordinates I'll be literally running along!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_521">
		<text>Wow, thanks man, I really appreciate it. Here are the coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_5211">
		<text>Yeah, take care man...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_mad_guy_dialog_53">
		<text>You have serious issues man, and about your friends... actually, forget that. I'm outta here!</text>
	</string>
	
<!--mad guy freeplay task part 1 -->

	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_2">
		<text>Ahhhh, another "rat catcher"!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_21">
		<text>You... you can talk?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_211">
		<text>Yes, not all controllers communicate telepathically, some have retained the ability to use your language.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_2111">
		<text>What are you doing here creature!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_21111">
		<text>That is for you to find out my friend...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_211111">
		<text>I am not your friend; I won't ask again, what are you doing here?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_2111111">
		<text>You just took care of a problem for me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_21111111">
		<text>What?.. What are you talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_211111111">
		<text>Go to the dead rats and see for yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_2111111111">
		<text>And what about the rats? Just some dead rats. Or...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_2111112">
		<text>Just take care of the rat problem and then we will talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_21111121">
		<text>OK, but I'll be back.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--mad guy freeplay task part 2 -->	
	
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_3">
		<text>So, have you done the job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_31">
		<text>Yes, now tell me what the hell this is about!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_32">
		<text>Not yet, still working on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_33">
		<text>Forget this, I'm outta here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_4">
		<text>Quite something eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_41">
		<text>What the hell is wrong with you?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_411">
		<text>This has been my house for years. A couple of drunkards stumble in for a game of poker and do you think I would just let them!? I don't think so! So I controlled your minds into believing they were rats.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_task_controller_dialog_4111">
		<text>You sick bastard! If I ever meet you again, I'll finish you off!</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
