	<!-- string_table -->

	<!-- fakes -->
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_1">
		<text>Guys, new rumor: a newbie was pulled from a death truck and people say he remembers nothing now. He doesn't know how to handle a gun and hangs around the traders; maybe we should rob him, huh? All goodies will be split 50/50, I promise you that!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_2">
		<text>Warning: I don't recommend you go to the Swamp. Some scum settled there known as swamp beast: eyes like a squid's, tentacles 3 meters long and it's extremely poisonous. Don't risk your ass and stay at the Bar if you're clever enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_3">
		<text>Vets say no signs of life after the Radar territory, however, here everybody insists it's full of Monolithians... but where is your evidence, newbies? Quite possible very impressionable comrades took the wrong pills and tell fairy-tales around the fire, so I want to clear up this delusional garbage and plan to raid this place. Any volunteers are welcome, loot split equally; ask Jashka at the Bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_4">
		<text>Scumbags, military completely went nuts! "Come and help us then you can drink our beer and vodka, all your needs will be catered to"... yeah, right!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_5">
		<text>Vitjok, shit! Where have you gone? What's the crap I heard about you finding a tunnel and deciding to search it alone at night, high as a kite, without a weapon?! What were you thinking?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_6">
		<text>There are rumors around that soon they will be cleaning on Escape. My informer reported that the military commanders are being pushed by government saying the black market here disturbed somebody very rich and powerful, so you guys best stay away from Sidor before it's too late - or the old bastard will send you all to your graves.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_7">
		<text>Did anyone hear that Barkeep had opened a fighting arena near the Bar the other week? I'm not sure if it's true; I mean, what normal person would possibly fight mutants for money and for fun in a public battle?! Is this the middle-ages here or what?! Hey Barman, - or should I call you Caesar? - did you hear me? Stop wasting our time with these rubbish ideas. Don't listen to him guys!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_8">
		<text>I am searching for information about a so called "doctor-death" who is rumored to kidnap his victims at the lake Yantar and maul them with a chainsaw. If anyone knows anything about it, please pm me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_9">
		<text>It's possible to buy drugs in Dead City!!! I just came from the Mercs camp: they said it's enough to bring just a "Night Star" with little cash and they will put them straight to your as... mouth! Also they will give you a sleeping bag with nails so you wouldn't be able to sleep deeply in danger areas!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_10">
		<text>I went to Agroprom with my mate yesterday... it's so peaceful there: not a single breath of the wind, military don't bother anyone, stalkers cleaning undergrounds and mutant numbers as low as at the Bar. Sergey, if you are reading this, come and see me near the wagon: we will discuss our next plans.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_11">
		<text>I saw something strange happening at the Rostok factory... That creature had claws and big edged spikes instead of fingers, then there was a bright light in the night sky, something took me from ground with a beam and then... I don't remember anything. Woke up in some house with a bottle of my favorite gin-tonic. What was that?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_12">
		<text>One day we're gonna sort this place out, we're gonna make order here. And I don't mean just clean places to live, I mean real order: a little perfect state inside of a state, like the Vatican... only radioactive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_13">
		<text>I think I saw some Mercs in the Forest last week! I was moving towards the Metal Factory when I had seen some movement; I laid down and grabbed my binoculars to observe, and seen about six men in gray outfits! I was observing for about 15 minutes, and then I'd run to the Duty outpost. What a mess!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_fakes_14">
		<text>Guys! I have just spotted a squad of Mercs few clicks north of here. No idea what the hell they are up to. Let's just relax a bit with that dog shooting before they assume we are trying to attack them: I don't want Merc spotlights on our asses...</text>
	</string>

	<!-- rumors -->
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_1">
		<text>Stalkers, if you don't want to get into trouble, try not to swing your guns in front of every idiot; especially be careful with the military! Stay away from bushes and don't provoke them, then probably you will be able to leave without spoiling your SEVA and a hole in the head.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_2">
		<text>There are some rumors that mutants emit radiation, but in such small dozes that at first it's not really noticeably. Glasses guy on Yantar affirms that we all be dead eventually and our clocks are ticking... 15 years, no more after contact with these creatures, so congratulations: we are all potential corpses in Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_3">
		<text>There is a rumor that some supplier set up his shop in a small basement at the Army Warehouses. He doesn't sell much, but at least he has medkits for lower prices and lots of drinks to quench your thirst.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_4">
		<text>The ones who think Cordon is a safe place are deeply mistaken. You guys remember the death truck? Don't try to get there: some horrible creature chose this place for his home and mangles people. But probably there is something valuable there that attracts the locals...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_5">
		<text>If somebody is planning a move through Garbage, do it warily: there is some kind of turmoil between locals again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_6">
		<text>For those who don't know, don't try and get to Darkscape: lots of military formations were seen over there recently. There's a rumor they are planning a huge foray into the area to make the second Cordon: it's almost the Zone's border after all...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_7">
		<text>Some strange things going on in Rostok: my mate heard that some strange things which look like humans were seen at the factory that can suck you to death! If somebody wants to help, ask Dima there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_8">
		<text>Currently, the Bar is definitely not a walk in the park: if you wanna join Duty - pay; if you don't wanna die from bleeding - pay; if you just wanna drink with mates - pay again. It's getting out of hand!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_9">
		<text>Scary things going on near the Radar: stalkers say hordes of the dead rising from graves and spirits possessing the living. You will also succumb to the control of powerful psi-emissions there and completely go mad. Save yourself and don't go there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_10">
		<text>Some interesting information going around: an old man from the Swamps went missing and nobody saw him now for a few weeks. Anybody know where he is? He owed me money. Hey, OLD BEARD, I will find you and you will be sorry!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_11">
		<text>Shit... I heard when somebody wants to leave Duty, it's like leaving some crazy cult: they smile at you, say "No problem, you can go", and then they find you and make you disappear... Well, maybe it's just a rumor to keep people from deserting, but I'm not planning to find it out myself...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_12">
		<text>Several months ago I saw a UFO. I swear I'm not kidding! It was a large, dark black object and it was glowing orange; some say it was military spy plane, but I know what I saw. Aliens are surely observing this mess. I would too if I was an alien...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_rumors_13">
		<text>There is a rumor that scientists were experimenting with teleport technology, successfully teleported several large objects and then started testing animals. Weird thing is that they went in living and came out in a coma. No physical injury or anything, just turned off, and later all subjects died. Turns out that those living things lost their living essence, or soul or something, during the process. That is some scary shit. They kept that secret because material science dismisses this completely.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- stories -->
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_1">
		<text>A short story guys. We met with Fedor, he said that some creepy things going on around here: suddenly he saw a rat come out of nowhere, nothing special, he kicked it and carried on walking, and then another one, but this time 2x the size of the first. So he goes around it slowly and suddenly a 4 meters tall rat with red eyes walking on its back legs appears. He exchanged glances and run away as fast as he could. After an hour at this place he found a dead controller. The moral is, be careful stalkers: you are not safe here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_2">
		<text>A dangerous thing to roam without a gun, for example today I went for "mushrooms" to the Forest, as a result, I was bitten and tried to find help at the miner's base. I was totally robbed and thrown, half dead, into the nearby swamps. When I woke up I had to run away from ghosts and so on with my naked ass, up to the Metal Factory. Be careful stalkers: greed can result in bad consequences.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_3">
		<text>Anybody know the mystical Guide? I was "lucky" today, stumbled on his stash on Swamps. I thought finally something good happened to me: dozens of artefacts, expensive exoskeleton, tons of hidden money and ammo... I tried to pull the stuff out and was hurled by an explosion. Turns out I'm in a fishing net and can't get out. Listen to me asshole: if I ever find you, say goodbye to your legs!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_4">
		<text>One day we decided to sneak up to the Monolithians there at the Dark Valley, but because there are thousands of them and only two of us, we decided to try our luck and befriend the bandits. Totally stoned, in clear sweat pants, we start telling them that they promised us a meeting, and "Can we come in?" They bought it, haha: we took what we found and ran away quickly. These morons didn't even know we robbed them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_5">
		<text>Has anybody heard about the undergrounds at the Radar? My friend told me that someone named Bold calculated the frequency and intensity of emissions there, but this idiot forgot his psi-helmet, and now the corpses of him and his comrades lie around near the bunker, gnawed by local wildlife.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_6">
		<text>Got a pack of secret docs for Barkeep. His eyes bulged when he saw them; he was like "Where the hell did you get these?" He says there is something important in the underground lab nearby; somebody should try and get there as many interesting things regarding army experiments can be found.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_7">
		<text>A funny thing happened to me guys. It was business as usual at the factory on Cordon, when suddenly my pal runs out of nowhere and screams: "Trolls, trolls!!!" I think to myself: "Trolls in the Zone? Holy shit!" Then he looked at me strangely and pulled out his PDA, laid it on the ground neatly, and with all his strength proceeded to beat it with his shoe, six times! Then I knew he was disturbed for sure.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_8">
		<text>Guys, I strongly recommend you avoid the local cuisine, especially the drinks from the slicker at the Bar. We joined him a few times for a meal when he pulled out a bottle and said it's magic: "If you drink 10 times, a genie will appear; 20 drinks and Diablo himself will appear!" Well.. we drank and drank and drank and let me tell you, after the headache I had in the morning I would've rather dealt with the devil!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_9">
		<text>Duty welcomes anyone in our new bar! Feel free to visit us: pleasant company, good stories, and tons of loot await you at the 100 Rads bar!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_10">
		<text>Don't listen to those idiots who claim they can take you around to the local treasures. I went one day to the old village on Yantar; suddenly a very colorful dude appears with expensive armor and tells me: "Hey brother, do you need artefacts? I'll take you through to this place". I decided to join but after the second mile I got nervous and asked where we are. He turned to me and said with a nasty smile: "That's for me to know and you to find out", - and then just ran away and left me there!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_stories_11">
		<text>Did you know that people who originally were at ground zero in the NPP got such a massive dose of radiation that they could actually hear the radiation? It is something that you can hardly test in a lab! Testimonies were describing feeling like a thick silence muffling all other sounds. One became unable to hear clicking of his own teeth if clutching them together. Also metallic taste in mouth was reported and painful pressure on eyeballs... that is how massive radiation was there. Incredible that these people were able to work in such conditions!</text>
	</string>

	<!-- spam -->
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_1">
		<text>Repchik and dubchik, that's all that matters, even in the Zone. Am I right guys?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_2">
		<text>Anyone who has money and wants to waste it, Sidor from Cordon is always happy to trade.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_3">
		<text>This message is spam! If anyone is interested in seduction pills, ask Leha the Savior in the Bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_4">
		<text>Tired of scary monsters? Not enough money to pay all your debts? Dark stalkers wanna rape you? Write to me, Vlad95, as fast as you can, and I will deal with all your problems: one bullet at a time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_5">
		<text>I've spent so many years searching for the truth in the Zone and finally I found it! It's your personal X-Ray extension module 2.0! Are you in a bad mood? Listen to music nobody likes, nobody to talk to? Now you can play tetris, do puzzles, chat with mates, have important meetings online. For a once in a lifetime deal, come to the village in Dead City.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_6">
		<text>La-la-la, la-la-la... Vadik, i am near his bunker. Pm me as soon as possible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_7">
		<text>Fire power! That's all that matters! Yeah guys, I'm talking not about an ordinary gun, but a supreme one - Winchester 1300! For only 10000 rubles this baby could be yours. Price negotiable, so hit me up, brothers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_8">
		<text>Has somebody seen my repair kit?! I lost it on Cordon because of some scumbag. Please pm me if you find something...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_9">
		<text>Five, four, three, two, one... nuclear rockets launched! All of you will be dead in the next 10 minutes, run from the Cordon villages little piggies... run, hehe!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_10">
		<text>Anybody know what's going on outside? The guys from that outpost said a zombie apocalypse is going on in the US! is that true?! I hope we never caused it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_11">
		<text>Do you believe in ghosts, stalkers? Not Zone creatures, but real human ones? I do. I met one in the underground lab around here! The good thing is, they didn't try to kill me; the bad thing is that I am probably one of them now! Ha? Haha...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_12">
		<text>Damn, who dropped my account from the stalkers network database?! Hey, admins, wake up, I'm writing to your pm already for a week now you bastards!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_13">
		<text>Have you ever been caught by a Whirlpool anomaly? It's really funny... you just need to be careful not to end up covered in shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_14">
		<text>Do you hear them too? The voices... shh, you hear them? No? Oh... you have to pray more then. Your faith isn't strong enough. They say that you have an important purpose!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_15">
		<text>Mates, I'm stuck in some underground! I can't remember how I got here... Help me! According to the PDA, it's located in the north.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_16">
		<text>Don't you think I forgot about you, Sidor! You're still responsible for that job...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_17">
		<text>Holy crap! I accidentally turned out to be at a military outpost the other day, but the soldiers didn't even start shooting and let me cross their turf! Did a real human bite them?..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_18">
		<text>I heard the Mercs have fortified Dead City. The hell do they need there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_19">
		<text>Oh lord! I had stuck at the Construction Site last night. It's so damn scary there! A very few stalkers around but lots of mutants... I wanted some abandoned building to be my shelter for the night, but turned out it was occupied by some beasts. Anyway, don't you ever visit that forgotten place at night!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_20">
		<text>Has anybody ever been to the Rostok factory? I heard nobody hangs out there except some ecologists and those military guys from that outpost. The thing is, there might be a lot of valuable stuff there; why don't we cooperate and visit the place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_21">
		<text>Guys, I don't really recommend you to grab all the artefacts you see. My buddy found one last month, and he still can't get rid of it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_22">
		<text>Don't you ever go to the Forest... by car: there's a throwing up anomaly on the main road. I saw a Chimera falling from a 50-meter height because of it! That's some shit indeed...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_23">
		<text>I've been to North Hills the other day, and the only advice I can give is, only go there by vehicle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_24">
		<text>Did anyone hear this scream coming from the Construction Site? They say the place is really wild one... I wouldn't go there if I were you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_25">
		<text>Am I the only one who noticed all these useful supplies inside of undergrounds and labs, like food or batteries? I'm really curious to know who the hell left it all there; I mean, it'd be clear if there were dead bodies nearby... but there aren't! My friend told me that he once found a sausage packed like 10 years ago - but it wasn't even dry! He ate it and didn't even notice any consequences for his stomach! That's what I call magic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_spam_26">
		<text>What the hell?! I found a stash in the Forest yesterday, and it seemed like some crazy guy left it: there was some stinky meat inside, along with notes covered in blood, and a newly-polished Colt! Something I don't think it's some mutant's meat...</text>
	</string>

	<!--jokes-->
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_1">
		<text>A drunken stalker staggers into a Catholic Church, enters a confessional booth, sits down, but says nothing. The Priest coughs a few times to get his attention, but the stalker continues to sit there. Finally, the Priest pounds three times on the wall. The stalker mumbles: "Ain't no use knocking! There's no paper on this side either!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_2">
		<text>Bandits grab some rookie: "Hey dude, wanna play a game?" They ask "Here is a dice, if you roll 1-5 we gonna kick your ass". "And if I roll 6?" - asks the rookie. The bandits laugh and answer: "Then you'll win yourself another roll, man".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_3">
		<text>A stalker met an old civil Zone inhabitant: "How old are you grandpa?" - One hundred and fifty-eight... - Do you smoke or blooze? - Of course I do! I'll be living forever if I won't!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_4">
		<text>Why do Burers laugh when playing football? Because grass tickles their balls!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_5">
		<text>A Chinese saying tells that one painting worth 10 thousand words. And I think a good punch in the face does exactly the same.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_6">
		<text>You know what happens to a homeopath who forgets to take his medicine? He dies of an overdose!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_7">
		<text>If it smells, it's chemistry. If it breeds, it's biology. If it doesn't work, it's physics...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_8">
		<text>If you ever get lost and very tired, call out a Bloodsucker: he'll suck all the tiredness up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_9">
		<text>How many theoretical physicists specializing in general relativity does it take to bring an artifact to the base? Two: one to hold the artifact and one to move the universe in the respective direction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_10">
		<text>On one heavily rainy night, Dutyers were infiltrating a bandit base. Crouched behind a large stone, one of them initiates a move forward yelling "Cover me!" Nearest Dutyer opens his umbrella above his head...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_network_jokes_11">
		<text>Hey, a new joke I just heard! How do you recognize a flying stalker? He has a giant crow on his back!</text>
	</string>