	<string id="help_raiders_text">
		<text>There's a military squad seen on the road. I really doubt I'll be able to get to the Sarcophagus myself, so I should offer them my help to discover anything that'd help me get into that place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_help_military_text">
		<text>The military squad wants to occupy the high ground, and their leader - Lt. Dudaev - promised to introduce me to their commander if I help the guys: I'm pretty sure he knows where the Sarcophagus entrance is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wait_helis_text">
		<text>We need to gain a foothold near the gate and hold out positions, waiting for the helicopters to arrive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="destroy_btr_text">
		<text>The helicopters haven't done the job... which means we'll have to deal with the BTR on our own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ambush_task_text">
		<text>Those Monolithians again... damned fanatics! We need to deal with them till they haven't clapped all of the soldiers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_task_text">
		<text>Well, the assholes are decently equipped indeed! I wonder where... but it's not the time. I need to get rid of the RPG guys unless I want to scrape the guys' brains off the walls.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutants_wave_text">
		<text>Oh, come on! A wave of mutants is heading towards us, so we need to do something about it. Besides, I'm pretty sure there are some fanatics left around...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_recon_leader_text">
		<text>Well, I helped the military and Dudaev's kept his promise: he'll introduce me to the commander. I need to get to him and ask about the Sarcophagus.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_dudaev_text">
		<text>I've agreed to help the military take out the Monolithians. They even let me use a BTR to take the assholes out! That's another childhood dream come true...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="help_dolg_text">
		<text>There's a Duty squad billeted on the NPP outskirts. I should offer the guys my help - and perhaps, they'll tell me how to get into the Sarcophagus.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg1_help_text">
		<text>I need to place the transceiver as near to the BTR as possible so the helicopters can take it out, and then move in and eliminate the Monolith threat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_recon_text">
		<text>The leader of the Duty squad asked me to track down the recon group which searched for the entrance to some underground. Isn't it the Sarcophagus? If so, I need to find the guys for sure.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="aes_sar_code">
		<text>Sarcophagus entrance code</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="aes_sar_code_text">
		<text>Code that opens the Sarcophagus entrance door at ChNPP is 4237.</text>
	</string>