	<string id="help_loners_task_text">
		<text>Not sure if I should've offered my help, but I guess I can't back down now. I need to kill these pseudodogs so the loners can advance to the 100 Rads Bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_petrenko_text">
		<text>Barkeep sent me to his backroom: some Petrenko guy should explain me all this underground labs situation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_task_text">
		<text>A loner by the name of Hunter has been mugged by bandits, and his rifle is now with them. I feel sorry for this poor sobbing bugger so I should go teach the gopniks a lesson and return his beloved rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="attack_heli_task_text">
		<text>Petrenko's requesting backup: the Bar is under attack by Mercs. I need to help the survivors defend themselves against the killers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="dolg_join_task_text">
		<text>I want to join Duty, and to increase my chances I need to deliver some supplies to their squad at Rostok Factory. Here's list of what I must bring:\n- 10x 5.45x39 AP ammo;\n- 10x "Tourist's Delight" canned goods;\n- 10x Canned corn;\n- 10x Army medkits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_task_1_text">
		<text>Comrade General instructed me to meet the scout at lake Yantar. I don't have a right to let down neither of them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_be_a_spy_task_text">
		<text>I need to place a bug inside the Freedom bar, steal any intelligence and then bring it back to Comrade General. It doesn't sound easy... but I think I'll handle it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_task_mutants_text">
		<text>The squad sent to the Construction Site five days ago has never sent a sitrep ever since. Comrade General surmises it's something about the radio signal but I'm almost sure it's way more deep... Anyway, I should get to those parts and see what's this shit all about.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_muta_ver_text">
		<text>The Construction Site squad had run into some deep trouble indeed. I need to report on my intervention's results to Comrade General.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_task_sins_text">
		<text>So, our faction is having a negotiation with the archenemy - the Sin. There's some negotiator waiting for me at Garbage, and who the hell knows what will he'd ask instead of the information...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_labs_pc_code">
		<text>Labs PCs password</text>
	</string>
	<string id="labs_pc_code_text">
		<text>Petrenko has decrypted the password for PC located in underground labs: they used an old encryption system, therefore the pass is pretty simple - "top_secret".</text>
	</string>