	<string id="meet_seriy_task_text">
		<text>Sid has finally dug up info regarding that Strelok guy, and now I need to met a stalker by the name of Seriy at the Garbage. It's the only clue at the moment, so it's not like I have a choice... again.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="meet_bes_task_text">
		<text>There seems to be a problem for a stalker group at the Garbage: their "head", Bes, sent an SOS signal. Well, I need to meet them and find out what's wrong.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_sniper_text">
		<text>Bes told me that some shithead is having fun "shooting turkey" with a sniper rifle. I need to deal with the moron, but before that I should get to that green house not far away and grab some shooter.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="assault_hangar_text">
		<text>Seriy's boys are having trouble with some bandits, and they decided to attempt retaking the hangar currently occupied by the assholes. It's in my interest this doesn't fail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_boars_text">
		<text>A squad of some "Duty" requested assistance taking out a wave of mutants and guaranteed their gratitude to all who'd help deal with the sons of a bitch. I think I'll need to find out who those Duty characters are...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="task_to_pass_task_text">
		<text>The Duty checkpoint leader offered me a deal: I take out the local beasts, and they grant me free access to the Great Metal Factory. These guys seem alright, I don't think they're bullshitting me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="seriy_flash_info_text">
		<text>Mole writes to Seriy: "Me and the boys might've dug up Strelok's stash at the Institute. The loot isn't worth much, but we're not after it... we're after something more valuable. Anyway, come by sometime - and we'll drink!"</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sins_get_art_text">
		<text>The Sin negotiator's agreed to exchange the "Goldfish" artifact for the Duty disc. If there's a peaceful way of doing all this, I should choose it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sins_talk_blockpost_text">
		<text>Comrade General's ordered me to meet one of his men. I'm not sure why - but there's only one way to find out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sins_clean_enemy_base_text">
		<text>I should've guessed: I and the guys are about to destroy the Sin base. That's the last hour those pricks will survive, haha!</text>
	</string>