<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- meet doorman -->

	<string id="out_doorman_talk_2">
		<text>Greetings stalker, how can I help you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_doorman_talk_21">
		<text>I'm Marked One. Colonel Petrenko sent me to see Barkeep and Voronin.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_doorman_talk_211">
		<text>Oh, so you're Marked One. Come on in, I'm sure he is expecting you. Welcome to the new 100 Rads Bar. At least we can play pool here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_doorman_talk_2111">
		<text>Thanks for letting me in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_doorman_talk_22">
		<text>Any chance of letting me in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_doorman_talk_221">
		<text>You have no business here stalker - move along.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_doorman_talk_2211">
		<text>I'll be back when I do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_doorman_talk_3">
		<text>You again? I hope you have business here this time...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_doorman_talk_31">
		<text>Nope, but I'll be back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_doorman_talk_4">
		<text>Take it easy and enjoy yourself, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_doorman_talk_41">
		<text>Don't mind if I do.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- meet barman at outskirts -->
	
	<string id="out_barman_talk_0">
		<text>So, what can you tell me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_2">
		<text>Glad to see you made it, Marked One. We got word that you managed to take down the Merc helis, good job!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_21">
		<text>Yeah, it wasn't easy, but I'm here in one piece.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_211">
		<text>I can see that. Well, I'm busy gauging the damage done to my business. It's a mess for everyone... We lost many good men during the attack. The delicate balance of power has shifted and Freedom is on the rise now, since Duty have been hit so hard - and let me tell you, Duty isn't happy. Why don't you go speak to Voronin in the back room while you're at it? We've got a problem, a big one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_2111">
		<text>I'll go see him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_31">
		<text>Have you spoken to Voronin?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_311">
		<text>Not yet, I'm on my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_32">
		<text>Good luck out there, Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_321">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_33">
		<text>My congratulations, Strelok. You disabled all this damned crap which brainwash hundred of our mates through the years. Voronin awaits you. I guess he wants to thank you personally.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_331">
		<text>Thank you. I'll go and see him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_34">
		<text>Hey, mate. You just passing through or have anything to talk about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_barman_talk_341">
		<text>Just looking around.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- meet Voronin -->
	
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_2">
		<text>Hey, you've made it! I've heard from Colonel Petrenko that everything is sorted out at the Bar. Well, as good as it can be... Hopefully someday we can rebuild what we once had. The mutants are flooding the place just like how it was before we established the Bar - the Wild Territory has re-emerged. However, we can't dwell on it with the situation at hand. Do you mind hearing me out, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_21">
		<text>Shoot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_211">
		<text>As you know, the way to Pripyat and beyond is covered with deadly psy-emissions due to the Brain Scorcher. It has been like that since the Zone existed. Sometimes the strength of them increases or falls at certain intervals, but it's the same pattern. But after all that scavenging in the old laboratories Petrenko has done - way before X18 and others - we've discovered how to shut this system down. We need someone that has proven himself, and you're the finest man I've seen so far for such a mission. There's going to be disagreements among my men, but I want the Scorcher to be deactivated - even if Freedom wants the same thing. That contraption has been the bane of human existence for too long. Go and see Ivancov for more information, I marked his location on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_2111">
		<text>Agreed. If we have a way to stop it, then I'll do everything I can.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_3">
		<text>Go and see Ivancov, he'll brief you on the situation. He can explain our plan much better than I.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_31">
		<text>OK, I'm on it.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- meet ivancov -->
<!-- get bad hemlet at yantar -->

	<string id="out_ivancov_talk_2">
		<text>How did you find this place, stalker? I'm not going to gun you down, but if you don't have a reason to be here, I suggest you move along.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_ivancov_talk_21">
		<text>General Voronin sent me here for a debriefing on the Scorcher situation. I'm Marked One.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_ivancov_talk_211">
		<text>Oh, my apologies, I didn't know. Well, Marked One, here's the situation: We need to disable the emitters which are causing and broadcasting the massive psy-emissions fields blocking the way to the center. You will need a way to protect you from these emissions. Go and see Professor Sakharov back in Yantar; he can help you out with one of his psy-helmets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_ivancov_talk_2111">
		<text>I'll go see him then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_ivancov_talk_21111">
		<text>Hold your horses there! Turning off the Brain Scorcher's emitters is not enough. There is a sort of "backup Scorcher" which is under the Lost Factory, within the X16 lab beneath it. Before you shut off the Scorcher, X16 needs to be shut down or else the Radar antennae will still be operational. The scientists will help you out with that as it comes - they are as eager as anyone to shut down the blasted things.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_ivancov_talk_211111">
		<text>Okay then, I'll keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_ivancov_talk_3">
		<text>have you disabled the emitters yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_ivancov_talk_31">
		<text>Not yet. I'm working on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_ivancov_talk_4">
		<text>Hey, if it isn't the emitter disabler. Good job stalker, never doubted you for a second!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_ivancov_talk_41">
		<text>Yeah thanks, all in a days work.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- lost factory and radar scorcher disabled -->
<!-- disable earthquake device at basement -->

	<string id="out_veronin_talk_4">
		<text>Thank you Marked One, Duty owes you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_41">
		<text>Glad to help, General. However, these tremors are still a thing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_411">
		<text>Ah, yes, now that you mention it, the quakes we feel are caused by an old experimental earthquake device - a derelict, but functional weapon of destruction, that could've been used to target specific areas on the globe. It wasn't such a problem, but ever since we've moved here the tremors have risen. Even Freedom has noticed them and are accusing us of instigating all this. For the record, we didn't.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_4111">
		<text>Then we've got to turn it off for everyone's sake. Where is it situated?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_41111">
		<text>It's in a lab under the old water dam. I've sent others to investigate, but they haven't returned.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_411111">
		<text>I'll take care of that too. They're getting worse, and who knows what a strong one will do to this building.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_5">
		<text>Hurry if you can - these earthquakes are becoming more frequent and irritating!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_51">
		<text>I'll sort it out. You help your men tend to their wounds.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- earthquake device disabled -->
	
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_6">
		<text>Marked One, we can't thank you enough. A possible conflict with Freedom has been avoided in our moment of vulnerability. Now we can concentrate on our work without all the interruptions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_61">
		<text>It was no problem, General. See you later, I guess.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_611">
		<text>Not so fast! Someone had left a note for you while you were gone. Seems like he wants to meet you at the old church - it's not far away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_6111">
		<text>A note? Well, uh, thank you. I'll go and check the church.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- veronin after all finished -->

	<string id="out_veronin_talk_7">
		<text>You take care out there, Marked One.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_veronin_talk_71">
		<text>I will thanks General.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- meet guide -->
<!-- chitchat -->
	
	<string id="out_guide_talk_2">
		<text>Strelok, it's nice to see you with such vitality. I believed you had truly passed away, but it seems I was wrong.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_21">
		<text>Guide - am I right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_211">
		<text>Yes, I am Guide, the very same from the legends, more or less - the one who led you to the center months ago. Do you remember me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_2111">
		<text>Vaguely. That handwriting was familiar. Have you seen Doc? He wanted to get a hold of you too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_21111">
		<text>Yeah, I'm here because of that... but since we have an extra minute ask me anything, and I will answer with whatever humble insights I have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_211111">
		<text>That's very handy: I have a lot of questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_22">
		<text>Why did you lead me to the center in the first place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_221">
		<text>It was a hunch. At first, I didn't know who you people were... but something in my gut told me you were to be trusted. A seemingly normal guy such as yourself among all these warped realities was an attractive prospect, I must admit. The whole thing kind of reminded me of these other two guys I took out once, a professor and a writer. Call it an act of charity, or perhaps I was getting bored that day - you figure it out and choose which suits your ego.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_2211">
		<text>I see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_23">
		<text>How did you get us past the Brain Scorcher back then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_231">
		<text>Call it intuition if you must. I'm no man of science or God by any means, but I can read the Zone like an open book. What you might see as boars feasting on a dead stalker, I would see as a clue about the zone around us and an opportunity to learn more. I have a sort of sixth sense that allows me to casually sidestep the inconveniences of the Zone. Knowing how to pass the Scorcher back then was as natural as the act of walking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_2311">
		<text>Right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_24">
		<text>What do you know about the Zone's origins?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_241">
		<text>Whatever you've come to suspect is a half-truth. Indeed, the Zone was given life by the mistakes of humanity, but it has grown beyond mere human understanding. It has an unripe sentience to it - the embryo of a new realm not bound by cosmic laws. Even if the Zone's core is to be torn to pieces, it won't make it disappear. At best, it'll only stop the growth. Yet somehow, I doubt it would all end there like a fairytale. This only seems like a prologue to something far more sinister.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_2411">
		<text>Interesting theory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_3">
		<text>You can ask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_31">
		<text>Ask freely.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_32">
		<text>Any questions left?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_4">
		<text>So now you are a bit more up to speed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_41">
		<text>So what will you do? We're planning on going back to the center. Do you want to help or not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_411">
		<text>Yes, I will guide you. We can't go now through Pripyat's outskirts , need to go through undergrounds. Talk to me when you're ready to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_4111a">
		<text>I'm ready to go now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_4111b">
		<text>Okay, give me a little more time to prepare.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_4111c">
		<text>Let me get there alone, meet you there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_41111">
		<text>Best of luck to you. Oh, and I have something for you - a "Compass". It will bring you good luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_411111">
		<text>Thanks, I'll keep it close.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_411111b">
		<text>Come when you're ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_go_0">
		<text>I think I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guide_talk_go_1">
		<text>You sure? We still have some time.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- after dialog we meet fang at military warehouse -->

	<string id="out_guard_conversation_0">
		<text>Hey Stalker, this is freedom territory and we are closed at this moment. What is your business here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_conversation_1">
		<text>I have a password.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_conversation_11">
		<text>Let me in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_conversation_21">
		<text>You are from... DUTY?! Get the hell out of here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_conversation_22">
		<text>You think I am THAT stupid and forgot your face already?! Get lost, you Duty bastard!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_conversation_2">
		<text>Hmm, really? That's interesting, what is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_conversation_3">
		<text>Torchok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_conversation_4">
		<text>How did you... okay, never mind. I guess you are a friend of ours. You may pass, just don't act like an ass in there and drink moderately!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_flashcard_1">
		<text>Hey, you... did you see the flashcard on the barman's table? Empty your pockets!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_flashcard_11">
		<text>Get lost!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_flashcard_12">
		<text>Alright, relax. Take your thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_flashcard_121">
		<text>Really? You thought you could get out of here without any trouble and sell it? Idiot, if I see you here ever again you are dead! Understand?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_flashcard_1211">
		<text>Yes, I am going right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_flashcard_13">
		<text>It was not me, it was...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_flashcard_131">
		<text>Who?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_guard_flashcard_1311">
		<text>Probably this one! Near the table!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_merc_robbery_0">
		<text>We know you got some important info from Freedom. Can you be so kind and give it to us? We can of course put a bullet in your head too if you want...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_merc_robbery_1">
		<text>Yeah, sure, I don't want any trouble. Take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_merc_robbery_11">
		<text>Good decision, now you can walk away from here alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_merc_robbery_2">
		<text>Get lost, punk!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="out_dolg_guide_dialog_0">
        <text>I will wait for you here while you finish your business there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="out_dolg_guide_dialog_11">
        <text>All done, let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="out_dolg_guide_dialog_12">
        <text>Ok, I'll be back soon hopefully.</text>
    </string>
	
<!-- misc -->

	<string id="out_veronin_back_text">
		<text>Sergeant, we detected a group of mercenaries moving towards your position... I guess we were too late. I'll wait for the report.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- lukash -->
	
	<string id="out_lukash_start_0">
		<text>Hi stalker, what can we do for you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_start_1">
		<text>I was passing by and thought I would introduce myself</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_start_11">
		<text>A wise move. My guys don't like unfamiliar faces walking around here, they get a bit twitchy. So what's your name stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_start_111">
		<text>I am Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_start_1111">
		<text>Strelok, wow in the flesh. You're a very good person to know, so I hear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_start_11111">
		<text>Really? Well if you say so...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_start_111111">
		<text>Ah come on, don't be modest man! I heard you're a man who gets the job done. I am Lukash by the way, leader of Freedom in these parts and all other parts he he. Maybe one day you could join us in our quest for freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_start_1111111">
		<text>Maybe, but I have many things to do first.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_start_11111111">
		<text>Ok, well we always need things done around here, so don't be a stranger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_start_111111111">
		<text>Ok, sure.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="out_lukash_task_0">
		<text>So, about that offer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_1">
		<text>You ready for a big task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_11">
		<text>Sure, lay it on me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_12">
		<text>Not yet, give me some time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_111">
		<text>There is a place called the Construction Site, not too far away; I'm sure you're familiar with it. The Merc trader there has a key that he stole from me. It opens a door on Radar where I have an important piece of machinery kept hidden. He knows what I am hiding, but does not know where it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_1111">
		<text>So I just waltz in there and take it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_11111">
		<text>Haha, funny guy! No, first you will need to get the password to enter the Merc camp. Go see the stalker trader nearby: he knows it and with some persuading may just give it to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_111112">
		<text>Actually, I have the password already.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_1111121">
		<text>Great! You're half way there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_11111211">
		<text>Ok, so I have the password. All I need to do is, get past the guards and then just take the key, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_111111">
		<text>Ok, so I'll need to get the password, get past the guards and then just take the key, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_1111111">
		<text>Go at night, they are all drunkards at the bar and sleep very heavily, but be careful. Usually he leaves the key just lying around, bragging to everyone how he holds the key to the future, then gets drunk and leaves it there for the picking. Of course neither I nor my men can get anywhere near there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_11111111">
		<text>Then I take the key to Radar and retrieve your machine?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_111111111">
		<text>Exactly, you catch on fast. Do this for us and the guys will look upon you very favorably, and I will give you a little something in appreciation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_1111111111">
		<text>Ok, mark the areas on my PDA and I'll get going.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_0">
		<text>About the task.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_1">
		<text>You found out the password yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_11">
		<text>Yes, got it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_12">
		<text>Not yet, still need to get it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_111">
		<text>Ok now go get that key.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_1111">
		<text>Ok, I'm on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_2">
		<text>You found the key yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_21">
		<text>Yes got it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_22">
		<text>Not yet, but I will soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_211">
		<text>Great now go get me that machine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_2111">
		<text>Ok, I'll bring it soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_3">
		<text>So, do you have the machine yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_31">
		<text>Sure, here it is. Do you mind telling what it actually is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_32">
		<text>Not yet, sorry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_311">
		<text>Good job! I knew you were a "go to" guy and you delivered. Since you did me a huge favor, I'll let you in on the secret. This machine can create anomalies. Those dangerous, freaks of nature. Can you imagine if it got into the wrong hands? One of the Eggheads was messing around one day and created it quite by mistake. When the military heard about it, they hired the mercenaries to get it for them. I just couldn't imagine a weapon of this magnitude getting into military hands, that is why we intervened and stole the machine. We are all about freedom, and that very freedom which we strive to attain would be history should the military start messing around with this baby.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_3111">
		<text>Wow, Ok, well I'm glad I helped you then. Sounds like it was a worthy cause.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_31111">
		<text>Worthy indeed. Now about that little something I promised you. Here it is, compliments of the boys to you, and like I said before, don't be a stranger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_task_during_311111">
		<text>thanks, I really do appreciate it. Perhaps we will meet again.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="out_lukash_join_0">
		<text>So, I'm back after my quest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_join_1">
		<text>Hey, so are you ready to join Freedom yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_join_11">
		<text>Yes, I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_join_12">
		<text>Not yet, maybe later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_join_111">
		<text>Then it is so, take this suit, you are one of us now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_join_1111">
		<text>That's it? No fancy ceremony or anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_join_11111">
		<text>No need, you have proved yourself to me, that is enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_lukash_join_111111">
		<text>Thank you, I will wear the suit with honor.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- hunter -->
	
	<string id="out_hunter_start_0">
		<text>Well if it isn't my old mate Marked One.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_hunter_start_1">
		<text>Good to see you made it out of there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_hunter_start_11">
		<text>Yes, and thanks to you I still have my baby.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_hunter_start_111">
		<text>Don't mention it, stay safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_hunter_start_2">
		<text>Hey, how goes it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_hunter_start_21">
		<text>Well I'm alive, but thanks to you I lost my baby and had to buy a shitty AK!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_hunter_start_211">
		<text>Ok... stay cool man...</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Upgrades by the Duty technician -->

	<string id="dolg_fixer_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello. Are you the one repairing and upgrading things?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_fixer_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes, I'm the local technician. But you can count on the repairs alone. Only Duty members get the upgrades from me. These are the rules. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_fixer_dialog_2">
		<text>Well, thanks for that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_intro_dialog_0">
		<text>Hi, I need some help with the equipment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_intro_dialog_1">
		<text>You're not the only one after hustle like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_intro_dialog_2">
		<text>So what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_intro_dialog_3">
		<text>Alright, I'll help. I'll repair your stuff, at least. Well, I can even assume that you are one of us already, and upgrade some of your stuff. We were running for our lives, so I left all the tools there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_intro_dialog_4">
		<text>I could fetch those tools for you, if you upgrade my stuff afterwards. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_intro_dialog_5">
		<text>Yeah, of course, Marked One. You're a true friend to Duty, so I'll treat you like one of us. Well, maybe it'll be more expensive. I just need the tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_intro_dialog_6">
		<text>That's a deal, I'll get them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm here about the tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_1">
		<text>What do you got there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_2a">
		<text>Brought you something, a tools for rough work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_2b">
		<text>Brought you something, a tools for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_2c">
		<text>Got you a calibration toolkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_3a">
		<text>Splendid! Well, now I need tools for rough work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_3b">
		<text>Splendid! Well, now I need tools for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_3c">
		<text>Splendid! Well, now I need calibration toolkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_3ab">
		<text>Splendid! Well, now I need tools for rough and fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_3ac">
		<text>Splendid! Well, now I need tools for rough work and calibrations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_3bc">
		<text>Splendid! Well, now I need tools for fine work and calibrations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_azot_repair_bring_dialog_3abc">
		<text>That's all! Now I have a complete set. I can upgrade whatever you want!</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Upgrades by the Freedom (?) technician -->
	
	<string id="out_chef_repair_intro_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello. Are you the one repairing stuff around here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_intro_dialog_1">
		<text>Howdy. I'm also the one upgrading everything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_intro_dialog_2">
		<text>That means you'll help me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_intro_dialog_3">
		<text>I would, but I just got here, so I don't have any tools yet. Well, someone like you could help me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_intro_dialog_4">
		<text>Yeah, I can look around. So that's a deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_intro_dialog_5">
		<text>Deal!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm here about the tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_1">
		<text>What do you got there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_2a">
		<text>Brought you something, a tools for rough work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_2b">
		<text>Brought you something, a tools for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_2c">
		<text>Got you a calibration toolkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_3a">
		<text>That's great! Well, now I need tools for rough work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_3b">
		<text>That's great! Well, now I need tools for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_3c">
		<text>That's great! Well, now I need calibration toolkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_3ab">
		<text>That's great! Well, now I need tools for rough and fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_3ac">
		<text>That's great! Well, now I need tools for rough work and calibrations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_3bc">
		<text>That's great! Well, now I need tools for fine work and calibrations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_chef_repair_bring_dialog_3abc">
		<text>That's all! My tool set is complete now. Thanks a lot!</text>
    </string>
</string_table>