<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows–1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- ARENA -->
    <string id="bar_arena_guard_dialog_0">
        <text>You are not allowed here noob, this area is off limits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_guard_dialog_1">
        <text>Why? What's happening here? Do I need to register my weapons or something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_guard_dialog_2">
        <text>No. This is the ARENA, if you want to know more, ask our manager. But only VIP's or Duty members can enter, or visitors during performances if they buy a ticket.. For noobs like you, there is a bypass road nearby.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_0">
        <text>I want to talk about being a VIP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_1">
        <text>If you are not a VIP then go ask our manager for details and stop wasting my time!</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_2">
        <text>I have a special VIP card, so open up pal!</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_3">
        <text>Show it to me! Okay, Marked One.. "The Slayer". Seems you are not such a noob as I thought before... it's your lucky day, the door is unlocked, enjoy.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_21">
        <text>I am a member of Duty now.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_211">
        <text>Really? Let me check.. yeah, you are on the list. Hmm, a newcomer to Duty and already a VIP, damned Voronin... Okay, anyway, the door is unlocked, you can walk around.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_22">
        <text>I am not.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_23">
        <text>I've beaten the best so now what?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_231">
        <text>Go and speak to the boss, he will give you a pass.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_2311">
        <text>Ok thanks</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_24">
        <text>Can we not come to some sort of an.....arrangement...?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_241">
        <text>Absolutely not! Well... unless you have 8000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_2411">
        <text>Now you're talking my language, here you go.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_24111">
        <text>Well, would you look at that! It seems you are on the list. Sorry for the misunderstanding. Please feel free to pass through here whenever you wish.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_241111">
        <text>Thank you sir!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_2412">
        <text>No, I don't have it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_24121">
        <text>Well then get out of my sight!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_arena_guard_vip_241211">
        <text>Damn capitalist!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_welcome_0">
        <text>Welcome to ARENA headquarters! I don't remember you being here before. I guess you will be interested to know that this building is not always closed to visitors, only for newcomers.. If you want to know more details, just talk to me, I will give you all the necessary information that will clear your head of the rumors.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_welcome_1">
        <text>Thanks, I will think about it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_0">
        <text>I have couple of questions...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_1">
        <text>Ask, i'm listening.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_11">
        <text>What is this place?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_111">
        <text>It's my business in this crazy world. Arena - a place where every stalker can test his skills in a duel with mutants. If this stalker attains enough credit for his skills, he can raise a lot of money. Half a year ago myself and a friend cleared a nest of bloodsuckers. We drove the last, quite mature one, into a house, all exits were closed and we sat and waited. Next thing my mate tells me - "let's have a bet. I will go in and kill him in 2 minutes or less". He entered the house and did it. This gave me the idea of ARENA. We made a deal with Duty, took this hangar and made converted it into an arena. So now we have our own business in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_12">
        <text>Where do these mutants come from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_121">
        <text>We have a deal with Duty. Before, they used to kill all of them, and then I suggested money in exchange for the injured or weak ones. They quickly agreed and ever since then we have an almost unlimited source of living mutants. And I'm even stuffing the dead beasts corpses and selling them outside the Zone. It's very popular now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_13">
        <text>Where are you from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_131">
        <text>Lot's of places. I'm not even sure any more what to call my homeland. I spent a long time in Africa, then few years in Equador. Then I heard about a wonderfull place and heard that I can get lot's of riches there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_info_10">
        <text>No more questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_rules_0">
        <text>What are the rules?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_rules_1">
        <text>Oh, the rules, they are quite simple. I figured them out myself. There is a cell in which we place a mutant. You pay money, and you choose the time in which you will kill this beast. If you are lucky - there is a reward. If not - I keep the money for myself. If you die - I promised to bury you with full honors. The shorter the time you choose - the larger the reward will be. You can also get extra bonuses if you become number 1.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_rules_2">
        <text>Which one?</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_rules_3">
        <text>A free passage through arena during day light, we have a strong security here to keep out idiots and dumbasses. Just to keep this place safer.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_0">
        <text>I want to fight. Which beast do you have available at the moment?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1">
        <text>Nobody to fight for now. Come back here later, when the next Duty mutant raid returns.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_2">
        <text>We have 2 dogs. Quite ugly and big beasts, pretty well beaten. Also angry, like my mother-in-law.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_21">
        <text>I will try. Let these dogs out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_22">
        <text>Nah, I wont fight with a dog.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_100">
        <text>Now, give me the money for participating. 1000 rubles please.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_101">
        <text>Here are your 1000 rubles</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_105">
        <text>I don't have enough money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1051">
        <text>Too bad, come back again when you're a little more flush...</text>
    </string>    
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_7">
        <text>We have quite a fluffy and scratchy pseudodog at the moment. Not sure how Duty captured it, because this beast is real crazy, I'm surprised they all survived the capture.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_71">
        <text>Let's play with this pseudodog.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_72">
        <text>Nah, I wont fight with it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_700">
        <text>Now, give me the money for participating. 1500 rubles please.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_701">
        <text>Here are your 1500 rubles</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_705">
        <text>This cost is too high for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_7051">
        <text>Beggar... I think then it's time for you to leave.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_221">
        <text>Aw, little girl scared by a little doggie? Okay, don't cry...</text>
    </string>
   <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_200">
        <text>Good. Now you should choose the time in which you will kill the mutant. If you succeed you win the reward, if not I keep the fee. Remember, the shorter the time you choose, the bigger the reward.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_201">
        <text>10 seconds, double the prize.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_202">
        <text>30 seconds, you will win half of the bet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_203">
        <text>1 minute. You will win a fifth of the bet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_204">
        <text>I changed my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_205">
        <text>20 seconds, double the prize.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_206">
        <text>40 seconds, you will win half of the bet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_2041">
        <text>Damn, I had a better opinion about you... I'm not refunding your money!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_300">
        <text>Bet accepted, you have only 10 seconds. The official part is over. Welcome to ARENA.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_301">
        <text>Bet accepted. Official part over. Welcome to arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_302">
        <text>Bet accepted, you have a minute. Official part over. Welcome to arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_303">
        <text>Bet accepted, you have 20 seconds as a beginner. Official part over. Welcome to arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_3">
        <text>A freak in a gasmask. People call them "snorks". Skinny and weak at first glance, but nimble and quick like Jackie Chan. I saw some of his movies when I was a kid....</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_31">
        <text>Give me this snork.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_110">
        <text>For you, 2000 rubles to try.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_111">
        <text>Here are your 2000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_115">
        <text>Sorry. I don't enough have money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1151">
        <text>Beggars in the Zone.. what is this place coming to?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_32">
        <text>Nah, I don't want to fight with a snork.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_321">
        <text>You scared that this half rotted freak in a gasmask would make you look bad?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_4">
        <text>At this time it's a real luck. We captured a young bloodsucker. He is still a bit naive, but already a worthy opponent.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_41">
        <text>Okey, get this bloodsucker ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_120">
        <text>3000 rubles entry fee and I'll ready the bloodsucker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_121">
        <text>Here is your money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_125">
        <text>I don't have that much.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1251">
        <text>Oh shit, even my son has this kinda money, and he is still a child!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_42">
        <text>Nah, I don't want to fight a bloodsucker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_421">
        <text>Aha! You are frightened. As I thought...</text>
    </string>
   <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_5">
        <text>At this time we have a small gnome like creature in a black cloak - burer they are called. It was really lucky that Duty got him. He almost took down the whole squad before they wrangled this bastard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_51">
        <text>Get this freak ready for action!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_130">
        <text>Not so fast. First pay me the 5000 ruble entrance fee.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_131">
        <text>Here is your money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_135">
        <text>I don't have enough right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1351">
        <text>If you are so poor, then get lost!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_52">
        <text>Nah, I don't want to fight with a burer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_521">
        <text>He is half of your size man, why are you so afraid of him?</text>
    </string>
   <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_6">
        <text>Oh, this is special case. Not sure how they captured him, but he is a real monster! To everyone, his name is "Beast". If you will beat this bastard i will give you a special VIP-card so you can get around there anytime you want. So, do we have a deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_61">
        <text>Agreed. Give me that "Beast".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_140">
        <text>Ok, if you agree, pay me 5000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_141">
        <text>Here are your 5000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_145">
        <text>I don't have enough money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_1451">
        <text>Even stalkers are poor now... Good times we live in...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_62">
        <text>Nope, Beast is too much for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_621">
        <text>Actually, even I fear this beast, so I don't blame you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_start_0">
        <text>I am here about the last fight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_start_11">
        <text>Hello! We have a new beast here. Wanna try your skills on it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_start_21">
        <text>So, what are you waiting for? Come on, go through this cell door to your destiny.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_start_31">
        <text>Sorry, nobody to fight for now. Wait a day or so until we get another mutant delivery.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_start_41">
        <text>Well done! Here is your reward. If you ever want to fight for more money, just come back here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_start_51">
        <text>Sorry brother, you lost. Come back and try next time if you want.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_manager_start_6">
        <text>We don't have any new beasts yet, come back later.</text>
    </string>

<!-- Barman first meet -->

    <string id="bar_barman_meet_0">
        <text>Hey, Marked One! You've got something for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_meet_1">
        <text>Ratcatcher; you wanted me to help him, right? Well, here's the alibi needed so that the Military will let him off the hook.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_meet_2">
        <text>Great work! Fast, clean service. We could use a guy like you around here. Apparently you're looking for that Strelok fellow, am I right? How about you work for us some more? You never know what might pop up about him. World's a small place, I can guarantee you that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_meet_3">
        <text>Sure, but no suicide missions. Am I clear?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_meet_4">
        <text>OK stalker, I've got something for you then; still high risk, but take it or leave it. There's some boys down in the Dark Valley, at the old stables, and they need help with dealing with the local dime-a-dozen cultists – the Monolith goons. They've managed to not get killed by both thugs and fanatics, so they must be doing something right. Maybe you already know since you're involved with Sid, but we traders are interested in learning a route to Pripyat and the NPP, pass the dreaded Brain Scorcher. Apart from this Man of Myth – the so-called "Guide" – nobody is said to have been there and lived to tell the tale.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_meet_5">
        <text>There's something related to the labs in the Dark Valley?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_meet_6">
        <text>Apparently so... Best bet is that the Monolithians got it under their control. I'm not that informed about it. Colonel Petrenko knows best. Go talk to him, he's in the back room. He's deeply invested in this sort of research, mainly because it might lead to these Sin guys he hates so much.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_meet_7">
        <text>Let me back there, I'll talk to him myself.</text>
    </string>
    
    <string id="bar_barman_af_merger_01">
        <text>I wanted to ask...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_af_merger_02">
        <text>Yes?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_af_merger_03">
        <text>Sid told me someone knows about "transmutation" here, and about the device for advanced stalkers.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_af_merger_04">
        <text>I do. They are using it to merge artefacts which sometimes produces more positive effect for stalkers. I recommend you visit our local scientist at Yantar. He is deals with that kind of stuff and can give you more information. Please don't mention him that I told you this though.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_barman_af_merger_05">
        <text>Sure, thanks.</text>
    </string>
    
<!-- Petrenko darkvalley-x18 task -->

    <string id="bar_petrenko_valley_0">
        <text>You're Colonel Petrenko, aren't you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_valley_1">
        <text>Ah, so you're that guy Sidorovich has been playing around with. Fresh from a Death Truck too, how golden. The name is Petrenko – Colonel of Duty, second-in-command of General Voronin. Nice to meet you stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_valley_2">
        <text>Nice to meet you too. Now, what's with this whole business in the Dark Valley?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_valley_3">
        <text>Simply put, we've had some stalker boys telling us some intriguing things about Monolith activities. Apparently there's a lab named X18 under their base. I'm not sure what exactly is buried under there, but neither do the Monolith. They can't open it yet, or maybe they don't want to. The information is pretty sketchy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_valley_4">
        <text>And you want in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_valley_5">
        <text>Exactly. Whatever is in those labs will attract... the Sins – those damn aberrations. Go to the old barn, the mates over there have a pretty solid plan. Bring me whatever you can find after your digging, and I'll reward you handsomely. Any bit of info, however small, can be crucial.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_valley_6">
        <text>Really? Sounds like old crap to me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_valley_7">
        <text>Just think about it for a second: the old experiments back in the day were pretty extensive and could provide the backbone for new ones. That kind of information can be a great bargaining chip for Duty, and Sin will surely show themselves to gather it. One other thing, some people have come back from these underground labs saying they heard voices, or even seen ghosts from the past! This has driven some people mad, but you may learn something, if you don't shit your pants first, ha!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_valley_8">
        <text>OK, I'll go see them and we will talk later.</text>
    </string>

<!-- Petrenko darvalley-x18 task finished -->
    
    <string id="bar_petrenko_x18_1">
        <text>Colonel, I've got some documents for you from X18.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_x18_2">
        <text>Hmm... that's interesting. There are some things I already know in there, but there's new details. Voronin will be interested in those I'm sure. There is also one encrypted file which I can't open with my current equipment. But anyways, the file header indicates it has something to do with the X18 bosses... Anyways, good job stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_x18_3">
        <text>Damn, that Strelok sure loves anonymity. Well, now at least I have new leads.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_x18_4">
        <text>I discovered an old encryption system here, which they used in all labs from what I found. The last global password change was to "top_secret". Maybe you can dig in further if you like.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_x18_5">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string> 
	<string id="bar_petrenko_x18_41">
        <text>By the way, here are the other docs I found in X18.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_petrenko_x18_411">
        <text>Thanks, you have outdone yourself stalker!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_petrenko_x18_4111">
        <text>Sure, no problem.</text>
    </string>
    
<!--vintar start-->
<!-- Bloodsucker King task -->
    
    <string id="bar_petrenko_king_bloodsucker_0">
        <text>Seems we meet again, Colonel.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_king_bloodsucker_1">
        <text>Well, well, you have quite a reputation amongst Duty now, going on a Bloodsucker hunt all by yourself like that. You big damn hero!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_king_bloodsucker_2">
        <text>Yeah...well...don't believe everything you read in the papers.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_king_bloodsucker_3">
        <text>Don't be shy, you'll get used to the fame in due time. Anyway, we received word from Dima about your little "deal". You did good Marked One. Hell, maybe even better that my best men. The Ecologists are filtering out the deadly gases from our base in the factory as we speak. It's sad that so many were killed by those damn Bloodsuckers... I've got to warn you before I give you the key to the lab underneath Rostok: there's a sort of "Bloodsucker King" down there. That's why we sealed it off in the first place - it's a damn nest! If you're really going down there, drag that ugly bastard to Hell for me, will you? Here's the key then. They're all yours, stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_king_bloodsucker_4">
        <text>I've probably pissed him off by killing his children. Might as well finish the job.</text>
    </string>
	
<!-- Bloodsucker King hold -->
    
    <string id="bar_petrenko_bsking_hold_0">
        <text>Hey, about that Bloodsucker King...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_bsking_hold_1">
        <text>Yeah?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_bsking_hold_2">
        <text>Maybe we should name him Dracula or something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_bsking_hold_3">
        <text>...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_petrenko_bsking_hold_4">
        <text>(I wonder why he's giving me that look...?)</text>
    </string>
    
    <string id="bar_petrenko_bsking_killed_0">	
        <text>Problem with "Dracula" solved.</text>	
    </string>	
    <string id="bar_petrenko_bsking_killed_1">	
        <text>Yeah? Did you kill him?</text>	
    </string>	
    <string id="bar_petrenko_bsking_killed_2">	
        <text>Yes! I think i finished him</text>	
    </string>	
    <string id="bar_petrenko_bsking_killed_3">	
        <text>Great! Good job, stalker!</text>	
    </string>	
    <string id="bar_petrenko_bsking_killed_4">	
        <text>Thanks.</text>	
    </string>
	
<!--Petrenko: documents task-->
    
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_0">
		<text>I want to discuss the docs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_1">
		<text>What documents? And what do you want to discuss?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_2">
		<text>Sidorovich sent me to search the old facility in the Forest. That's everything I've found there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_2n">
		<text>Sidorovich sent me to search the old facility in the Forest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_2n1">
		<text>And how is the search doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_2n20">
		<text>I'm working on it but I need some more time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_2n2">
		<text>I came to tell you that I won't be doing this anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_3n">
		<text>Are you sure? This is not urgent: you can do it later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_4na">
		<text>Really? Well, I could actually continue searching if you're not in a hurry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_5na">
		<text>Great, I'm waiting for the results, but don't keep it on back burner!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_4nn">
		<text>Yes, I'm sure, I won't be doing it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_5nn">
		<text>Alright then, I won't try to make you do it. Abort that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_3f">
		<text>Show me what you've got. Wow, that's a big pile of papers! Let me take a quick look... there's something about the old entrance to the X-18. Have you already been to that place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_4f">
		<text>No, but I can pay it a visit - I know where it's located.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_5f">
		<text>Then look there and then we'll think what to do with that information. Go now, and I need to think some more about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_4ff">
		<text>Yes, I'd read it through and decided to check there too; I found a whole journal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_5ff">
		<text>You're fast! Well, Marked One, great work... for which I can pay double! Sin doesn't even know about these documents, so that'll help us in the negotiations and stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_6ff">
		<text>And what's there in these papers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_7ff">
		<text>The only thing clear is that nothing's clear. This is very complicated and vague. I can't tell you anything specific. But that's our leverage over the Sin, and that's exactly what we need. According to the records, experiments got out of control fast, that's why they couldn't clean up the mess and destroy the notes. Or decided that nobody will look for that in the Zone. Anyway, I want you to find some more docs for me. You should look for it at Lake Yantar.\n\nYantar is full of mystery and there are so many mutants that not everyone can get there. So there aren't many willing. And those eggheads are always looking for people to clear out the local hangars and basements. There may be some docs. Get there and take everything that you'll find. But first talk to Sakharov, he'll help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_8ff">
		<text>Alright. These papers again... when will it all end?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_4fn">
		<text>No, I have no desire to go there. I've already ran through it. I don't think there's anything there left.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_5fn">
		<text>Yeah, you're right. Well, we already have enough. It'll come in handy. Take your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_3a">
		<text>Show me what you've got. Yes, interesting papers. Let me take a quick look... nothing to work with, sadly. Are you sure you'd found everything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_4a">
		<text>Hmm, I can look for some more, if necessary.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_5a">
		<text>Yeah, you'd better do that: there may be something left - though I'm not sure about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_4an">
		<text>Yes, I had looked it through. Every corner. So much time has passed: no way something is still remaining.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_done_3b">
		<text>Show me what you got. Yes, interesting papers. Let me take a quick look... nothing to work with, sadly. Although, there's something about the old entrance to the X-18. Have you already been to that place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_part2_0">
		<text>I'm here to talk about the old entrance to the X-18.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_part2_1">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_part2_2a">
		<text>Nothing found yet, but I'll continue the search.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_part2_2b">
		<text>I've been there and found some journal. Very interesting stuff!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_task_part2_3a">
		<text>Let me know if you find something.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Barkeep: documents task -->

	<string id="forest_docs_barman_start_talk_0">
		<text>Hi, Barkeep, I have a business matter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_barman_start_talk_1">
		<text>Well, business is always good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_barman_start_talk_2">
		<text>Sid told me about the docs, but he said that he quit the case. Do you know something about that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_barman_start_talk_3">
		<text>Well, of course. I'd mind my own business, but I'm safe under Duty's protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_barman_start_talk_4">
		<text>Cut to the chase.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_barman_start_talk_5">
		<text>You'll have to get to another place and look there: it's deserted and dangerous, stalkers are a rare sight there. You know, the Zone often "freezes" the places, like stopping the time there. That's why many are left untouched, stay in one condition for fifteen to twenty years. I'm sure there's something left. Go look there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_barman_start_talk_6">
		<text>Well, that's good, but what place are you talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_barman_start_talk_7">
		<text>That's a mine or something like that; located In the Forest, to the north of the Dark Valley. I've even heard that the scientists were experimenting on the rocks there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_barman_start_talk_8">
		<text>Yeah, very interesting. Well, I'll look into that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_docs_barman_start_talk_9">
		<text>And don't take your findings to me, go straight to Petrenko. He'll be glad and he will pay you.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Petrenko: Yantar documents task -->

	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_0">
		<text>I want to discuss the Yantar documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_1a">
		<text>And I already thought you've forgotten about them... did you bring them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_2a">
		<text>Yes, all the documents from Yantar - take them. I've digged everywhere - there's nothing more to look for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_3a">
		<text>Great! Now let me look through them. It seems that someone seriously miscalculated and did not pay enough attention to safety...\n\nI knew it was a thing!.. even I have goosebumps reading this. And this, this... well, complete sloppiness! But still not fully clear.\n\nListen, it would be a huge understatement to say you helped Duty; you simply saved us! Here's your reward... and Duty owes you now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_4a">
		<text>That's good to know! And a reward won't miss me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_1b">
		<text>You got all the documents?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_2b">
		<text>I only found these, and there's nothing more to look for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_3b">
		<text>So, let's see what you have there... the most important is missing! We must look further.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_4ba">
		<text>Well, I'll continue the search: perhaps I hadn't noticed something...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_5ba">
		<text>Okay, I'm waiting. But you better hurry up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_4bb">
		<text>Sorry, but I only found what I brought. There's nothing more there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_5bb">
		<text>Listen, it would be a huge understatement to say you helped Duty; you simply saved us! What kind of reward do you want: an outfit, or a gun?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_6bba">
		<text>An outfit would be fine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_7bba">
		<text>Here's a great outfit for you - we used to give these to our recruits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_6bbb">
		<text>A gun. Does any ammo go along with it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_7bbb">
		<text>Certainly! Here's your new weapon and some ammo for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_1c">
		<text>So, how's the search going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_2c">
		<text>I refuse to look for these documents - not interested. Besides, it's too difficult.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_docs_task_done_3c">
		<text>Understandable. Well, thank you for what you've brought anyway; Duty owes you a massive favor now! Here's your reward for the effort.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Bar attacked by merc helicopters -->
<!-- after task done let's move to outskirts -->

	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_02">
        <text>I received your call for help, what can I do?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_2">
        <text>Thanks for coming, Marked One. We've been caught off-guard by this attack. Damn these mercs; they've gotten the big stuff out! Is this retribution?! Anyways, Arnold was up on the water tower with the RPG, but he bit the dust. Please, take the choppers down while we hold them here! I'll mark his last position on the map – the RPG is all yours.</text>
    </string> 
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_21">
        <text>I'll get right on it!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_03">
        <text>The helis are destroyed.</text>
    </string> 
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_3">
        <text>Stalker, we can't thank you enough! My men and I will stay and clean things up and hopefully re-open the bar soon. We locked it down when the mercs attacked. I`ve unlocked the door now and will start refurbishments right away.</text>
    </string> 
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_31">
        <text>I see, well, glad I could help out. So, what happened to Voronin and Barman?</text>
    </string> 
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_311">
        <text>With the help of our best soldiers, Barman and Voronin were escorted to the Outskirts of Pripyat. They've set up a new Stalker Bar there. You should go there and meet up with them – there are some problems in the Outskirts, as you'll see. Oh, by the way: I think I know how to thank you! If you go towards the Bar, you'll get into that house... There is a door - we used to hide something behind it... Anyway, it's open now - and you can grab everything what's in there!</text>
    </string> 
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_3111">
        <text>Yeah, thanks for that. I'll leave right away.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_0">
        <text>About the helis.</text>
    </string> 
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_4">
        <text>Hey Stalker, how is it going out there?</text>
    </string> 
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_41">
        <text>I'm out of rockets; do you have any?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_411">
        <text>Take these, they're all we have left.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_4111">
        <text>Let's hope it's enough.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_petrenko_heli_talk_42">
        <text>I'm working on it.</text>
    </string>
    
<!--bar loner side task -->

	<string id="bar_help_to_loners_0">
        <text>Hey stalker, we have a problem here. Interested in doing our group a little favour?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_help_to_loners_1">
        <text>Sure, tell me about it.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_help_to_loners_2">
        <text>Here is the deal: we are group of newcomers who are trying to reach the 100 Rads Bar, but a bunch of Pseudodogs are nesting near the Bar entrance and are blocking the way. If you can help us, I will share some loot with you. I've sent you the PDA coordinates, just in case. Good luck!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_help_to_loners_3">
        <text>Sorry, another time.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_help_to_loners_4">
        <text>Don't worry, we are not going anywhere... maybe you will have a heart and change your mind sometime.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_help_to_loners_5">
        <text>OK.</text>
    </string>
    
<!--bar loner side task done -->
    
	<string id="bar_loners_task_done_0">
        <text>Any progress in killing all those mangy mutts?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_loners_task_done_1">
        <text>Not yet, but I'm working on it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_loners_task_done_2">
        <text>Eliminated. You can walk through.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_loners_task_done_3">
        <text>Thank you, stalker. Some of us already wanted to return to Garbage, but you saved us! By the way, here is a reward. We hope you'll find plenty of artifacts in the future!</text>
    </string>
    
<!--bar loner chitchat -->
    
 	<string id="bar_loners_info_0">
        <text>Y'know, we decided to stay here for now. It's quite a comfortable place for trading – lots of stalkers and Duty guys pass by, so we can gather what we need. Maybe later we will move out to a better place. Though your efforts weren't for nothing; at least you helped all the other Stalkers who will come to Bar in the near future.</text>
    </string>
    
<!--bar informer -->

	<string id="bar_informer_0">
        <text>Hello, Marked One. My name is Snitch and I know many things – little stories that may rouse your interest. Wanna know something interesting about the Zone?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_1">
        <text>500 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_11">
        <text>A while ago, a group of stalkers attempted to reach the center of the Zone, right through the Brain Scorcher. As you must know, the path to Pripyat and beyond is covered with deadly psy-emissions that makes your brain boil – turning humans into a soulless beasts. However, it is said that the group marched on and disappeared. Hearsay among expert stalkers is that members of the group returned, but no one really knows how they did. No one really knows if this even happened, though it makes you wonder...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_2">
        <text>1000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_21">
        <text>You know the bandit base in the Dark Valley? They keep all their stuff in the underground storage, though it is heavy guarded. If someone is crazy enough to rob them, then he could sell their supplies to Barkeep and get some good money out of it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_3">
        <text>1500 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_31">
        <text>Scientists in Yantar always need body parts of mutants for their experiments – they pay with hard cash and they've got plenty of it, so you can bring in as much as you want. They also seek out willing stalkers for field experiments with animals and anomalies. Their assistants get to access their advanced eco suits – quite useful to survive heavily radiated areas and deadly anomalies, even psy-emissions fields. It could be useful in places such as the Radar, Lost Factory or beyond that. Don't go thinking it makes you immune to the Scorcher though...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_4">
        <text>2000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_41">
        <text>There's a place called North Hills past Radar. It's rumoured that there is a stash there that is beyond what anyone could imagine. Apparently it requires a leap of faith, whatever that means. They say you can find it on the “W.C. island” and you'll know when you see it... It is also rumoured that a map to this 'wonder stash' is hidden in the forest somewhere in a humongous anomaly formation.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_5">
        <text>Do you have enough money?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_51">
        <text>Yes.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_52">
        <text>No, sorry.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_informer_53">
        <text>Return when you have some cash.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_informer_6">
        <text>Do you have anything else?</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="bar_informer_7">
        <text>I'm sorry, Marked One, but I don't have any more info for your right now. Come back later.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_16">
        <text>1000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_informer_18">
        <text>I've heard there is something hidden in a code locked place that could be of huge value put in the right hands. Rumour is that the code to the door was written down on a piece of paper and torn in half. Apparently there is some loner mad scientist in the North Hills who has one half. Not sure how true it is.</text>
    </string>
	
<!-- Voronin side tasks -->
	
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_join_0">
		<text>Greetings. I'm Voronin, leader of Duty. Please, have a look around, but do not trouble us. We don't like drunkards and rowdys, so don't even think about firing a weapon in here, unless you want to meet your maker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_join_1">
        <text>I want to join Duty forces.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_join_2">
        <text>It's not that simple. To join us as an outsider, you will need to do one important job for us.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_join_3">
		<text>What I have to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_join_4">
        <text>I need to send this delivery to one of our squadron officers near the Rostok Factory; they are having troubles there, and are in desperate need of supplies. Deliver them without a hitch, without stealing anything, and for me it will be enough to trust you. Can you do that for us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_join_5a">
        <text>Of course, I will be back soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_join_5b">
        <text>I need to think about it.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_0">
        <text>So, can I join Duty?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_10">
        <text>You finished the task?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_1">
        <text>Yes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_11">
        <text>Good job! Now you just need to make monetary investment. 5000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_1111">
        <text>I have money.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_11112">
        <text>Now, you need to take the Duty oath. Repeat after me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_11113">
        <text>Let's do it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_3">
        <text>"I am stately swear to protect my country against the Zone and any stalker which would like to help our goal. I'll never go against the moral code and stop everyone who will join our enemies and support living of this abormination! We are Duty, Zone must be stopped and only we can do it! hurrah!"</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_4">
        <text>I am stately swear to protect my country against the Zone...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_5">
        <text>Perfect. Now you are officially a member of Duty. As a beginner, you won't get too much - just a basic outfit and the honor that comes from being a member of Duty. Your commander is me for this time, but if any of our guys ask for help, never refuse. One for all and all for one!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_6">
        <text>I'm glad to be part of Duty.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_join_done_1112">
        <text>I've changed my mind, it's too much for me, sorry. See you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_join_done_2">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_join_done_21">
        <text>Hurry up, I won't wait forever.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_done_101">
        <text>So, can you make a monetary investment now? 5000 rubles.</text>
    </string>

    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_job_0">
        <text>Do you have any job for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_job_6">
        <text>Finish this first.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_job_5">
        <text>I've got your first official task. You can prove your worth to us by helping our recon group which is currently at Lake Yantar. We sent a messenger to them, but we have had no news from him  for 2 whole days. Something happened, so now we are sending you. Your task is to figure out the current situation at the camp and assist them with whatever they need. Also try to find the missing messenger and bring me his badge. Can you deal with it, soldier?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_job_51">
        <text>Of course, General! I'll do it.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_job_511">
        <text>Don't let us down, we are counting on you.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_job_52">
        <text>I need time to think about it. I'll be back later.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_job_521">
        <text>Don't put it under carpet for too long, soldier. Our guys may be in danger.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_job_done_1">
        <text>I am here about my task.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_job_done_2">
        <text>Well done, soldier. Not only did you figure out what was going on, but you also returned the badge of our messenger. He was a good man, we will miss him. I will send this back to his relatives back in Moscow so they may grieve properly... And you, soldier, from this impressive showcase of skills and knowhow, I promote you to the rank of Junior Sergeant! You get your reward and also access to our armory for a special shooter. Talk to Ivancov, he will give you a proper one.</text>
    </string> 
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_job_done_3">
        <text>Nice job, soldier. You figured out the problem and wiped the floor with those bandits... However, you didn't find our messenger? Not even a badge? I assumed the poor lad died out there and wanted to give something to his family... no? Well, anyway, you did your job, soldier. From this moment on, you are a Junior Sergeant! Please continue to work with this dedication.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_1">
        <text>Yo, Marked One. Interesting day, right? Lot's of new faces, fresh beer, blood and puke stains in the corners - and idiots sneaking around, not knowing what's good for them...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_2">
        <text>You're not much of a people person I see.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_3">
        <text>I can't say that I really hate them... But sometimes, when they start asking stupid questions or pester me for favors, I'd massacre them with a battle axe. Let's end this useless chitchat and go straight to business, if you don't' mind. You have some reason to be here... right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_11">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_111">
        <text>Really. Really? Really... You are telling me that you are genuinely interested in a bored, fat guy on guard duty? O-kay bucko, what you wanna know?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_1111">
        <text>How did you get here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_1112">
        <text>What are you selling?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_1113">
        <text>How good are you at upgrading weapons?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_11111">
        <text>It's a long story. Before I got here, I was just an ordinary lazy coder and webmaster for some game company... Hmm, what was the name... ah... can't remember. We had some success with a couple of post-apocalyptic shooters, then our boss went mad and fired all of us and went off to some Caribbean island... Something like that. I had no idea how to continue earning the daily bread for my big family without working 2-3 part-time jobs. And then, as you already know, the Zone appeared, lots of newbies wanted to find some meaning in their lives and some profit as well. So why should I stay away from modern trends? As the result, I dug up an old pistol that my grandfather left to me, bought ammo for it, took some money I had stashed, and came here. I learned how to maintain weapons and gear, upgrading and tweaking them, selling them in bulk... So here I am, managing the armory, sending big checks back home for my wife and kids. That's my story.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_11112">
        <text>I sell many things, rare weapons which you won't find anywhere else, but it's all for Duty members. If you want to get some pieces of this golden mine, you need to join Duty first. Weapons from the armory is forbidden for our ordinary soldiers though, you need to be given a high rank.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_talk_about_11113">
        <text>Good enough that Duty didn't ask for a contribution when I wanted to join. I have some natural talent, but my mentor taught me everything. He was a strange guy, wore glasses, very focused on his work, kind of weird. When he heard my story, he taught me the fundamentals about weapons, then moved on to something else when he got bored of me. I've tried finding him, but the nickname he used when teaching me was most definitely a fake. It's scary to think that he only taught me one-fifth of his knowledge... He has to be a university graduate for sure...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_1">
        <text>Voronin sent me. He said you had a special gift.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_11">
        <text>Yeah, I already prepared a nice gun for you. Seems like you proved yourself to get this. Here, take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_111">
        <text>[Take it]</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_1111">
        <text>Modified MP5A4 with fixed buttstock created by Heckler and Koch in 1966. It has built-in sight, has big magazine to stuff your enemies with lead, light weight and comfortable to use for secret recon operations. Have fun with it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_11111">
        <text>Thanks, bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_1">
        <text>Listen my friend, for now we have a quite complicated task for you... As you know, we are in a state of war with Freedom. Their ideals are a threat to our mission, and they are a very resourceful foe. That's why I want to keep an eye on them. I need you to take this bug and get through to their base in the Outskirts and place it on the window sill as you enter bar on the left. Any information that we can get from this will help us get rid of these buffoons. I will send a password to your PDA. You will need this to pass their guard. The Swamp is blocked by Military for now, so I asked a guide to escort you and bypass the usual paths to go there. He is waiting for you. Oh, and I suggest you don't wear your uniform, they won't appreciate it. While you are there, snoop around the bar and see if you can get any other intelligence or items that may be useful.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_11">
        <text>Just call me 007.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_111">
        <text>Try to be a little more discreet than a Hollywood blockbuster though. Good luck.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_work_1">
        <text>I'm here about the bug.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_work_11">
        <text>Did you plant it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_work_2">
        <text>Not yet, I'm working on it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_work_21">
        <text>Hurry up, they change the password about every week or so.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_done_1">
        <text>All done, I got a flash drive and set the bug.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_done_11">
        <text>Hah, you did it! Good job Sergeant, now it will be easier for us to figure out what's going on in their "secret chambers". You proved yourself worthy to us, and even more! You acted like a true professional by infiltrating enemy lines and getting us important intelligence. For that, I am giving you a position of Lieutenant and also a special present! Go and see Ivancov on the roof.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_done_2">
        <text>All done, but I had to kill all of them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_done_21">
        <text>Sergeant, you acted without any tact. Even by killing all of them, there are twice punks waiting to take their place. Didn't you think about it? The long-term benefits would've eclipsed what you did. At least you got a flashdrive with some intelligence info in case they try to strike back. For that, I am giving you a position of Lieutenant. Now, dismissed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_done_3">
        <text>All done, but I killed everyone and didn't get any intelligence.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_done_31">
        <text>Sergeant! How could you be this sloppy and hotheaded?! You just murdered them all and completely disregarded my orders! What will we do now?! We'll have a full-on war with the rest of these punks brandishing Lukash as their martyr! And we've got to intelligence to counter that! Marked One, you're hereby dismissed from Duty in shame! Take your money and leave me at once!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_done_8a">
		<text>All done... but I had to return the flash drive - they'd spotted me. The good thing is, they hadn't noticed the bug and I managed to get out freely.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_done_9a">
		<text>Yeah, these are not the results I've been waiting for... at least the op went successfully. Anyway, you passed, sergeant: now it will be easier for us to figure out what's going on in their "secret chambers".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_done_8b">
		<text>All done: the bug is set... but I completely forgot about the other intelligence. I'll get back there and get it.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_2">
        <text>Hi mate. Voronin said you have something special for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_21">
        <text>Yeah, of course, I already cleaned up this toy especially for you. I am sure you will like it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_211">s
        <text>[Take it]</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_2111">
        <text>OC-14-4A "Groza-4" bullpup assault rifle which uses 9x39mm special rounds. It was designed by TsKIB SOO in Russia and has quite good accuracy characteristics. You can create a hole into anyone even from a distance of 200 metres. Hard weapon for hard guys like you. It also supports addons like a grenade launcher the all the good stuff. I improved some properties, so it's modified into a, how should I say... uber-killing weapon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_21111">
        <text>Thanks again, bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_0">
        <text>Good day, Lieutenant. Want to drink something? Or you're interested in another dirty job? OK then, listen... We sent a squad to a Construction Site road almost 5 days ago, but we haven't had a sitrep since. I guess their radio signal isn't getting through from their position. I need you to figure out what happened to our strike team. The reason I sent them there was to investigate a rumors about some strange new species of mutants, and document anything about such a species. Are you ready to go look into the secrets of this area?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_1">
        <text>Of course, I will find them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_2">
        <text>Right then, good luck Lieutenant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_work_1">
        <text>I'm here about the raid group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_work_11">
        <text>Did you help them out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_work_111">
        <text>Not yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_work_1111">
        <text>Don't slack off, they're relying on you. Go go go!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_work_12">
        <text>Yes, I did.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_done_1">
        <text>Wow, Lieutenant, just wow. That had to be rough, but you did it with honor. Not only did you save our strike team, but also another one near the pump station, and we got the information we needed about this new mutant. Looks like it was born from the Burers coming in contact with the radioactive mucus of the lake's water. We should warn the scientists and stalkers to stay far from it. And you, my friend, for your incredible service to our cause, attain the highest rank of our group - Major! From now, all Duty groups need to respect you and act accordingly. Ivancov has some sort of "ultimate weapon" for you, which will win you every battle you partake in. Be proud, Major!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_done_11">
        <text>Not bad Lieutenant, not bad... At least half of our team is alive, and you did your mission as expected. However, our guys who researched the new mutants died, and the bulk of their observations were lost. We will need to consult the Ecologists about what we should do next... And you, my friend, for your honorable service to our cause, attain the highest rank of our group - Major! Here is your reward for your help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_done_12">
        <text>Lieutenant, I'm sad to admit it, but you failed us... Too many good soldiers died there, and for what? We even didn't get any information about the strange mutants, only your words, and that's not enough. We needed scientific data, which only our group could produce... Despite your service to our cause, I must discharge you from Duty for this failure. I will give you money for your troubles, but I think from this moment on our roads must diverge.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_done_13">
		<text>I'm afraid most of your men are dead...</text>
	</string>	
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_job_done_2">
        <text>Thanks, I appreciate it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_0">
        <text>Yes, my friend, do you want to deal with Sin? I guess you know they are quite severe guys and trouble us often. They extorted from us valuable information which we need to take back. Petrenko doesn't like it one bit, but their boss suggested a solution to us: they will send a negotiator who will propose their terms for a possible agreement. If we agree to them, they will give us back our valuable information. Can you figure it out, Sergeant, and become our spokesman?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_1">
        <text>Of course, I will shake out it from him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_2">
        <text>Go luck Sergeant, and let your goal light up your way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_done_0">
        <text>It was a hell of a job, but I did it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_done_1">
        <text>Exceptional Major! You not only got what we needed, but also helped us to give Sin a false sense of security! You've earned my praise, I am proud of you. And for that, I bestow upon you a special weapon! Ivancov is waiting for you. By the way, Sid said the Ecos in Yantar need help with something, go see if you can help them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_done_12">
        <text>Well, you got rid of Sin for good... But what will the others think of us as negotiators? You didn't end talks with this guy peacefully. You could've tried harder... At least we got the information that was lost. Here is your reward. By the way, Sid said the Ecos in Yantar need help with something, go see if you can help them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_done_13">
        <text>You failed me, Major. We got only parts of the stolen information. How can we stay here now that our positions are compromised? All that because of your inability to negotiate with anybody except yourself. You can't stay in Duty with such sloppy results. I will pay you, but it's not the result I expected out of you. Sid said the Ecos in Yantar need help, go and see if you can do any better for them.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_done_131">
        <text>Sorry, I don't know how it went wrong.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_done_14">
        <text>Seems like you still have work to do with the Dark stalkers!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_done_141">
        <text>Yes, ok, I'm on it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_new_job_alter_done_2">
        <text>Thanks, I tried my best.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_veronin_dolg_last_no_job">
        <text>Not now my friend. Duty has no troubles as of now, and we have you to thank for that, Major!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_30">
        <text>So... I`m back for another gift.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_3">
        <text>You really are some insane do-all killer robot, aren't you...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_31">
        <text>Really now...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_311">
        <text>Yeah... You are like the Terminator. Maybe you're even some cyborg sent by NATO to clean up the Zone. Or maybe his is all a VR experiment and I'm just some NPC you're talking to. I don't know, the point is that you're scary...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_3111">
        <text>I asure you that I'm as normal as you... OK, bad example, but you know what I mean.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_31111">
        <text>Sureee.... Hey, at least I can hand you another cool weapon for all your troubles. Here it is, take it! C'mon!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_311111">
        <text>[Take it]</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_3111111">
        <text>Here we go... I present to you the RG-6 developed by TsKIB SOO, also known as 6G-30 - multi-shot and fast grenade launcher specially built for heavy targets like military outposts, high-ground bunkers and even tanks! It fires 40mm grenades and has a six-shot cylinder. This lil' bitch will turn any dumb bastard into a fried piece of meat. Take care of it and have fun!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ivancov_dolg_present_31111111">
        <text>I will. Thanks mate.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leave_dialog_0">
		<text>I've helped you enough, but I have to continue my way alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leave_dialog_1">
		<text>Well, I respect your choice. Thank you for everything you've done for "Duty".</text>
	</string>		
	<!-- Voronin: eliminate the bandits -->
	
   <string id="forest_bandit_job_0">
		<text>I need a serious job; do you have something for me?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_1">
		<text>Hmm, yeah, there's one... special job, so to speak. But it's only for thore who isn't afraid to get their hands dirty.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_2">
		<text>I can't remember the last time mine were clean...</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_3">
		<text>Then listen. There are reports that our posts on the Rostok Factory and in the Forest have been scouted by bandits - even pictures may have been taken. And we don't like a bit of that. Your task is to eliminate these scouts and take all the storage devices. Don't forget about smaller ones such as USB sticks and memory cards.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_4">
		<text>Where can I find these bandits?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_5">
		<text>We know more about the bandits than they know about us: their numbers, location - we have all of that. I'll mark their current position in your PDA. Once you've got there, take care of their snipers and then get rid of the rest. Don't forget about their leader - you'll probably find the data in his den.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_6">
		<text>Got it! Kill the bandits, collect all storage devices and bring them here. But why don't you deal with them yourself?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_7">
		<text>Because the info saying we've been scouted can be wrong: we don't want to attack the bandits in the open - but a lonely stalker won't be that suspicious and won't leave any track. Either way, I'm waiting for the results.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_8">
		<text>Alright, I'll deal with them.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_done_0">
		<text>I've brought you all the stuff, and the bandits are dead.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_done_1">
		<text>Yes, my lads reported me that there was gunfire at the place.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_done_2">
		<text>Did they tell you anything about mercenaries?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_done_3">
		<text>The mercs? No, and what about the mercs?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_done_4">
		<text>It appeared that bandits really did scout your posts. When I grabbed everything, mercenaries appeared, six men. They ordered the scouting, but I have no idea why. I gave them nothing and fought my way out.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_done_5a">
		<text>That's not good news at all, the last thing we need is a confrontation with the mercenaries! But at least they didn't get any information.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_done_5b">
		<text>These mercs are getting annoying, and it's time to do something about this.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_done_6">
		<text>Here, take all the stuff I've found.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_done_7">
		<text>Nice job, and I didn't forget about your reward.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_fail_0">
		<text>I've taken care of the bandits and found all the storage devices, but there was an issue...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_fail_1">
		<text>Yes, my lads reported me that there was gunfire at the place. What issue?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_fail_2">
		<text>It appeared that bandits really did scout your posts. When I grabbed everything, mercenaries appeared, six men. They ordered the scouting, but I have no idea why. It wasn't going to be a fair fight, so I had to give them all the data. Though they didn't let me go in peace, despite their promises.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_fail_3a">
		<text>That's highly disturbing news. I don't even know what that means. Alright, although you couldn't fulfill your mission, at least you've got rid of the bandits. So here's your reward.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_fail_4">
		<text>I did all I could.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_bandit_job_fail_5">
		<text>I know. You aren't a Duty member and don't have to risk your life for our sake. Here's your reward.</text>	
	</string>
	
	<!-- plichko -->
	
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_0">
		<text>Can I help you stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2">
		<text>It's my first time here. Could you tell me a little about this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21">
		<text>Before the accident in '86 this was an industrial area. As you can see, there ain't much left of it now... In the basement by the hangar you'll find the 100 Rads bar. The place is run by the local trader who doubles up as a barman. If you want to trade, talk, get a mission or find out the latest news, that's the place to go. There's also the Arena where you can fight and make some cash. Duty's base is not far from the Arena. If you want to join Duty go straight over there - they'll tell you who to speak to. Oh, by the way, all of this area is protected by Duty so behave and keep your weapons holstered. If you start shooting, the patrol will "calm you down" pretty quickly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_211">
		<text>You said there's a bar here. Can you tell me where exactly it is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2111">
		<text>In the basement behind the hangar...I'll mark it on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21111">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_212">
		<text>You said the Duty base is here. How do I get to it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2121">
		<text>It's not far from the Arena. I've marked it on the map for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21211">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_213">
		<text>You said there's an Arena here? Where exactly is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2131">
		<text>Go out of the hangar with the broken roof and you'll end up right in front of it. I'll mark it on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21311">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_214">
		<text>Thanks again for all the information.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_hunter_start_01">
		<text>Please, can you help me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_start_02">
		<text>What is the problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_start_03">
		<text>I'm so embarrassed! I was returning from the Construction Site when some bandits had mugged me: they took my prized possession, my rifle. I'm too scared to go and get it, so please help me. I'll try to make it worth your while.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_start_04">
		<text>Sure, I'll get it back for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_start_05">
		<text>Sorry, I have more pressing matters to attend to.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_hunter_finish_0">
		<text>About your weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_finish_01">
		<text>Did you get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_finish_02">
		<text>Not yet, I'll have it soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_finish_03">
		<text>Yes, here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_finish_04">
		<text>Wow, thanks very much, you don't know what it means to me. Here is a reward for your trouble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_finish_05">
		<text>Thanks man, take care.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Ivancov: about Garik -->
	
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_0">
		<text>Hello, soldier.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_1">
		<text>Hey. What do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_2">
		<text>Can you help me with something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_3">
		<text>Sure, go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_4">
		<text>Have you met Garik?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_5">
		<text>Yes, of course: we've been comrades for a long time. Has anything happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_6">
		<text>I'm looking for him: he's missing and there's no news about him. Do you know something about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_7">
		<text>Well, he's a pioneer: always looking for something, exploring. Why do you even care?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_8">
		<text>I found his PDA and would want to return it... if that's still possible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_9">
		<text>Last time I've seen him, he was going to Pripyat underground. Look for him there... if you can get there, of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ivancov_about_garik_10">
		<text>Good, thanks a lot.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<!-- Ivancov (or not?): about repair -->
	
	<string id="duty_repair_intro_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey. So you are the local technician? I need some things to be fixed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_repair_intro_dialog_1a">
		<text>Whoa, not so fast, stalker! The rules are different here: I can only deal with the Duty members' equipment... or our good friends', at the very least.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_repair_intro_dialog_2a">
		<text>Is there any way to become such "friend"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_repair_intro_dialog_3a">
		<text>I'm not the one to come up with the rules but you usually need to help the faction; we'll talk once you've proved yourself... but again, I'm not the one to decide.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_repair_intro_dialog_4a">
		<text>I see. Well, thank you anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_repair_intro_dialog_1b">
		<text>Of course, Marked One! People like you are always welcome here. I will repair or upgrade your equipment if you want me to.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_repair_main_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm here to repair a few things of mine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_repair_main_dialog_1a">
		<text>Didn't I tell you only our members and friends are welcome here? Since you are neither, no way I can help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_repair_main_dialog_1b">
		<text>Yeah, I've already heard you helped our guys at the Factory and killed the beasts underground as well. I can repair your equipment if you want me to.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_repair_main_dialog_1c">
		<text>Hey Marked One! I've already heard about the Bar showdown. That's impressing! Now I can repair or even upgrade your equipment if you want me to... unless you need some hi-end upgrades. But if you really need some, talk to Petrenko - he has some special missions for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="duty_repair_main_dialog_1bc">
		<text>Yeah, I've already heard you helped our guys at the Factory and about the Bar showdown. That's impressing! Now I can repair or even upgrade your equipment if you want me to... unless you need some hi-end upgrades. But if you really need some, talk to Petrenko - he has some special missions for you.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Barkeep: about Garik -->
	
	<string id="barmen_about_garik_0">
		<text>Barkeep, I really need your help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_about_garik_1">
		<text>What happened, loner?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_about_garik_2">
		<text>I've been looking for any info about Garik for a long time already - though I'm not even sure if it's a name or nickname.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_about_garik_3">
		<text>You don't mean my bodyguard, right? Well, of course I know Garik; how could I not? Every trader does: the guy brings many artifacts, never haggles. Has something happened to him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_about_garik_4">
		<text>He's missing - which often happens here. I was asked to find him, or at least his body.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Boris -->
   
    <string id="bar_boris_talk_1">
        <text>Hi there... (clears throat) Iiiiiis Boris!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_boris_talk_2">
        <text>Dude, no need to yell, I'm right in front of you... So, what are you doing here at the trashcans? Tourist Delight not serving you well? Or did Barman suddenly forbid serving gopniks?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_boris_talk_3">
        <text>Oy blin, as if you're a prophet! I suppose mixing Pripyat Beer, vodka, wine, Tourist Delight and peanuts ain't the best idea... Oy mama...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_boris_talk_4">
        <text>My condolences. But what kind of slav are you then if you can't hold such a molotov coctail in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_boris_talk_5">
        <text>Ey, ey! Look at this stance! Heels flat on the ground, not like some amerikanski shpion! Adidas tracksuit? Check. Makarov? Check!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_boris_talk_6">
        <text>Okay, okay, bratan, keep calm. I never seen you here before, where the hell did you come from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_boris_talk_7">
        <text>Estonia, brat. The economy in my town went pizdec, so I went nahui and landed here, in the slav promised land. Now I'm free to squat everywhere, and whenever I want! And the economy is simple - do job, get money, buy slightly irradiated and past-expiry-date food! Nothing babushkas recipes won't fix!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_boris_talk_8">
        <text>Well damn, you sure feel at home here. Well, get better comrade, I have to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_boris_talk_9">
        <text>Sure thing! When I get better, I will start my mission of teaching the slav ways to all people who either forgot them, or are too stuborn to accept them. Stay cheeki breeki my friend.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
