<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<!-- agroprom stalker chitchat -->
	<string id="agr_factory_stalker_about_0">
		<text>What's going on here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_stalker_about_1">
		<text>We're fighting, or more specifically, camping out like sitting ducks. Talk to Mole if you want to know more - he's the leader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_stalker_start_0">
		<text>Man, that was a fight and a half - you wouldn't wish something like that on your worst enemy. Those Army boys are getting pretty cocky!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_0">
		<text>Where is the Agroprom Research Institute?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_10">
		<text>Not far from here. Follow the road to the West and you'll come to the Institutes gates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_100">
		<text>I hear the Military have set up a base there, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_120">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Help to Mole -->	
	<string id="agr_krot_help_0">
		<text>Help me, stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_help_10">
		<text>Ok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_0">
		<text>What are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_20">
		<text>I'm coming back from the factory, which is a bit further down the road. I don't know how, but the Army found out about our group. I didn't wait for them to show up and took off as quickly as I could. I hope our boys got out of there 'cause otherwise they won't be alive for much longer - you saw the choppers yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_300">
		<text>I see, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_400">
		<text>I see, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Talk to Mole -->

	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_0">
		<text>Thanks for your help, stalker! If you hadn't shown up, I'd be a dead man by now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_10001">
		<text>I am looking for information about Strelok. Maybe you know something?</text>
	</string>
<!--
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_10002">
		<text>Where is that flash drive now?</text>
	</string>
-->
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_10002">
		<text>Where is this book now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_15001">
		<text>OK, go down this spiral staircase, past a few columns, and you will walk into a machine room. Keep an eye out for a safehouse in one of the rooms nearby, that's where I found that encrypted book with information though was unable to figure it out and the location is vague to me now. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
<!--
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_15001">
		<text>OK, go down this spiral staircase, past a few columns, and you will walk into a machine room. Keep an eye out for a broken airvent in one of the rooms nearby, that's where I hid it, but the location is vague to me now. Good luck!</text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_15003">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
<!--
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_15002">
		<text>Yes, tell me what you remember about where you hid it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_1502">
		<text>I hid it in the underground. This is one of the many entrances that will lead you into the interconnected basements. I can try explain where I hid it, but you're on your own, the basement network is huge and confusing and full of weird mutants and theres no way I'm going back in there.</text>
	</string>
-->
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_15002">
		<text>Yes, tell me what you remember about where you found it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_1502">
		<text>I saw it in the underground. This is one of the many entrances that will lead you into the interconnected basements. I can try explain where it was, but you're on your own, the basement network is huge and confusing and full of weird mutants and theres no way I'm going back in there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_2">
		<text>Seriy didn't send me here for nothing, and I just saved your ass, so if you know anything else about Strelok, now's the time to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_30001">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_3001">
		<text>Yeah, we looked for it too but couldn't find it. I'll send you some info about it. That's everything we have on the stash.</text>
	</string>
		
<!-- Mole: about toolkits -->
	
    <string id="agro_fixer_krot_dialog_0">
		<text>Hi, I have a few questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_krot_dialog_1">
		<text>Ask away, I'll try to answer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_krot_dialog_2">
		<text>Kulibin asked me to find him some tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_krot_dialog_3">
		<text>Well, there was a factory and RI here. But... any valuable stuff is already out of there, you know.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_krot_dialog_4">
		<text>Ok, thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_krot_dialog_5">
		<text>Actually, there's another thing: except the large Garbage, there is a small one in the Dark Valley - not many stalkers know about it. Look over there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_krot_dialog_6">
		<text>Well, now it's interesting. Thanks a lot!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_krot_dialog_7">
		<text>You're welcome.</text>
    </string>
		
<!-- Mole chitchat -->

	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_20">
		<text>Yeah, there's a Military base. I'm not sure how many of them there are exactly but it's at least a platoon. They're well-armed and you've got no chance of breaking through - they'll take you down before you can say "hello, comrades". The best way of getting in is during the night 'cause the base is well-guarded during the day - they got checkpoints everywhere and anyway, I heard a deserter-soldier from that base is hiding in the marshes. If you can find him I'm sure you can shake some useful info out of him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_0">
		<text>What's going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_100">
		<text>Me and my boys found a nice little area full of artifacts but those Military bastards attacked us for some reason. I don't know what the hell they wanted from us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_200">
		<text>Yeah, I've heard about him. I think he used to "make his living" in this area - it's quite a good place, actually. He left a long time ago; I don't know when it was exactly and I've got no clue where he was headed. That's everything I can tell you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_2000">
		<text>You weren't waiting here for no reason, were you? Otherwise why would the Spetsnaz show up here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_250">
		<text>OK, I know something about Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_2500">
		<text>Yeah? I really need to know that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_3500">
		<text>If you lied to me, I'll find you and finish what the soldiers couldn't!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_400">
		<text>I'm not lying. I know that nobody trusts anyone here so you have little choice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_100">
		<text>OK, listen. I found a book that might lead you to some information which would interested you, and if it gets into the right hands, it just might be very useful. I wanted to sell it to Barkeep, but since you saved my life, I'll let you have it.</text>
	</string>
<!--
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_100">
		<text>OK, listen. I found a flash drive that just might contain info you would be interested in, and if it gets into the right hands, it just might be very useful. I wanted to sell it to Barman, but since you saved my life, I'll let you have it.</text>
	</string>
-->
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_100_old">
		<text>OK, listen. They say Strelok used to sneak around here, and his stash is somewhere around here below ground. Its rumoured that he hid it in a pipe somewhere. We looked for the stash but we found jack shit, maybe you'll be luckier. This is everything I know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_2000">
		<text>What else do you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_250">
		<text>I don't know anything else. I told you everything I knew and now you have to work it out on your own. Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>
		
<!-- Misc -->
	
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_00">
		<text>Hey stalker, good to see you again! What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_0">
		<text>Tell me about this place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_1">
		<text>This is the area around the Agroprom Research Institute. The Institute itself is to the Southwest. The factory, which served as the Institutes technical production facility, is to the North. The buildings have been abandoned for a long time and there's nothing to be found there, but the Army has been searching there very actively recently.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_2">
		<text>Tell me more about the Institute.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_21">
		<text>There are loads of legends about the Institute. Before the accident in 1986 the only thing here was the Institute of Crop Selection and Genetics. The area where the factory is now was used for experimental crop fields. After the accident, they closed the Institute and burned the fields. Then they remembered about it, they whitewashed the building, put up a fence around it and built some barracks. Hell knows what went on there but they sure as hell weren't short of funding.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_3">
		<text>Tell me more about the factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_31">
		<text>The factory was built at the end of the 80s. They said it was going to be used to build and test machines that could treat soil affected by radiation. As far as I know, nobody ever saw a single machine come out of that plant. It's totally empty now, which makes it a favorite spot for stalkers. I hear the place is pretty safe as long as you avoid the dark corners.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_4">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Ratcatcher task -->
	
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_0">
		<text>What are you doing here? I was told to check on you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_10">
		<text>I'm hiding here. I don't want no trouble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_100">
		<text>Who are you hiding from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_50">
		<text>Well, I am a deserter according to the Military code and I have been wrongfully accused of murder. Until I can clear my name, I cannot go near the Military base or I'll be executed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_141">
		<text>What were you accused of?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_20">
		<text>I am from the recon unit. They sent us into the catacombs to see what's going on below the base. It's hell down there, I'm telling you. I was the only one to get out of there... Everyone else is dead and those bastards have accused me of murdering all of my comrades!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_120">
		<text>Catacombs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_30">
		<text>Underground tunnels. They go from the Institute to the area around it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_140">
		<text>Oh, the underground, ok... So what actually happened down there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_3111111111">
		<text>You probably wouldn't believe me, but I'll tell you anyway. The Agroprom Research Institute, before the accident in 1986 was just the so-called "Institute of Crop Selection and Genetics." Apparently used for experimental crop testing. After the accident they fenced it off and built some barracks there. I didn't know what they did at the Institute before, but I know now. They were experimenting with animal genetics. If you saw the beast that I saw down there, you would understand how my group ended up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_31111111111">
		<text>Did this beast have tentacle-like things around its mouth and can turn invisible?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_311111111111">
		<text>Yes! How did you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_3111111111111">
		<text>I have seen one before, very nasty creature, so I believe you for sure. Maybe I can talk to the Military for you and clear your name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_31111111111111">
		<text>No! The Military wouldn't listen to fantasy stories from a stalker. There is another way though. In the institute, they have loads of old documents that tell of all the weird things that took place here. I'm sure it will mention this species in there. If you could, get the documents and take them to Barkeep for me. He has some high-powered connections that will listen to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_311111111111111">
		<text>Do you know where they keep these documents at the Institute?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_3111111111111111">
		<text>At the HQ. It's on the third floor of the Institute. That's where they keep those damn papers. But it's a mission getting there. By day, the area is teaming with patrols but not as much at night. I'll tell you this for free: If you wanna get inside, you'll have to go through the catacombs - you stand no chance at the gate, but its up to you. Oh, one more thing: I have the RI guard chart. Not sure if it's new enough but still, it should help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_31111111111111111">
		<text>Ok, I'll do it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_2">
		<text>Do you have the case yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_21">
		<text>Yes, it was exactly where you said.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_211">
		<text>Great, thanks very much! Please take it to Barkeep so that he can clear my name!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_2111">
		<text>I'm on my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_22">
		<text>No, I'm working on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_221">
		<text>Please hurry, I cant stay in this place forever!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_4">
		<text>Have you taken the documents to Barkeep?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_41">
		<text>Not yet, but I'm on my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_5">
		<text>Barkeep has cleared my name. Thank you stalker, I owe you a world of gratitude.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_51">
		<text>No problem, glad to help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_ratcatcher_start_0">
		<text>Don't shoot, man!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="agr_ratcatcher_start_32">
        <text>Look, is this the case you're looking for?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_ratcatcher_start_33">
        <text>Yes, it is! Have you already been to the institute?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_ratcatcher_start_34">
        <text>Yup... What am I supposed to do with it? If you need it, just take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_ratcatcher_start_35">
        <text>Nah, why would I want it? Take it to Barkeep, he'll use his own channels. Thank you again, stalker!</text>
    </string>
	
<!-- Wounded fixer -->
	
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_0">
		<text>Ahhh, stalker, help me...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_1">
		<text>Here's a first aid kit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_1a">
		<text>I don't have a medkit, really sorry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_2">
		<text>Oh, thanks...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_3">
		<text>Feeling better now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_4">
		<text>Yeah, painkillers do work. Oh, those bastards...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_5">
		<text>What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_6">
		<text>Hmm, not much...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_7">
		<text>Uh-huh. I see. See you later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_8">
		<text>Alright, I'll tell - you saved me, after all. I'm one of the diggers and was trying to loot the underground. So, I found a set of tools - expensive one - and some other stuff. Then the bandits came, took everything and stabbed me. And you've saved me... thanks a lot! If we catch up later, there'll be something for you. And now I'm going to track down those bandits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_sanek_dialog_9">
		<text>Well, good luck finding the morons.</text>
    </string>

<!-- Ratcatcher about -->
	
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_0">
		<text>I've got a couple of questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_10">
		<text>What do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_1000">
		<text>Anything interesting in the area?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_120">
		<text>How much do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_130">
		<text>Here, take the money. Now tell me where it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_131">
		<text>Piss off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_140">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_20">
		<text>Yeah, there are a couple of places but you'll have to share some of your wealth, buddy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_21">
		<text>It used to be pretty quiet but now the Army has got all excited and started wasting everyone. They smoked the bandits out recently and I hear some managed to escape into the catacombs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_30">
		<text>Thirty, deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_40">
		<text>The exit from the railway tunnel is nearby. It's fairly safe in the dead end. At least nobody has been eaten while sleeping... yet.  Also, to the Northwest of the factory you'll find a marsh with a wagon in it.  But be careful, there's a shitload of radiation around it, so it's best to approach it from the western side. Oh, and one more thing: a soldier has been spotted there. He's likely to be from the Military base at the Institute. The poor bastard is probably crazy - he's been there for a couple of days and I doubt he'll survive much longer on his own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_9999">
		<text>Bye!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_0">
		<text>Anything interesting happening here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_1">
		<text>Do you know about Ratcatcher? The info will cost you 30.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_11">
		<text>Deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_111">
		<text>We have a local hero around here called Ratcatcher. He lives in the marshes. The man bred so many rats in the collectors that they'll soon eat those Army bastards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_1111">
		<text>Great. Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_1112">
		<text>Tell me more about the collectors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_11121">
		<text>Collectors are your standard shit-stinking sewers that take waste from the Institute and dumps it in the nearest water reservoir. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_111211">
		<text>Great. See you and take care of yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_12">
		<text>I know that already. Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_121">
		<text>I don't have anything else to tell you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_13">
		<text>I don't have enough cash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_14">
		<text>I'm not interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_3">
		<text>Anything interesting happening here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_31">
		<text>Nothing. Absolutely nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_311">
		<text>I see. Bye!</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Old ratcatcher stuff -->
	
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_01">
		<text>What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_011">
		<text>Tell me about the collector. How do I get inside? Where are the exits and entrances?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0111">
		<text>It's dangerous inside the collector. There are six entrances and two of them are in the area around the Institute where the Military have set up a base. That area is patrolled and the Captain keeps the patrol schedule in his armory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_01111">
		<text>How do you know all that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_011111">
		<text>The rats told me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0111111">
		<text>...I see. Bye! Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_012">
		<text>Nothing. See you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_013">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0134">
		<text>I live here, if you can call this a life. I breed rats in the collector to annoy the Military fucks at the Institute.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0135">
		<text>I am Ratcatcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_01351">
		<text>What are you doing in this marsh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_123">
		<text>Oh... I get it.... well, I'm from another story. Ha-ha-ha...</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Upgrades by the technician -->
	
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_intro_dialog_0">
		<text>So you're the one repairing stuff here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_repair_intro_dialog_1">
		<text>Well, I try. I'm just the handy man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_repair_intro_dialog_2">
		<text>How did you get here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_repair_intro_dialog_3">
		<text>I came here just now, a couple of hours ago. Was going to help Mole, but by the time I got there - they had already fended off the enemy and set up a camp. So I've decided to help, make the repairs around here. If things go well, I'll stay here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_repair_intro_dialog_4">
		<text>And how are things going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_repair_intro_dialog_5">
		<text>Not bad, but I did travel light, didn't take anything with me on the way here. Seems like there was a camp here before, because I found a stash with a lot of materials. It had everything I need except for the tools. And it's not so simple to make the repairs without them. Will you help me? If you find two or more sets of tools, I'll give a nice discount.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_repair_intro_dialog_6">
		<text>Both repairs and upgrades. Surely I can patch up a torn jacket but without tools there is nothing more I can do. Will you help me? If you find two or more sets of tools, I'll give a nice discount.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_repair_intro_dialog_7">
		<text>Alright, I'll help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_repair_intro_dialog_8">
		<text>I've no idea, go ask Mole, he knows the territory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agro_fixer_repair_intro_dialog_9">
		<text>Got it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm here about the tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_1">
		<text>Is there anything new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_2a">
		<text>Yes, brought you tools for rough work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_2b">
		<text>Yes, I've found tools for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_2c">
		<text>Yeah, here they are! A whole set of calibration tools. I hope you haven't found it yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_3a">
		<text>Oh, good. Now I can repair some things for stalkers. It would be just great if I could get some tools for fine work and calibration.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_3ab">
		<text>Oh, good. Now I can finally repair things for stalkers. It would be just great if I could get a calibration toolkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_3ac">
		<text>Oh, good. It was tough without them. Well, It would be just great if I could some tools for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_3abc">
		<text>Finally! A whole set. Now I can repair just anything. I can even make an exoskeleton out of your suit. Well, no. I'm kidding.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_3b">
		<text>That's what I'm talking about! Now I can repair things for stalkers. I just need tools for rough work and calibration for a full set.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_3ba">
		<text>That's what I'm talking about! Now I can make repairs and upgrades. I just need a calibration toolkit for a full set.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_3bc">
		<text>That's what I'm talking about! Now I can make repairs and upgrades. I just need tools for rough work for a full set.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_3c">
		<text>Wow! Where did you get them?! These are great for complex things like upgrades, but aren't suitable for repairs. So it would be great if could you find tools for rough and fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_3ca">
		<text>Wow! Where did you get them?! These are great for complex things like upgrades and now I can repair stuff with tools for rough work. Although it would be great if could you find tools for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_fixer_repair_bring_dialog_3cb">
		<text>Wow! Where did you get them?! These are great for complex things like upgrades. Yeah, we're almost done. I just need tools for rough work.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- freeplay -->
<!-- agroprom task liar side task -->

	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_2">
		<text>Hey man, lend me your ear for a minute will you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_22">
		<text>Not now dude, I have to see a man about a horse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_21">
		<text>Sure man, what's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_211">
		<text>I`m really down and out man finding it hard to even walk these days. I spoke to a medicine man and he said he will whip up something for me but that I need a gravi artefact, you wouldn't be a pal and get one for me would you? I can reward you handsomely!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_2111">
		<text>Yeah sure no problem, I`ll be back with it soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_21111">
		<text>Bless you brother!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_211111">
		<text>Take care now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_3">
		<text>Welcome back brother, did you get the artefact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_32">
		<text>Not yet, I`m still looking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_31">
		<text>Yes, here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_311">
		<text>Hmm, this isn't a stone blood, I really need a stone blood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_3111">
		<text>You specifically asked me to get a gravi, I`ve no doubt about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_31111">
		<text>Really? Sorry, it`s the illness you see, I get forgetful. Please, I really need a stone blood for the medicine man, please my reward will be worth it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_311111">
		<text>Ok, I`ll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_311112">
		<text>Look man, I`ve got better things to do with my time. You asked for a gravi and I gave you one, Goodbye!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_4">
		<text>Hey, you're back. Did you find one?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_42">
		<text>Not yet, I`m still looking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_41">
		<text>Yes, here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_411">
		<text>A stone blood, oh no, don't tell me I told you to get a stone blood? Look, you probably think I`m an idiot, but what I need is a meat chunk artefact, the medicine man requires it to heal me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_412">
		<text>A stone blood, oh no, don't tell me I told you to get a stone blood? Look, you probably think I`m an idiot, but what I need is a gold fish artefact, the medicine man requires it to heal me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_413">
		<text>A stone blood, oh no, don't tell me I told you to get a stone blood? Look, you probably think I`m an idiot, but what I need is a urchin artefact, the medicine man requires it to heal me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_414">
		<text>A stone blood, oh no, don't tell me I told you to get a stone blood? Look, you probably think I`m an idiot, but what I need is a kristall thorn artefact, the medicine man requires it to heal me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_415">
		<text>A stone blood, oh no, don't tell me I told you to get a stone blood? Look, you probably think I`m an idiot, but what I need is a soul artefact, the medicine man requires it to heal me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_416">
		<text>A stone blood, oh no, don't tell me I told you to get a stone blood? Look, you probably think I`m an idiot, but what I need is a slime artefact, the medicine man requires it to heal me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_417">
		<text>Look man, I`ll level with you, I`m not sick. I was just trying to get some artefacts the easy way seeing as my legs have been bad lately...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_4171">
		<text>Ok, well, now you die!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_4172">
		<text>Why the hell didn't you just tell the truth? Well you got two from me, you`re not getting a third, goodbye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_4173">
		<text>Sigh, I should've seen it coming, here, take this, you obviously need it more than I do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_41731">
		<text>Thank you brother, you are a scholar and a gentleman.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_417311">
		<text>Don`t call me brother, you lied to me, I'm leaving now before I get angry, good day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_4111">
		<text>This is starting to tic me off, are you sure this time??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_41111">
		<text>Yes, please, I`m sure of it this time, I`ll really make it worth your while!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_411111">
		<text>Ok, but this is the last time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_411112">
		<text>You wasted enough of my time, Goodbye!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_5">
		<text>Please, I assure you, this is the last time, will you help me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_6">
		<text>Are you sure you cant help an ill man find a stone blood?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_7">
		<text>Do you have the artefact yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_liar_dialog_71">
		<text>Not yet, I`m still looking.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
