<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<!-- Village leader -->
	<!-- Investigate construction site task -->

	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_0">
		<text>Hey stalker, we have many problems here, which did you hear about?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_1">
        <text>Barkeep sent me, said you had some sort of mutant trouble?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_11">
        <text>Indeed we have. We've been under attack from strange mutants and I have lost three of my best fighters! They seem to be coming from the nearby underground lab, so we locked its gates down.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_111">
        <text>How can I help?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_1111">
        <text>Well, we got the Ecologists to mix up a deadly cocktail of poisonous gases to kill the bastards, but it hasn't worked. We can still hear them howling. Someone will have to go in there with a gas mask and assess the situation.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_11111">
        <text>I suppose that's where I come in, right?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_111111">
        <text>Here's the deal: Get a gas mask, go in there, and kill whatever is left of the bastards. About four of them. My men have seen them at the construction site and our headquarters. Retrieve the PDAs off my three fallen fighters and I'm sure I can return the favor, somehow.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_1111111">
        <text>Where can I get a mask from?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_11111111">
        <text>I have one. But if you need one more, then go see the Ecologists in the nearby tunnel, they're sure to have one. I'll give you the coordinates.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_111111111">
        <text>OK, I'll be back with the PDAs!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_2">
        <text>Do you have the PDAs for me and killed all the mutants?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_21">
        <text>No, not yet. I'm working on it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_22">
        <text>The mutants are all dead. Here are your men's PDAs.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_221">
        <text>I thank you, stalker. Now we can go back to our headquarters in peace. We'll filter out the gasses right now. Now, what can we do for you in return?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_2211">
        <text>You mentioned that the gate to the underground is locked.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_3">
		<text>I am here about that problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_4">
        <text>Hey stalker. Thanks again, you are a legend. I was going to help, but last week I took a bullet to the knee!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_41">
        <text>Yeah, yeah, no problem!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_5">
        <text>So, have you managed to kill all of them yet?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_52">
        <text>No, not yet. I'm working on it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_51">
        <text>Yes, they are all dead. It should be real safe here now.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_511">
        <text>Great job! I spoke to Colonel Petrenko while you were down there. He was impressed by your bravado and said he has just the task for a hero like yourself.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_5111">
        <text>OK, I'm listening.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_51111">
        <text>We've had some Stalker boys in the Dark Valley telling us some intriguing things about Monolith activities. Apparently there's a lab named X18 under their base. I'm not sure what exactly is buried under there, but neither do the Monolith. They can't open it yet, or maybe they don't want to. The information is pretty sketchy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_511111">
        <text>And you want in?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_5111111">
        <text>Yep. Whatever is in those labs will attract... the Sins – those damn abhorrations. Go to the old barn, the mates over there have a pretty solid plan. We needed an executioner, and we think we found him. Bring me whatever you can find after your digging, and you will gain great favour with the big-wigs. Any bit of info, however small, can be crucial. When you are done, report to the Colonel in the bar.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_51111111">
        <text>Ok, I'll go see them and report to the Colonel.</text>
    </string>
    
<!-- Get key (not) from Petrenko -->

	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_22111">
        <text>Well, that place is a restricted area, and we think there are or were nests of these mutants down there. But I tell you what, if you go down there and clear the place out, I won't ask any questions and turn a blind eye. Deal?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_221111">
        <text>Sure. So who has the key?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_2211111">
		<text>Usually our leader, Petrenko, has the key. But he gave it to me. It's sad that so many were killed by those damn Bloodsuckers... I've got to warn you before I give you the key to the lab underneath Rostok: there's a sort of "Bloodsucker King" down there. That's why we sealed it off in the first place - it's a damn nest! If you're really going down there, drag that ugly bastard to Hell for me, will you? Here's the key then. They're all yours, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_22111111">
        <text>Thanks, see you.</text>
    </string>
	
<!-- Alternate Duty route -->

	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_23">
        <text>The mutants are all dead. Here are your men's PDAs.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_231">
        <text>Thank you Brother. Now we can go back to our headquarters in peace. We'll filter out the gasses right now. There's just one more thing we need done.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_2311">
        <text>Sure, what is it?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_23111">
        <text>Well, we think there might still be a nest of these mutants down in the lab. Please go down there and clear the place out, you will win favor with Duty's elite for sure!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_231111">
        <text>Sure, no problem. You said it's locked though, so who has the key?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_2311111">
		<text>Here it is, go well brother!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_help_23111111">
        <text>Thanks, I'll be back soon.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!-- If you skip the dialog after returning the PDAs and talk to Dima again, he won't give you the X-14 key; I've created a dialog to get it in case you've skipped that part -->
	
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_key_0">
		<text>We didn't finish talking about something...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_key_1">
		<text>About what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_key_2a">
		<text>About the lab: you said it was locked down, right? I have to get inside, so I need the key. Where can I get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_key_3a">
		<text>Yeah, it was - and there's a reason for that: we think there are or were nests of these mutants down there... but screw the formality. If you go down there and clear the place out, I won't ask any questions and turn a blind eye. Comrade Petrenko used to hold that key, but he granted me it when I'd been headed here. If you're really going down there, drag that ugly bastard to Hell for me, will you? Anyway, here's the key then. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_key_4a">
		<text>Thank you! I can assure you nobody will ever recall the local Bloodsuckers after some time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_key_2b">
		<text>About that "one more thing". What do I have to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_key_3b">
		<text>We think there might still be a nest of these mutants down in the lab. If you go down there and clear the place out, you will win favor with Duty's elite for sure! Here's the key - you can access the lab right away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_key_4b">
		<text>I got you. It will be cleared out as soon as possible!</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- eco tunnel -->
	<!-- get gasmask and clean factory -->
	
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_0">
		<text>Hey stalker, what can I do for you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_1">
		<text>Dima from Duty said you might have a gas mask for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_11">
		<text>Ah, so you are the crazy one who will go in there! Well, here it is. If you'll need gasmask, I'll give you. Just be swift and you'll be fine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_111">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_2">
		<text>Hey stalker, have you cleared out the factory yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_21">
		<text>Not yet, I'm still working on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_211">
		<text>Well, good luck stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_2111">
		<text>Yeah, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_2112">
		<text>Do you have another gas mask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_21121a">
		<text>Yes, but I can't give you any more for free. One usually costs 3500 rubles...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_21121b">
		<text>Not to offend you young man, but... haven't I already stated we struggle to get equipment in these parts? Even if there are some masks left, those can only be used internally but not sold - however regretful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_211211a">
		<text>Here's the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_211211b">
		<text>Well... I'll manage without it then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_211212a">
		<text>And here's your gas mask. Be careful with it: it's almost impossible to get one here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_211212b">
		<text>Sorry but I can't just give such things away for free: I'll have to pay for them in this case.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_211213a">
		<text>I'll try. Well, good luck with the experiments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_211212">
		<text>Yeah, makes sense... Anyway, I won't disturb you then.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- factory cleaned -->

	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_3">
		<text>Hey stalker, thank you for clearing the factory. I will now go and neutralise the gas so we can claim our headquarters back!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_31">
		<text>A pleasure. See you.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- toxic gas area cleaned -->
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_4">
		<text>Hey Stalker, good to see you again. We have cleared out the toxic gases and its business as usual, good job!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_41">
		<text>Hey, yeah no problem, glad i could help, see you.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--meet duty leader first -->
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_6">
		<text>Hey stalker, what can we do for you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_61">
		<text>What are you guys doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_611">
		<text>It's all top secret, but if I were you, I would go and see the Duty leader in the village before roaming around these parts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_tunnel_eco_mask_6111">
		<text>Thanks for the tip I guess.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--Supplies for Duty-->
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_ammo_01">
		<text>I am here about supplies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_ammo_0">
		<text>Yep, Voronin told me he sent some newbie. We are in deep shit there... fleshes, boars, dogs, strange creatures, military, lots of shit we couldn't handle without any reinforcement, at least we receive supplies every week so we can handle the situation properly. Did you bring any ammo and supplies?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_ammo_11">
		<text>Yep, here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_ammo_12">
		<text>Nope, I didn't bring any.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_ammo_31">
		<text>Thank you man, I am not sure how we would've dealt with the problem without this, we have wounded guys here too, so they desperately needed it. I will report to Colonel immediately about your good job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rosf_dolg_leader_ammo_32">
		<text>Well then what are you doing here? Bring us some supplies and then we can talk about your reward.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>