<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- meet ghost at the hotel -->
	
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_1">
		<text>Finally, you made it. Was getting scared there for a second. With the Military and Monolith at fisticuffs with each other, it isn't a walk in the park. Good to see you haven't lost your touch.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_11">
		<text>Does seem like it, fortunately.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_111">
		<text>Well, besides that, we've still got a huge problem. Before we can head to the Generators, we have to find the security override codes for the whole damn complex. To be clear: No override, no shutting down the Generators. And no amount of explosives I can cook up will even dent them with it active. Don't ask why and how it works, but it's so advanced that Fang was marveling at it - that's got to mean something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_1111">
		<text>Then where is the override?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_11111">
		<text>That's the thing... It's in the damn Sarcophagus of the Power Plant. That's what we gathered. They had some experiment within the Sarcophagus - I don't know what and I rather not know. But they had top scientists working there associated with the Generators. For all intents and purposes, the override should be in there. We never managed to get to it before because of... Well, you know what happened back then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_111111">
		<text>And I have to get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_1111111">
		<text>I'm still preparing the explosives, and someone's got to keep this place safe until Fang gets here with the decoder. I wish I could help, but it seems you're on your own. Again. It's going to be hard; the NPP is a war zone right now with you-know-who fighting you-know-what. You think you can pull it off?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_11111111">
		<text>Not like I have a choice, now do I? I'll do it. Just get everything sorted out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_111111111">
		<text>Heh, understandable. Be careful Strelok, this is Monolith territory. The best route is to sneak through the stadium area, there are a few snipers, but not too bad as I remember it. The second way is to take either side road around the stadium but it is full of anomalies and mutants. The choice is yours. I'll get everything ready. You come back in one piece OK? At the end of all this is one damn good drinking game.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_1111111111">
		<text>I'll take you up on that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_3">
		<text>Make haste, we must not waste any time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_31">
		<text>Got it, on my way.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- ghost chitchat -->

	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_4">
		<text>Can I ask you something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_5">
		<text>Sure, ask away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_51">
		<text>Remind me of how we met.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_511">
		<text>You saved me man, big time... Yeah, that happened, and my ego never fully recovered. I got maimed by a Chimera real bad under a full moon one time. I shot the bastard till it stopped moving, but my guts were practically spilling out. I had to settle in an attic and try my best to survive. Guess who I found there? It was you. Even though you were a stranger, you could've killed me right then and there, yet you risked everything by dragging me to Doc's swamp house. If it hadn't been for you, I would've died that night. Been sticking with you ever since. The rest is history.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_5111">
		<text>I see, thanks for the info.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_52">
		<text>What's your story?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_521">
		<text>Lone child with a family decorated with military prestige. Been in about every special ops team on this side of the world, with about thirteen languages under my belt, including Arabic, Mandarin, French, a couple of obscure African languages – even a little bit of Japanese too. I've been around, as you can guess. Then came 2006, and the Zone with it. Back then, there was a branch created by NATO called the Zone Task Force made to investigate the Zone. We were the best of the best. Stayed in that until mid-2009 when my team was left for dead after a mission went awry. Only I survived; as you see, I never gave the bastards that ditched us their money's worth.  That's where my moniker comes from: a bitter, wandering soul pinning for the past.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_5211">
		<text>Thanks for sharing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_53">
		<text>I heard you have a penchant for knives?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_531">
		<text>Kind of a quirk of mine. I preferred silenced handguns in my early days until a mission in Africa. My mates and I had to assassinate these warlords – child trafficking and prostitution, organ trade, blood diamonds, really sick shit. Thing is, we entered the country officially with fake IDs and all, as “humanitarian workers”. Heh heh heh, got that right. With only a couple of nickels and emergency rations to boot, in these sorts of conditions, you... improvise. You go back to the bare basics, like pre-historic hunters before they learned what gunpowder was. Really, all you need is a knife, determination, and a sick bastard to send off to hell when you get down to it. After working my shoulder so that piles of them stacked up like some grotesque Mount Everest, I made it my trademark. My shoulder's getting stiff at my age, so I tend to use it to carve my name on certain deeds. Guns have less glamour to them though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_ghost_talk_5311">
		<text>Interesting story.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- vasilev -->
	
	<string id="pri_vasilev_talk_1">
		<text>Marked One, I thank you sincerely for helping my men. The Ecologists and us have a mutually beneficial relationship. We protect them and they get specific items of interest to us with no questions asked. I'm glad you decided to help us; we can both benefit from the situation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_vasilev_talk_11">
		<text>Glad to help Lieutenant. If you need any more help, please don't hesitate to ask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_vasilev_talk_111">
		<text>Well, actually, there is something you could help with. The scientists need an escort. They want to take some readings and will be in constant danger from Monolith and mutant attacks. I would gladly help, but I cannot spare any men at this time what with the constant Monolith presence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_vasilev_talk_1111">
		<text>Sure Lieutenant, I'll be happy to help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_vasilev_talk_11111">
		<text>Good man. I'll send notice of your acceptance to them. Keep them safe!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_vasilev_talk_111111">
		<text>OK, I'll be along there shortly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_vasilev_talk_3">
		<text>Take care out there. The damn fanatics are crawling all over the place!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_vasilev_talk_31">
		<text>I'll keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- eco contact side task -->
	
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_1">
		<text>Yes stalker, what may we do for you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_11">
		<text>Lieutenant Vasilev sent me to help guard your field crew.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_111">
		<text>Ah yes, he sent news of your arrival. Well, actually there is no crew, just one field agent. Gone are the days when many would volunteer for such jobs, it's just to dangerous these days. Can't say we like buddying up with the Military too much, but they're of great assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_1111">
		<text>I see, well, I'm here to help. When do we leave?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_11111">
		<text>Ah, an eager stalker. Good then, you can go meet my field agent immediately, He is in a building nearby. I'll mark his position on your PDA. Fair warning: there seems to be something causing psi-emissions at the old bus station. We need to know what's with that. Best to take measurements there and kill two birds with one stone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_111111">
		<text>OK, I'll be on my way then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_3">
		<text>So, Marked One, was my field agent successfully guarded?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_31">
		<text>I'm still working on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_311">
		<text>Please hurry back to him. He must be protected!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_3111">
		<text>Right, on my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_32">
		<text>Yes, all went well; your field agent will give you the readings. And by the way, it was a Burer causing the psy-visions, but I sorted it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_321">
		<text>Excellent, that is good news. Professor Sakharov and Deedee will be very pleased. Here, take this Ecologist suit and elite detector as a sign of our appreciation. Remember to drop by to Yantar with your rare artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_3211">
		<text>Thank you, I appreciate it. See you around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_33">
		<text>I have the readings, but I'm afraid your field agent is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_331">
		<text>I don't believe it! I'm bitterly disappointed. At least this brave man didn't die for nothing... He gave us the readings we need. Go on your way stalker, we no longer require your assistance here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_3311">
		<text>A thousand apologies. I couldn't save him. I'll be going now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_34">
		<text>I'm afraid that your field agent is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_341">
		<text>I don't believe it! I'm bitterly disappointed. He died for nothing... Just get lost stalker! You're of no use to us now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_3411">
		<text>A thousand apologies. It went all wrong, I'll be going now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_35">
		<text>No, I'm afraid your field agent is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_351">
		<text>I don't believe it! I'm bitterly disappointed. Did you at least retrieve his detector with whatever readings he gathered so that his death has a semblance of meaning?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_3511">
		<text>Sorry, I came here as soon as I could without thinking about it. I'll retrieve it immediately.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_4">
		<text>Get out of here stalker! You've done enough damage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_41">
		<text>Fair enough, I'm leaving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_5">
		<text>Hey Marked One, good to see you again. Take care out there, it's Monolith territory!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_51">
		<text>Yeah, I will, see you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_6">
		<text>So, did you get the detector yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_61">
		<text>Not yet, I will go get it as soon as I can.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_62">
		<text>Yes, here it is. And again, my apologies for your loss.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_621">
		<text>Get out of here stalker! You've done enough damage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_eco_contact_talk_6211">
		<text>Fair enough, I'm leaving.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- field agent -->

	<string id="pri_field_agent_start_1">
		<text>Well it's about time you got here. I was nearly carried away by the damn rats!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_field_agent_start_11">
		<text>I'm here now, so let's go and get the damn readings.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_field_agent_start_111">
		<text>OK, just keep the mutants off me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_field_agent_start_1111">
		<text>Lead the way, I've got you covered.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- secret trader -->

	<string id="pri_secret_dialog_1">
		<text>Hmm, who do we have here? Ah don't tell me, don't tell me....you're the one they call Marked one right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_secret_dialog_11">
		<text>The one and only.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_secret_dialog_111">
		<text>Damn I'm good! So what can we do for you today?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_secret_dialog_1111">
		<text>I need some supplies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_secret_dialog_11111">
		<text>Sure, sure, if you've got the dough, trade away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_secret_dialog_111111">
		<text>Let's do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_secret_dialog_3">
		<text>Welcome back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_secret_dialog_31">
		<text>Thanks, let's trade.</text>
	</string>
<!-- soc -->

	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_21">
		<text>Let's move up the street. If anything happens, cover me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_211">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_31">
		<text>Thanks for the help, Marked One. That was a hard fight. We can rest here. If you wanna keep going, I'll tell you more about the area. If you go back and turn right you'll reach the bus station. That area is open and not very safe. If you go forward you'll end up in front of the hotel. To the right of it is the Monolith base. Those guys have no limits. Behind the base is the stadium. We were planning to get to the station through it. That's all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_311">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_41">
		<text>Thanks for the help. Good luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_411">
		<text>Bye.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
