<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- meet Dudaev -->
<!-- raid with military btr task -->

	<string id="aes_military_talk_0">
		<text>Hi! You are Strelok right? I am Lieutenant Dudaev, but you can just call me Max. I heard you were around these parts, trying to find something. You want to help us take the high ground? Let's break through and I will present you to our commander. We could be mutually beneficial to each other.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_military_talk_1">
		<text>Ok, sounds good, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_military_refuse_1">
		<text>No, sorry, I must go alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_military_refuse_21">
		<text>That's a pity, we could really use someone like you. Oh well, good luck to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_military_refuse_211">
		<text>And to you too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_ask_player_0">
		<text>Open the gate marked one, we'll cover you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_ask_player_1">
		<text>Ok, I'm on it</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_0">
		<text>These damn BTRs, cant turn a corner without seeing one!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_1">
		<text>What should we do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_2">
		<text>Wait for the helis to do their job, then come and speak to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_21">
		<text>Ok, sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_3">
		<text>The helicopters failed and we have no experienced personnel left; take this RPG and blow that bastard BTR to smithereens, then we can move forward!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_31">
		<text>You can count on me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_6">
		<text>Have you destroyed the BTR yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_61">
		<text>No, I'm working on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_62">
		<text>Yes, its done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_621">
		<text>Good job, let's move forward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_raid_btr_6211">
		<text>Lead the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mutant_wave_dialog_2">
		<text>Damn these mutants, will they ever end?? Keep at it Strelok!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mutant_wave_dialog_21">
		<text>Yes let's get back to it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mutant_wave_dialog_3">
		<text>Strelok, thanks, you have helped us greatly. Now as I promised, I will present you to our leader, he may know more about the whereabouts of the entrance to this place you seek.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mutant_wave_dialog_31">
		<text>Great, lead the way.</text>
	</string>	
	
	<!-- meet Macarov -->
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_talk_0">
		<text>Hi Strelok, I am captain Makarov, finally I can put a face to a name. Dudaev already informed me about the goal of your mission. His friends are my friends too, and after how you have helped us, I guess I can trust you. We are not sure how many monolith troops are nearby and we already lost our snipers. Are you capable of driving this BTR?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_talk_1">
		<text>Of course: cars, bikes, BTRs, all the same right?..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_talk_2">
		<text>Yeah... good, good. At least you've had some driving experience... Lieutenant, you come with us, your guys can stay here and rest a bit. Ok Strelok, we are ready when you are, climb in and we can start this operation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_talk_3">
		<text>Ok, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_talk_1b">
		<text>BTR? Are you kidding me?! I'm experienced enough to do it without BTR.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_talk_2b">
		<text>Yeah... good, good. At least you've had some experience... Lieutenant, you come with us, your guys can stay here and rest a bit. Ok Strelok, are you ready? Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_talk_3b">
		<text>Ok, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_raid_done_0">
		<text>Thank you for helping us, Strelok! I knew you were a trustworthy guy... We will hold this position until the NPP is fully under our control. If you have any problems in future, just find me and I'll help where I can.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_raid_done_1">
		<text>Of course, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_raid_done_2">
		<text>The Sarcophagus is near to your current position, I guess it's the main reason why you are here, the code to the door is 4237. I wish you good luck stalker! You have free pass here. Hope we meet again one day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_mil_recon_raid_done_3">
		<text>Thanks and good luck to you.</text>
	</string>
	

	<!-- duty task -->
	
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Hey, stalker, you're just in time. If you are keen, we are about to assault the mono bastards and could use a good strong lad like yourself. What do you say are you in or out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_start_dialog_22">
		<text>No thanks, I think I'll take my chances on my own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_start_dialog_21">
		<text>Sure, why not, what do you have in mind for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_start_dialog_211">
		<text>I'll admit I recognize your face, Strelok, I know you are an accomplished stalker. I have a special task for you. There is a BTR in our path that needs to be eliminated. I have two choppers waiting for the signal. All you need to do is place this here tranceiver as near to the btr as you can and the choppers will do the rest. Game?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_start_dialog_2112">
		<text>No thanks, too risky, I'll take my chances thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_start_dialog_2111">
		<text>Ok, I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_start_dialog_21111">
		<text>Good. Remember, place it as near as you can and get the hell out of there! We'll fight through the first resistance, then hang back until the choppers have done their thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_start_dialog_211111">
		<text>Ok I'm on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Remember, place the transceiver as close as possible. When it's close enough, it will signal the choppers. We'll rush in after they've done their job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_start_dialog_31">
		<text>Roger that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_raid_dialog_2">
		<text>Good job stalker, I knew I could count on you. I need help with one more thing please. I sent out a recon group to find the entrance to the underground here, but they never returned. Please can you try and find them and see if they were successful?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_raid_dialog_22">
		<text>No thanks, I'm on a mission and have been delayed too long already.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_raid_dialog_21">
		<text>Sure, I'm going that way, I'll keep an eye out for them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_raid_dialog_3">
		<text>Thanks marked one, at least we know they succeeded in their quest and they died heroes!..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_raid_dialog_31">
		<text>Yes, yes they did.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_dolg1_leader_raid_dialog_4">
		<text>Hey man. Wow, crazy battle that was. I saw you in action and i was impressed! I need help with something please. I sent out a recon group to find the entrance to the underground here, but they never returned. Please can you try and find them and see if they were successful?</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
