	<string id="about_enciclopedia">
		<text>About the encyclopedia</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_enciclopedia_text">
		<text>This is the encyclopedia. As you progress in the game, information about the world around you will be added here, sorted by topic.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Memories-->
	
	<string id="memuars">
		<text>Personal notes</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_beginning">
		<text>Who am I?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_beginning_text">
		<text>Damn it, it's all a haze now... I remember a car: they drove me somewhere for a long time, my whole body hurt, and then - darkness... but what was before that? So confused.\n\nI woke up inside of this fat guy's crib: he calls me Marked One - probably because of the strange tattoo on my arm. In my PDA, there only is this weird mission to kill some guy called Strelok... is this device even mine? Looking at Strelok's photo, I'm not even sure if I knew him or not...\n\nDammit! It's all like a bad dream you can't wake up from. What to do? Where to go? And worst of all - who am I? Alright, I need to calm down, control myself. The first thing I'll apparently have to do is work for this Sidorovich: he claims to have saved my life after all... And actually, it shouldn't be too bad. I'll take a walk, calm down myself - and perhaps my head will be clearer.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_first_opinions">
		<text>First impressions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_first_opinions_text">
		<text>Well, well, well... I got some fresh air, saw the local wildlife (interestingly, I seem to remember some of it already, but it's all in a haze), and even had a chance to try the local amusement called "anomalies" (judging by the fact that I survived, I probably came across them before, but my brain stubbornly refuses to remember). Sidorovich is one clever bastard: he knows he can use me almost for free... but maybe he'll help me find this bloody Strelok fellow after all. Nevertheless, it's not like I have a choice: the guy's my only connection with my past.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sl_krot">
		<text>Meeting Mole</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_krot_text">
		<text>Meeting Mole paid off: it seems like the group's stash does exist and it's located in the catacombs below the Institute... I'll have to go there. I don't know what I'll find there... but perhaps this stash will help me solve the mystery.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_strelok_key">
		<text>Strelok's stash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_strelok_key_text">
		<text>Awfully familiar place. I've been here earlier! I clearly remember that the door is locked, and the key is at the very bottom of the underground.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_first_deep_raid">
		<text>First deep raid</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_first_deep_raid_text">
		<text>While looking for Strelok, I went on my first deep raid into the Zone: towards the former Agroprom Research Institute. I'd found the fellow's stash, done some things inside - and all of a sudden, some Barkeep character sent me a message: like, go help my buddy - and I'll help you search for Strelok. Well, it appeared that he meant the local deserter who very much needs some documents located on the RI territory, where the local military guys are situated.\n\nAs far as I know, Barkeep is a trader, just like Sidorovich - which means he should be able to help me... however, no guarantees. Anyway, I need to come up with the plan of passing through the military base - and it'd be good if I managed to do this silently.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_barkeep">
		<text>Meeting Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_barkeep_text">
		<text>Well, I finally met Barkeep - the trader who asked me to assist Ratcatcher at the Agroprom. Though traders make a difference, this one doesn't: he knows he can turn me to his account, should he only promise to find Strelok... but we've been there already. The good thing is, the man looks better than Sidorovich - and that's something.\n\nAnyway, I need to get to the Dark Valley: the rumors claim a lab guarded by another pricks is situated there, which can shed light on the Zone's secrets - or something like that. Well, since I got myself into that deal, I'll have to deal with it for sure...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_mine">
		<text>Action at the mine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_mine_text">
		<text>Here we go again: I was trying to advance into the mine to find another exit when someone'd knocked me out - it appeared tat yet another Sin pricks are encamped here. And of course, their kingpin is not one of the friendly guys: he stole my stuff and got me to do some shit for him - it's about some documents of Borov, the Dark Valley bandits' ringleader. I still need my equipment, so I'll have to do some loud things there, at their base... or perhaps not quite loud?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_doctor">
		<text>Meeting Doctor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_doctor_text">
		<text>I don't know neither what to say nor should I be happy or sad: I found out that I am Strelok. I lost my memory a few months ago, and my friends - Doc, Fang, Ghost and Guide - have been looking for me since that day. Doctor said he was caught by the Mercs, but he decided not to tell more and invited me to his house at the Great Swamps to discuss things instead. All I need to find out is, who I was and where are the other guys.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_pda_fixed">
		<text>The PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_pda_fixed_text">
		<text>Well, the Yantar scientists couldn't fix my PDA, however, Sakharov managed to recover some info regarding our group. Doc and Ghost are alive and doing well - I've recently seen them, - but there's no sign of Fang and Guide, still. Nevertheless, I can't quit the job just yet, and the best thing to do at the moment would be searching for the guys.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_outskirts">
		<text>The Outskirts bar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_outskirts_text">
		<text>When the Great Metal Factory had been attacked, the locals - well, those of them who were managed to survive - decided to move to the Pripyat Outskirts and established a new bar. I have no idea on how the hell the Duty agreed to situate that close to the Freedom, but what I know exactly is, Voronin's men are having some bad time at the moment.\n\nBy the way, some earthquakes happen at these parts several times an hour. What causes these is a mystery... however, there are tons of such mysteries in the Zone, so it's not even like I should be worried about this shit.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sl_dream">
		<text>The Scorcher is done with</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_dream_text">
		<text>I've turned off the Scorcher and for some reason, I lost consciousness just as I did it... and had a dream: some crystal at the Sarcophagus, Proverb who saved me, and a Death Truck. At some moment I'd seen... myself? Yeah, I'm sure it was me, trying to reach that crystal with my hands. Is it the Monolith from those legends?.. Then I'd seen the NPP, a lot of fleeing rats, some man without his face seen... and the Monolith again. I don't even want to think about what does this whole mess mean...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_guide">
		<text>Meeting Guide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_guide_text">
		<text>Guide left me a note and has been waiting for me at the old church of Pripyat Outskirts. We met and had a conversation: he told me why and how had he managed to bring us all to the North, how'd he overcome the Scorcher, and he's also shared some of his Zone thoughts. Unfortunately - or perhaps not? - he has his own business to spend time on, so he won't help us get to ChNPP... therefore, it looks like we'll have to get there ourselves.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_pripyat">
		<text>Way to Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_pripyat_text">
		<text>Did I actually manage to get out of these goddamn labyrinths? When Guide told me about this underground I couldn't have even thought it's such large: all those halls, rooms, passageways - not to mention the terrible mutants and those zombified stalkers... that's some zoo indeed. And I still can't get the poor bastards wearing blue uniform out of my head: I could've sworn I saw them somewhere! But where?.. None of them carried any information, however, every stalker would become envious after seeing how well most of them were equipped; guns like theirs are usually used by the military or Duty... but screw them, I'll ask around about them later.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_ghost">
		<text>Meeting Ghost</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_ghost_text">
		<text>Ghost has been waiting for me at our old Pripyat stash. He told me we have a huge problem: to shut down the Generators we'll have to obtain some security codes. I've been entrusted to start the search in the NPP Sarcophagus; my pal will be preparing the explosives and waiting for Fang to come meanwhile. Well, it pretty much seems like my Zone journey is about to end very soon...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sl_5947">
		<text>I made it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_5947_text">
		<text>I've obtained the code to the stash of legends! Now all that's left is to find it.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Strelok info-->
	
	<string id="Strelok_Info">
		<text>Strelok info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="strelok_book">
		<text>Strelok's book</text>
	</string>
	<string id="strelok_book_text">
		<text>This is written on the cover of Strelok's book: "Hidden in plain sight, but far to reach, an open vent is what you seek".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="strelok_flash">
		<text>Strelok's flash drive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="strelok_flash_text">
		<text>Well, it seems that the stash gave me a new direction to follow. I found a flash drive with what appears to be a diary used by Strelok's group. Despite there just a few entries, I could work out that the group had two other members: Ghost and Fang. The diary also mentioned a "mutual friend" but I don't know if he was part of the group, however, he definitely helped them out.\n\nSo, now I have something solid: the name of someone who definitely knows Strelok - Ghost. As for Strelok himself, he may be somewhere in the North of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ghost_article">
		<text>Ghost profile data</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ghost_article_text">
		<text>Ghost is widely considered to be one of the Zone's best hitman. He can stalk his targets for days on end in severe weather conditions, and always does the deed with a tailored knife left in the poor fool's trachea. People say he was once a merc, but got fed up and became a lone bounty hunter. Once, he was severely injured, but was brought to the Doctor by Strelok himself. Ghost gained an intense loyalty for Strelok afterwards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fang_article">
		<text>Fang profile data</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fang_article_text">
		<text>Fang is an bespectacled brainiac with impressive mechanical skills. He tends to mumble to himself on occasion. However, despite sounding meek at first, he compensates with an exoskeleton he assembled by himself from spare parts. It's said he was seen with with Doctor not so long ago, and it's likely he knows something about Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_article">
		<text>Doc profile data</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_article_text">
		<text>Known simply as the Doctor, he's an old hermit that lives in the Swamps with his tamed pseudodog. It is said that if there is an incurable disease in the world, he knows how to cure it using the unique flora and fauna available in the Zone. There are records among the traders that show that months ago, he was searching among Death Trucks for someone called Strelok. The result of that scavenging is unknown.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="strelok_article">
		<text>Strelok profile data</text>
	</string>
	<string id="strelok_article_text">
		<text>Øèðîêàÿ ýëåêòðèôèêàöèÿ þæíûõ ãóáåðíèé äàñò ìîùíûé òîë÷îê ïîäú¸ìó ñåëüñêîãî õîçÿéñòâà.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Passwords">
		<text>Passwords and access codes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Found_PDA">
		<text>Found PDAs and notes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_001_name">
		<text>Anomalous Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_001_group">
		<text>Dark Valley Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_002_name">
		<text>Military Commander</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_002_group">
		<text>Cordon Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_003_name">
		<text>Bandit Stash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_003_group">
		<text>Dark Valley Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_004_name">
		<text>Zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_004_group">
		<text>Garbage Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_005_name">
		<text>Artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_005_group">
		<text>Agroprom Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_006_name">
		<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_006_group">
		<text>Bar Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_007_name">
		<text>Arena</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_007_group">
		<text>Bar Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_008_name">
		<text>Trader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_008_group">
		<text>Constr. Site Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_009_name">
		<text>Mercs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_009_group">
		<text>Constr. Site Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_010_name">
		<text>Anomaly Formation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_010_group">
		<text>Forest Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_011_name">
		<text>Secret Trader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_011_group">
		<text>Pripyat Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_012_name">
		<text>Weapon Fixer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_012_group">
		<text>Military Warehouses Info</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_013_name">
		<text>The WC</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_info_013_group">
		<text>North Hills Info</text>
	</string>