<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<string_table>
	<!--stalker trader-->	
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_2">
        <text>Hey stalker, is there something you would like to ask?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_21">
        <text>What's going on in these parts?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_211">
        <text>War. At least there used to be. This is where Duty and Freedom used to have most of their skirmishes, with others jumping into the fray for the heck of it. If you're in the least bit faint hearted, just make your way around to better places. This isn't the Cordon.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_2111">
        <text>I think I'll manage, thanks.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_22">
        <text>What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_221">
        <text>Well, where there was war, there were profits to be made and I provided essential services that all sides appreciated. When you needed ammo, medkits or food, I was here. People liked it when they didn't have to go too far for supplies while they were busy slaughtering each other over ideologies and rubels. Of course, all of that has since died down and they've moved further North with their little politics, but I like it here so I decided to stay. Now I also repair and service all makes of vehicles, its a living</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_2211">
        <text>I see. Well, it's good to have a trader in these parts.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_23">
        <text>What is this place?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_231">
        <text>You mean what "was" this place. If I remember right, it was going to be a big factory complex, though I've got no clue what it would've done. Construction was abandoned when, well, you know what happened around here thirty or so years ago...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_2311">
        <text>Right, yeah, thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_ask_25">
		<text>Thanks, see you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_2">
        <text>Hey stalker, haven't seen you around before. What brings you around these parts?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_21">
        <text>Just passing through really. I've got a lot on my mind.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_211">
        <text>Yeah, well, best you steer clear of the merc bar lest your knackers be removed with a switchblade, if you feel me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_2111">
        <text>They're that bad huh? Damn and I could do with a watering hole near by.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_21111">
        <text>Hmm, how badly do you need one?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_211111">
        <text>Always handy to have a thirst quencher close. Why do you ask?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_2111111">
        <text>Wellll, there IS one way to get in there and that's to have their password, which I just happen to know.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_21111111">
        <text>I guess you aren't just going to cough up the password. So what would tickle your tongue?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_211111111">
        <text>There are a few things I need. If you can bring them to me, then I'll give you the password. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_2111111111">
        <text>What sorta things do you need?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_21111111111">
        <text>I need a set of nuts, small and precision stuff, and also a set of transistors. My wireless is broken, see, and I cannot go through the day without music. If I were you I'd look around the old pumphouse for nuts, they were forever fixing stuff there, so I heard. No idea where you will find transistors, maybe check around the bandit camps. They are always fiddling with small things y'know, heh. So, you in?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_211111111111">
        <text>Sure, sounds easy enough. I'll get them for you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_211111111112">
        <text>No thanks pal, just buy a new one. I'm not that thirsty.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_3">
        <text>So, did you get the stuff?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_31">
        <text>Not yet, I'm still working on it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_4">
        <text>So, did you get the stuff?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_41">
        <text>Yep, here they are.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_411">
        <text>Excellent. You know, I had my doubts about you stalker. I really thought I wouldn't see you again.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_4111">
        <text>I am a man of my word. Remember that.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_41112">
        <text>Yes, I see that. And by the look on your face you already found the password. So I tell you what, since I promised to repay you, I will give you this as a token of my appreciation.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_41111">
        <text>Yes, I see that. OK then, so the password is "forgotten". Yeah, it was so easy you would never have thought of it, that's kinda the point. Tell it to the guards and they will let you in without a fuss.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_start_411111">
        <text>Thanks, I appreciate it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_1">
        <text>Do you need anything else done?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_11">
        <text>Actually yes. There's a shipment of fuel that's been stored on a ship on the river in Darkscape. I need it destroyed. Do you know how much damage a shipment like that can create in the wrong hands?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_111">
        <text>I can only imagine.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_1111">
        <text>Exactly. Go to the mercs base there. An agent of mine has left an RPG on the roof. Use it to destroy the shipment and I will give you a very tidy sum.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_11111">
        <text>Ok, I`ll do it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_11112">
        <text>Nah, I don't want to be messing with stuff that doesnt concern me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_2">
        <text>About the fuel task.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_21">
        <text>Yes, I heard you were successful, good job, here is what I promised.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_211">
        <text>Wow, thanks, more than expected.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_22">
        <text>Yes, please hurry before they use it for evil purposes.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_stalker_trader_fuel_task_221">
        <text>Ok, I'm still on it.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--Mercs base-->
	
	<string id="forg_password_dialog_2">
        <text>For your sake, stalker, I hope you know the password!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_password_dialog_21">
        <text>Yes, it's "forgotten".</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_password_dialog_211">
        <text>It's your lucky day. C'mon, in.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_password_dialog_2111">
        <text>See you around.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_password_dialog_22">
        <text>Sure, it's "fluglebinder".</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_password_dialog_221">
        <text>You better get the hell out of here stalker before I put a bullet in your head.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_password_dialog_2211">
        <text>Wow, touchy. See you around I`m sure...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_barman_good_dialog_2">
        <text>Hey stalker, what can I do for you?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_barman_good_dialog_21">
        <text>I`m looking for some supplies.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_barman_good_dialog_211">
        <text>Sure, check out my inventory.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_barman_good_dialog_2111">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_barman_bad_dialog_2">
        <text>You're not welcome here stalker, you best leave!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_barman_bad_dialog_21">
        <text>Sure ok...</text>
    </string>	
	
	<!--Duty-->
	
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_dialog1">
        <text>Uff... Are you... are you the new Lieutenant I heard about? Voronin spoke highly of you. You saw those ugly-ass mutants? They are quite dangerous creatures. Ugh, this Zone never lets up with its surprises... Well, at least we're still alive. Listen, it's not only us that needs help, these beasts cut us off from two of our men. They must be near the pump station by now, trying to patch themselves up. There are even more beasts lurking around there and I fear they'll get to our mates. You better have some medkits on you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_dialog2">
        <text>I will deal with it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_dialog3">
        <text>Thanks man. Sorry that we can't help you this, but I think it's better if you don't drag us along - we're barely alive as it is. We'll stay here and wait for you. I'll give you coordinates.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="forg_dolg_raid_wounded_dialog_0">
        <text>Help! I need a medkit!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_wounded_dialog_1">
        <text>[Give medkit]</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_wounded_dialog_11">
        <text>Thanks mate! These creatures are horrifying!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_wounded_dialog_12">
        <text>Thank you Lieutenant! We didn't think we'd make it out of this alive. The damn Burers almost got the best of us! We should return to our group as soon as possible and report back to base.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_wounded_dialog_3">
        <text>I don't have a medkit. Hang tight I will get one.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_dialog_end0">
		<text>How did you go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_dialog_end1">
        <text>All done.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_dialog_end2">
        <text>Thank you mate! Thank you! It was close! We were near death here, you did the impossible for us, we will never forget this. I will report to Vernonin that we are alive as soon as possible.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_dialog_end_fail1">
        <text>They died.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_dolg_raid_dialog_end_fail2">
        <text>Damn it, Lieutenant, that's quite bad news. These guys were the experts here, sent to research the new mutant type we've seen around here. We've only got some of their notes; the rest, they kept in their heads to transcribe later. Lots of important information was lost because of that... Well, at least we're still alive, right? Thanks for saving us from these freaks.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!-- informer -->

	<string id="forg_informer_0">
        <text>Hey man, I'm the local library around these parts, if you want some info about this place, I've got it, for a price of course.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_1">
        <text>500 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_11">
        <text>Rumour has it that the bandits are making rudimentary radios for communication using transistors and whatnot. Someone I know, who will remain un-named, went down into a bunker at their camp and saw some there.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_2">
        <text>1000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_21">
        <text>There is a pumphouse not far from here. The damn pumps were always breaking down and in need of constant fixing. Lots of tools were left there so I hear.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_3">
        <text>1500 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_31">
        <text>The merc barman has a key which he seems to be in love with. He always carries on about the key and how it will one day bring him power. No one knows what it is for and thinks he is mad. He just leaves it on the counter, almost taunting people with its presence like he doesn't care about it, but I'll tell you one thing, he doesnt sleep far from it!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_4">
        <text>2000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_41">
        <text>The mercs at the bar are a sticky bunch and don't like strangers, but if you know their password then they let you in, no questions asked. The password is "forgotten", yeah I know, original...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_5">
        <text>Do you have enough money?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_51">
        <text>Yes.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_52">
        <text>No, sorry.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="forg_informer_53">
        <text>Return when you have some cash.</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="forg_informer_6">
        <text>Do you have anything else?</text>
    </string>
 	<string id="forg_informer_7">
        <text>I'm sorry, Marked One, but I don't have any more info for your right now.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_16">
        <text>1000 rubles.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="forg_informer_18">
        <text>According to the old stories, there is a stash somewhere. The code to the door is lost, written down on paper, torn up and thrown away. No one knows what is in the room, but apparently the only person who may know anything about it ran away to North Hills.</text>
    </string>

<!-- Mill aka Milo -->

	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_quest_0"> 
		<text>Is there any job for me?</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_quest_1"> 
		<text>Yeah, there is. I have unconfirmed data that there's a rare weapon on an old barge in the Darkscape - called Gauss rifle, if I'm not mistaken. I've seen such guns before, but that's a modification of it with far better specifications or so they say. The barge is guarded by mercenaries, but they're from the opposed faction, so I won't mind if you kill 'em. Get the gun and bring it to me, but don't expect those guys to let it go easily! So, will you do the job for me? I'll give you the best price in the Zone!</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_quest_2"> 
		<text>Yeah, I was going there anyway.</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_quest_3"> 
		<text>Nah, I don't think I'll be there any time soon.</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_quest_completed_0"> 
		<text>The Gauss rifle...</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_quest_completed_1"> 
		<text>Quiet, you moron: too much people around! Give it here, slowly.</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_quest_completed_2"> 
		<text>Here, take it. Where's my pay?</text> 
	</string>
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_quest_completed_3"> 
		<text>Yeah, stalker, here's your pay. You've done a great job!</text> 
	</string>
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_box_quest_0"> 
		<text>Is there another job for me?</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_box_quest_1"> 
		<text>Actually, there is. The Gauss rifle you brought can't be tested without ammunition. I know for sure that the Monolithians from the Radar have a lot of it - pay them a visit! They won't give it to you without a good fight so keep it quiet... or however you want - just bring the box to me. And don't tell anyone else - let it be our little secret! So what, will you do me another favor?</text>
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_box_quest_2"> 
		<text>Radar, you say? Alright, give me the coordinates.</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_box_quest_3"> 
		<text>Radar, Monolithians... Mill, are you nuts? You'd better make the local drunkards fetch it themselves.</text>
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_box_quest_completed_0"> 
		<text>Hey Mill. Here's your box.</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_box_quest_completed_1"> 
		<text>Why are you always like that? Hollering around about things, like we're on some farmers' market! Give it here - again, slowly.</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_box_quest_completed_2"> 
		<text>You better stop shouting yourself. Anyway, here's your box.</text> 
	</string> 
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_box_quest_completed_3"> 
		<text>And here's your pay! You didn't let me down - I appreciate that.</text> 
	</string>
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_third_quest_0"> 
		<text>Is there something else of a job?</text> 
	</string>
	<string id="forg_mill_gauss_third_quest_1"> 
		<text>No, that's all for now.</text> 
	</string>
</string_table>