<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- Talk with Ghost -->
<!-- reach warlab task -->

	<string id="gen_ghost_breakthrough_0">
		<text>Here we are. You see those generators in the distance? They are the origin of everything, Strelok. All those labs, every little experiment, were meant to lead to this. Humans always think they can control nature, but never once consider how horribly wrong they can be...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_breakthrough_1">
		<text>I see. It's as chilling as I imagined. We've got to stop it before another blowout strikes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_breakthrough_2">
		<text>Won't be easy. There might be stalker detachments here fighting it out - maybe even the Military too, who knows. The entry to the X2 bunker is up ahead. Once we get there, Fang's decoder can let us in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_breakthrough_3">
		<text>And you'll set up the explosives as we planned?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_breakthrough_4">
		<text>Only after you deactivate this thing. To make sure governments don't get their hands on this. Follow me closely, and tread lightly - last time the three of us almost got turned into a mangled ball of flesh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_breakthrough_5">
		<text>I'll be right behind you.</text>
	</string>

<!-- get through the tunnel to warlab -->
	
	<string id="gen_ghost_distraction_0">
		<text>What do we do with these guys around?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_distraction_1">
		<text>We still stick to the plan: We blow this thing to kingdom come. These guys are from Monolith, and I doubt they're here to destroy this place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_distraction_2">
		<text>So they're here to keep control of it? Damn! But we can't charge head-on, they've got the advantage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_distraction_3">
		<text>They aren't a problem for a former ZTF like myself. Not far from here you'll find an old evacuation tunnel. I will distract them and you attack them from behind when they least expect it. Or we can straight up shoot our way there. I suggest the former.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_distraction_4">
		<text>Right, let's do this.</text>
	</string>

<!-- reach warlab task done -->

	<string id="gen_ghost_final_0">
		<text>So we made it. What will you do now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_final_1">
		<text>You will need to go down to the lab and input the override, this will disable the built-in defence mechanism. I'll set up the explosives and wait for your signal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_final_2">
		<text>Are you sure you won't need any help with all that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_final_3">
		<text>Of course not, I'm a trained professional! I've done demolition work many times before, so don't sweat it. When you give me the signal, I'll finish up and go to the nearby cemetery. Let's meet up there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_ghost_final_4">
		<text>Good luck then... old friend.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Talk to ghost at the cemetery -->
	
	<string id="gen_la_game_0">
		<text>Strelok... it was a long road to get to this point... you see all the changes around you? When the generators were disabled, all the harmful emissions disappeared. It caused the plants in this area to regenerate and become healthy again, actually I think nature will heal itself now... Even all the mutants have moved away from this place, they will all probably die without that energy feeding them, but who knows. I can't describe what all this means to me... we did it... we really did it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_la_game_1">
		<text>Indeed, it was teamwork that got us here.. Doc, Fang, Guide... without them I am not sure we would've been able to finish what we started. Still hard to believe, but I still have strange feelings about all of this. What if this is just another facade by the Noosphere? How can we be sure it won't happen again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_la_game_11">
		<text>Time will tell... we can't worry about that now.  We blew the generators up, the Zone is gone. Things should get better from here on out, you can already see the changes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_la_game_12">
		<text>Yes, we did it, now I have other important matters to attend to, can we meet later in the bar with all our friends?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_la_game_2">
		<text>You are probably right... It's just... ah forget it. Anyway there is still a lot to do here, there will be a lot to clean up and repair now that the Zone is gone. What are your plans now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_la_game_21">
		<text>I have some business in the outside world, but I will come back soon to help. Be careful and take care of yourself!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_la_game_22">
		<text>No, I need to be here now, still have a lot to do. Be careful and take care of yourself!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_la_game_3">
		<text>Of course I will, and never forget, if you need help, I will be here. Now I will go and meet with Doc. He has good connections and maybe we will start plans for our next journey!</text>
	</string>
</string_table>