	<string id="eliminate_gunslinger_text">
		<text>Woke up in some dude's den, can't remember anything... I only have a PDA with a picture of some other guy, and just one message: "Kill Strelok".</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="meet_sid_text">
		<text>I woke up inside of some kind of basement. Don't remember a thing... need to find out who and where I am.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_get_equipment_text">
		<text>The local trader by the name of Sidorovich advised me to get my equipment from some dresser downstairs. Something's telling me part of it won't be there...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="tutorial_artefact_text">
		<text>This trader, I woke up inside the basement of which, asked me to work for him in favor of my redemption... right, "asked". He said there is some "Whirligig" anomaly field" close by containing an "artifact" in its center, and I have to find and bring that thing in. Like I have a choice...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="rescue_novice_from_heli_text">
		<text>Apparently there's a rookie who has some info valuable for Sid, and he's in trouble. Somehow, I feel like a babysitter. Am I that old or what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_1_text">
		<text>The guy who, according to Sidorovich, saved me decided to use my help cleaning the place from local animals. Well, let's see if I still know how to use the shooter!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="assault_bandit_factory_text">
		<text>There was another contact of Sid's that didn't make it. Sid told me his body is at the bandit camp in the factory. The rookie village's leader, Wolf, should help me in clearing out the thugs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wagon_key_task_text">
		<text>Wolf's lost a key at the local underground and said that if I find it, as a reward I'll be able to visit his stash and grab everything from there, or I can just return it to him for a small reward.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="rescue_fox_text">
		<text>These strange Sin fellows seem to have a bone to pick with Sid. One of Sid's contacts, Fox, is being held hostage. Guess who has to play the diplomat? Another babysitting job... Great. Or maybe I should just kill them...? I feel like the way I approach this task might have future consequences...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="personal_sid_task_text">
		<text>The trader said he'll help me find Strelok, so I should work for him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shustriy_task_text">
        <text>Sidorovich asked me to find another of his contacts - Nimble. Last time they got in touch on Cordon after the guy had crossed the railroad.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="blokpost_case_text">
		<text>I've signed to steal some important case from the local outpost for Sidorovich. I'll be doing this at night, so it's a good idea to get an NVD - at least a little bit working.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="nimble_work_task_groza_text">
		<text>I need to find a rare instance of equipment, and bring it to Nimble. The first real mission is to bring him the OTs-14 Groza assault rifle, being able to use 5.45 and with an extended mag: it belongs to either some captain or a major based at the Agroprom RI.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task_magnum_text">
		<text>I need to find a rare instance of equipment, and bring it to Nimble. The next task is to bring him a revolver belonging to Borov - bandits leader controlling their Dark Valley base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task_ecolog_text">
		<text>I need to find a rare instance of equipment, and bring it to Nimble. The new task is to find an experimental scientific suit. Perhaps, Professor Sakharov from Yantar could help me.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sid_task_arty_text">
		<text>I promised Sidorovich to find these three rare artifacts: "Battery", "Spring", and "Shell". Well, I always have to keep my word...</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Freeplay-->
	
	<string id="esc_bs_task_text">
		<text>Found a dead guy's PDA who apparently liked riddles. I should follow them and see where they lead me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="safe_task_text">
		<text>So the riddles led me to a safe located at the local outpost. Let's see what's waiting inside...</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Found PDAs-->
	
	<string id="esc_messanger_pda">
		<text>Messenger's notes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="messanger_pda_text">
		<text>If somebody's reading this, it means I am dead. It was a bad idea to try and get something from these scumbags directly... but Sid knows how to persuade people, and probably their information is very important for his trade network. From what I heard, bandits are expecting some big guests, one known as Plague-Eye from Sin and the other - a mercenary which they call MadDog. They are planning to make an important bargain by transferring some rare item to the mercenary base. I am not sure what it is and why they need it, but this is about some big money. They arrive in a minute; I'll try to hide as close to them as I can to try and hear their plan. God help me, I just hope it's worth it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_bandit_flash">
		<text>Bandit's flash drive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_flash_text">
		<text>What the hel mate? We had arangements didn't we? You got the bians right? Wheres my new thools den? Boys are pissed of, 'cause all of shootas are fucked up allready. Even if sum friggin' noobs come our way we wont fucking stand a chanse! You sad you sent man trough Garbage two days ago, yeah?! Or you desided back out, huh? Thats some shady bisness u got there...</text>
	</string>