	<string id="find_computer_text">
		<text>To get shut down the Generators we need to find the security override codes. It's worth trying to search for them on old PCs - though I might will have to power them somehow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="restore_powerline_text">
		<text>Well, I was right: I must power the found PC somehow. There's a powerline in this room, so the only thing left is finding an energy source.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="follow_monolith_text">
		<text>I heard the call of the Monolith. He called me to him. Now I ought to go to him and get the answers to all my questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="get_gen_codes_text">
		<text>Alright, the PC seems to work; now I need to search for the file containing the codes, then download it to my PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="reach_generators_text">
		<text>The codes are obtained! Now it's time to get the hell out of here and head towards the Generators: Ghost should already be waiting for me at those parts. So is the Zone about to evaporate?..</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sar_dead_reseacher_pda">
		<text>Explorer's journal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_dead_reseacher_pda_text">
		<text>It's probably my last note. Not sure how many days I spent in this cage, but my supplies are running low. I noticed when I woke up there were these yellow eyes staring at me and I heard deep breathing. The breathing happened about every hour near the cell and then I heard some scary scratching noise... I fear to even be released, if I do, the Zone would surely take me... But I need to try because staying here forever is worse. Brother, forgive me, I knew it was a bad idea to take part in this expedition to the center of the Zone. All our military escorts are dead, it was bad luck that I managed to find this place. The things I saw there, their nature, I can't explain it. These genetic mutations are impossible! The artifacts and anomalies simply don't compare with Einstein's gravitational field interactions and any of our current photon theories. I could write much more, but I need to try to leave this place. If I can't get out of this alive, take care of our mother please, I love you both.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="sar_generator_doc">
		<text>Generators notes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_generator_doc_text">
		<text>Do you think "Generators" were created just to power supply for human minds control mechanism? It's much bigger: they wanted to play God and succeeded in it. I'm not sure who is running all this we've been told very clearly: we should finish the job quickly or there will be consequences. I constantly see some strange people near my home, near my family... I need to focus on the work because if something happens to them - I won't be able to live with it!\n\nHere's everything I could find on them: faces, names, witnesses... but it's not enough. They are using secret headquarters to perform their operations here, in Chernobyl, - but the KGB is ordered to keep away from them. I just hope this won't last long and it's possible to get away eventually...</text>
	</string>