<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- Sin leader meet dialog -->
<!-- Darkvalley docs task -->

	<string id="ds_boss_talk_11">
		<text>Stalker, I will only give you so much time to explain yourself, so do not try my patience.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_111">
		<text>Wh-What happened? Who are you? Why did you hit me over the head?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1111">
		<text>I am Veles, leader of Sin. You cannot simply WALK in to MY mines like that, stalker. Now, tell us your story - dare lie and we will simply use your body as a benchmark for the human body's pliability.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_11111">
		<text>Alright, I'll talk! I... I was trying to go down to X18 lab to uncover some documents, and the Military ambushed the Monolith base, but I managed to escape and found these tunnels to take cover. It's a safer route than walking outside. And that's why I'm here - I'm not from Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_111111">
		<text>Hmm... I'm not sure whether to trust you or not, but tell you what: Do a little job for us and I will look upon you more favorably.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1111111">
		<text>What's the job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_11111111">
		<text>Before that, I should explain what "we" are. Most of us don't care to use common languages anymore amongst each other. We developed our own method of speaking when we were being held captive all that time. We needed a way to talk freely about ways to try to escape and kill our captors without them knowing what we were planning. These mines lead to an old lab where human experiments were carried out - established with the other labs in the late 1980s after the NPP incident. We were political prisoners, mostly, who were the test subjects of these experiments; killing two birds with one stone. Even after the USSR collapse and Ukraine's independence, old Eastern Bloc countries handed over their troublesome cases to a joint Russian-Ukrainian research team. About two years before the Zone's emergence, after an accident, the lab below these mines collapsed, and some of us managed to escape and bring out some lab equipment to try to revert our mutations. Our only reason to live such a pitiable existence is the yearning we feel for our old humanity. To achieve that, we need any information or devices from the network of old labs in the Zone, which we can use and reverse engineer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_111111111">
		<text>That's pretty bad to say the least...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1111111111">
		<text>Yeah, well, sometimes life's a bitch. Don't worry, we lost our sense of pain long ago, so it doesn't hurt... much. Anyways... If you want the Sin to trust you, go to the bandit base in Dark Valley. There are important documents there that we need. Oh, and we took the liberty of removing some of your equipment. The bandits are on high alert and are wary, so having all that gear on you will rouse suspicions. I will give you some bandit gear for you to blend in and some standard shooters. Think of it as a test of virtue if you will. You'll get it all back when you're done. I will also give you this PDA module which allows you to download information wirelessly from any computer that has anything useful on it. So be sure to use it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_11111111111">
		<text>...It sounds like you don't want me to get out of this alive. I guess I have to prove you wrong.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1111111112">
		<text>Yeah, well, sometimes life's a bitch. Don't worry, we lost our sense of pain long ago, so it doesn't hurt... much. Anyways... If you want the Sin to trust you, go to the bandit base in Dark Valley. There are important documents there that we need. Oh, and we took the liberty of removing some of your equipment. The bandits are on high alert and are wary, so having all that gear on you will rouse suspicions. I will give you some bandit gear for you to blend in and some standard shooters. Think of it as a test of virtue if you will. You'll get it all back when you're done. I will also give you this PDA module which allows you to download information wirelessly from any computer that has anything useful on it. So be sure to use it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_12">
		<text>Did you find the bandit documents?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_112">
		<text>No, not yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1121">
		<text>I am losing my patience with you, stalker. Best you find them quick!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_11211">
		<text>Alright, alright, I'm going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_113">
		<text>Yes, here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1131">
		<text>Ah, excellent! Oh, and did you manage to get the info from the PC in the lab?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_11311">
		<text>No, I haven't found it yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_11313">
		<text>No, no-one told me to get any!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_113111">
		<text>Please, go and get it! It could be the breakthrough for us! If you do, I just might give you a task that you would be very interested in. Though i won't be your reminder by the way, you already have the code to this lab, so common... move.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1131111">
		<text>Right, I'm on my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_11312">
		<text>Yes, I have all the info you wanted right here</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_22">
		<text>Did you manage to get the info from the PC in the lab?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_221">
		<text>No, I haven't found it yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_222">
		<text>Yes, I have all the info you wanted right here.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Secret lab docs task -->
<!-- after task finished we get message to meet sakharov at yantar -->
	
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_113121">
		<text>Good job, stalker. I'm beginning to trust you, so be glad. I have another job for you if you want. We have heard news of a secret lab under the Rostok Factory, and this lab contains documents that pertains to our problem. Find them for us and we will be indebted to you. Oh and grab your stuff in that box on the shelf.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1131211">
		<text>OK, don't worry, I'm on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_113122">
		<text>Good job, stalker. I'm beginning to trust you, so be glad. Be on your way</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1131221">
		<text>OK, thanks, I'm leaving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1131222">
		<text>OK, thanks. By the way, I found these documents down in a lab in Rostok factory, are they any use to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_13">
		<text>So, have you found the secret documents yet, stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_131">
		<text>No, not yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1311">
		<text>Please, find them quick. This could be the big breakthrough for us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_13111">
		<text>Alright, I'll get them soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_132">
		<text>Yes, it was quite a journey, but here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1321">
		<text>Stalker, you have no idea what this means to us. All we have left is hope, and this gives us more that we could ever pray for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_13211">
		<text>I hope it will help you in some way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_132111">
		<text>Well, we will know more now about the experiments done on us than we did before. In return for your help, I will give you some information only known by few: There are secret traders in Deadcity and Pripyat. They have some equipment that most stalkers dream about. I will tell them about you - and if they are in those areas, you will get a PDA message of their coordinates where you can find them for a limited amount of time. These traders are gifted with strange abilities similar to the legendary man-of-myths. I can't say why they are like that - this requires further investigation on our part.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1321111">
		<text>Thank you, I really appreciate it.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Sin leader chitchat -->
	
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_14">
		<text>I'm honored to greet the Sin friend! How can I help you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_15">
		<text>Can I ask you a few questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_153">
		<text>I guess it can't hurt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_151">
		<text>Anything worth knowing about you on the personal level?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1511">
		<text>No. None of us are worth knowing. We are but people that are missing the most essential composite of humans: life. Remember that when you speak to us, but do not pity us - we find such an emotion revolting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_15111">
		<text>Sure OK. I won't.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_152">
		<text>Do you go outside much? You know, with Duty and all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1521">
		<text>Hah! That's a good one. Look, Duty can pretend they're hunting us down and jerk off over the thought of our complete eradication, but it's a load of crap. Wanna know how many of our guys actually got killed by Duty? Five. We killed way over that number just out of self-defense. When we go outside, it's mostly at night when they're busy dreaming about their dear grandma's. Besides, anytime they actual come up with decent plans, our complicity with those Freedom anarchists comes in. They tip us off when they get hold of anything regarding us, not even expecting anything in return. I haven't even met their leader for that matter. Good mates these guys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_15211">
		<text>Very good indeed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_17">
		<text>What do you know about those spherical devices outside?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_171">
		<text>Nothing, absolutely nothing - a real mystery. None of the documents we got from the X5 lab or anything we overheard from the scientists ever mentioned these things. What's strange is that similar devices were spotted around the Pripyat Outskirts. Peculiar indeed. This would require further investigation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_1711">
		<text>Hmm, strange indeed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_18">
		<text>So, did you get the PC info yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_19">
		<text>Thanks again stalker, you've been a great help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_191">
		<text>Sure, no problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_20">
		<text>So have you managed to get the info yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_talk_21">
		<text>Not yet man, I'm working on it.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- dolg side task -->
	
	<string id="ds_blockpost_attack_group_0">
		<text>Hi Major, nice to meet you again. Are you ready to show these bastards what we are made of?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_blockpost_attack_group_1">
		<text>Yeah, let's move.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_blockpost_attack_group_2">
		<text>Nope, give me a second.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_blockpost_attack_group_21">
		<text>Be quick my friend, we don't have much time until they spot us from their position.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_blockpost_attack_group_211">
		<text>Approaching the enemy base!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_blockpost_attack_group_final_0">
		<text>Thank you for helping us. We searched around and found lots of interesting information about their experiments which might be useful for Voronin.  Thanks again, Sergeant. If you will have any problems, I'm sure that can help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_blockpost_attack_group_final_1">
		<text>No problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_prisoner_0">
		<text>Where is the last data disc you stole?</text>
	</string>
<!-- dont shoot. don't shoot i surrender -->
	<string id="ds_boss_prisoner_1">
		<text>Why are you bothering with pointing a gun at me, Marked One? You murdered us and you're expecting that I spit it out? Please, don't insult me. I won't even budge under the worst tortures you can conjure up from your bag of tricks. However, if you want to know where I hid that precious disk of yours, you're going to have to obtain a rare artifact for me, and then let me go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_prisoner_11">
		<text>Tch, I don't need to cater to you. Just die.</text> 
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_prisoner_12">
		<text>Alright. Tell me what you're after and I'll get it. Anything more and I'm wasting you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_prisoner_112">
		<text>I need a rare artifact called Moonlight. According to the informations I obtained from X18, it should help us understand the experiments that was done on us. Act fast stalker, my legs already hurts sitting here in such a pose..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_prisoner_1121">
		<text>You can wait.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_prisoner_done_0">
		<text>Here it is. Where is the damn disc?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_prisoner_done_1">
		<text>Alright, you made your point. I hid not far from here; I'll send the location to your PDA. Hopefully a scavenger hasn't looted it already. That'd be such a shame.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_boss_prisoner_done_2">
		<text>And it'd be a shame if I just shot you in the face. Scram before I change my mind.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>