<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<string_table>

<!--meet countryside hermit and get good hemlet-->
<!-- let's move to brainlab after -->

	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Never thought I'd see a fresh face today. It's pretty lonely around here, like... all the time. What brings you around these parts mate?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_21">
        <text>Well, it's a long story. Short version is that I need to find an unblocked passage to the abandoned underground. Deedee from the bunker not far from here said you might be able to help.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_22">
        <text>Well, it's a long story. Short version is that I needed to find an unblocked passage to the abandoned underground, but I found it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_211">
        <text>Ah, Deedee, I haven't seen him for a long time. Not a very hands-on type, but a very good scientist nonetheless. I know where you can find a proper entrance. Should I take you there?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_2111">
        <text>No need to come with me; just mark it on the map for me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_21111">
        <text>Done. Good luck down there, stalker. Come by sometime, we can share some tales of adventure with a vodka or two.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_211111">
        <text>Thanks, I really appreciate the help.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_2112">
        <text>I'll take you up on that. This place is pretty intimidating.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_21121">
        <text>Sure thing, let us leave this instant. Stay close, there are a lot of vermin around here - we'll cover each others back.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_211211">
        <text>Thanks, I'll stick close.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Good luck out there, stalker.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_start_dialog_31">
        <text>Thanks, see you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_path_end_2">
        <text>Well, that's as far as I go. What lies beneath us gives me nightmares. Have at it if you dare.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_path_end_21">
        <text>Thanks, I really appreciate the help. I'll see you around.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_path_end_4">
        <text>Stay close stalker, we'll be there soon.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_path_end_41">
        <text>OK.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!-- Griboyedov 1st meet -->	
	
	<string id="country_major_begin_0">
		<text>I can't believe it: a stalker! It's not common for guys like you to be here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_begin_1">
		<text>Well, it was necessary to pass through these wastelands in search of the, so to speak, truth. It's strange to see the military here though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_begin_2">
		<text>We're here because of these scientists and that underground lab. We tried to take control over the Radar, but this wasn't possible... so we are here: in case the Monolithians try and get to the scientists - which, of course, is out of the question as they never come here. Actually, there is no one here at all, but us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_begin_3">
		<text>Don't you starve here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_begin_4">
		<text>No, we receive a large parcel dropped by helicopter once a month - thus, we don't complain. And you know what, stalkers aren't usually tolerated here... but I have my own opinion on this matter: we need to consider each person separately, and I can tell a good person from a bad one. You, for example, are a good person - that's why I'll let you walk here. You can even have a rest here if you need to.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_begin_5">
		<text>Well, thanks. It's kind of useful to communicate with people in such a hollow sometimes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_begin_6">
		<text>True that. By the way, if you need some work - just tell me: I could really use some help on a couple of things.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_begin_7">
		<text>Okay, I'll let you know.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Griboyedov's tasks -->		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin0">
		<text>Well then, Stalker, interested in some work? Not everyday you find someone here, so the reward will be appropriate.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin1a">
		<text>No, I'm not interested.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin1aa">
		<text>Yeah, I am. But I'll do it later.</text>
	</string>			
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin2aa">
		<text>Oh well, I'll try to sort it out myself.</text>
	</string>			
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin1b1">
		<text>No, I will not do it.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin1a1">
		<text>Well... sorry. Be careful when you come by here the next time. Anything can happen, you know.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin1a2">
		<text>Yeah, bye.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin1">
		<text>Yes, let's say I'm interested, what kind of work do you have in mind?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin2">
		<text>Well, here's the thing... In these places there are lots of mutants, and they are becoming more and more aggressive. A Dwarf got a habit of stealing stuff from our blockpost, and every single time he manages to get away. That bastard stole all the vodka we had stored! We can't afford sending our men to hunt down the thief, so, in short, you need to kill the bastard! Are you taking the job?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin3">
		<text>I'm in, why not. So much damage from this asshole. Any clues where I could find him?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin4">
		<text>My guys saw the dwarf each time when he was running towards the village. That's where you could look for him. They usually hide in the abandoned houses.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin5">
		<text>Well, I'll visit him. And what about the reward?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin6">
		<text>Don't worry about the pay, it will suit you. I'll give you money, plus you will be in good standing. And... One more request. I recently got a registered gun, and got distracted somehow and left it on a nightstand. So that bastard stole it. Such an unfortunate turn of events could undermine my authority. Will you look for the gun? Only quiet, ok? And in return, you'll get something extra.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_begin7">
		<text>So be it, I'll search for the gun.</text>
	</string>				
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish0">
		<text>Hey, commander!</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish095">
		<text>Well, what about the job, Stalker?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish00">
		<text>It's done. Your Dwarf is dead.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish00a">
		<text>I haven't dealt with the Dwarf yet. He's still alive and hanging around here somewhere.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish1a">
		<text>Ah, Stalker, stop dawdling. Please!</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish1aa">
		<text>I'll deal with it soon.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish1">
		<text>Oh, finally. What about the special request?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish2a">
		<text>No luck, commander. I only managed to find the Dwarf. But I couldn't find the stuff...</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish2a1">
		<text>Hmmm... You know, I can feel a lie from a mile away. Thought you'd keep the pistol? I would have paid for it. Now get out of here and pray that we let you pass the next time!</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish2a2">
		<text>Bye.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish2b1">
		<text>I see... That's a shame, Stalker. Yeah, it was a mistake to give such a task to a stalker. Well, nothing I can do. As I promised, here's your reward. Thanks.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish2">
		<text>Here's what I found - the Fort. I think that's what you're looking for.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish3">
		<text>Phew, you got me covered. Personal thanks from me, and here's a reward of course. And what else did you find from the other stolen stuff?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish40">
		<text>No, I couldn't find anything. Just some trash, really.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish50">
		<text>I see. Well, thank you, Stalker. Take the payment for the job.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish60">
		<text>Take care. See you next time.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish4a">
		<text>Look, I found this PDA. It works, but the data is encrypted.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish5a">
		<text>Hmm, a familiar PDA. But it is not so important. Generally speaking, there's nothing worth of interest on it. Here's a reward for the task.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish4b">
		<text>Look, here's an artifact I found. It looks kind of familiar, but still, I have never met such before.</text> 
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish4">
		<text>Yes. A lot of vodka, some food, this rare artifact and a PDA of an unknown Stalker. </text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish5">
		<text>You even managed to find the artifact? So that's how it disappeared! I thought one of our men stole it. Look, believe it or not, this artifact is mine. I'm quite surprised you let me know about the artifact, it's great to do business with you! May I have the artifact? I'll pay a good price.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish6">
		<text>OK, take it. I don't need it. Let's settle for 15000, no less. Plus rewards for the Dwarf and the gun? Agreed?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish7">
		<text>Yes, it's a deal. Here's your reward, and now I know that you are someone I can rely on when there's a harder task.</text>
	</string>		
 	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda0">
		<text>What about the PDA?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda00">
		<text>Yeah, what is it?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda0a">
		<text>What about the PDA?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda1">
		<text>Let me see. A familiar PDA. Owned by an experienced Stalker, he worked for us for sometime. He hunted rare artifacts, sometimes he found such things you couldn't believe to see with your own eyes...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda1z">
		<text>Take it, I don't need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda1zz">
		<text>The PDA probably has plenty of useful info. It may be useful for you. Go to the scientists here at the factory, they can definitely retrieve the data.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda2">
		<text>If it's not a secret, can you tell me what kind of jobs he was doing for you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda3">
		<text>Well, I will tell only you. I wanted to tell you anyway. That stalker supplied us with artifacts. He was capable of finding most rare types and worked with specific contracts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda3z">
		<text>Seems like you got your business rolling, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda3zz">
		<text>No one is free of sins. Here, in the center of the Zone, are very "juicy" places, so you can make good money on them. But the salary of military, you know... So we organized this business. Stalkers bring artifacts, I pay them well, we smuggle artifacts at the checkpoint at the Cordon and get our profit. \n And I wanted to ask you if you could supply us with artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda4">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda5">
		<text>We have not seen this guy for a while, he disappeared about a month ago. Now we know his fate when you found his PDA, but we need to move on. We need someone to deliver a package full of artifacts, will you take this job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pdada">
		<text>If you have serious business, I can participate. I'm in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pdada2">
		<text>Well, that's great. Come by when you decide to deliver the artifacts and we will discuss the details. And one more thing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pdanet">
		<text>No, that's too risky. Bandits will be happy to meet such a "courier" on a deserted trail. This sort of job is not for me .</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pdanet1">
		<text>I see. The choice is yours. But then one more request of you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda6">
		<text>What's that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda7">
		<text>Try to find any information about the owner of the PDA. It's still not clear whether he's dead or the Dwarf simply stole his PDA. His name is Garik. Find any information you can.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda8">
		<text>Ok, I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda88">
		<text>Sorry, I have enough problems besides this.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda0b">
		<text>You said that there is another job.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda9">
		<text>Oh, by the way, I almost forgot. I could offer you another job. Come, when you want to do a couple of tasks for a good payment.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pda3a">
		<text>But this is not your business, okay? Wait, I have another question for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_first_quest_finish_pdak0">
		<text>What question?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job0">
		<text>Is there a job for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job00">
		<text>No, there's nothing for you now.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="country_major_joba">
		<text>Yes, there are a couple of problems with mutants. Can you take care of them?</text>
	</string>				
	<string id="country_major_jobb">
		<text>I always have some job for you: I want you to deal with mutants, and there's a task regarding artifacts.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_jobc">
		<text>I always have some job for you: I want you to deal with mutants, and there's also a personal request.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_jobfa">
		<text>I always have some job for you: there's a task regarding artifacts, and I also have a personal request.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_jobf">
		<text>I always have some job for you: I want you to deal with mutants, bring me some artifacts, and there's also a personal request.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_jobba">
		<text>I always have some job for you: currently, I want you to bring me some artifacts.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_jobbb">
		<text>I always have some job for you: currently, I want you to deal with mutants.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_jobca">
		<text>Yes, I have a personal request. Will you take it?</text>
	</string> 
	<string id="country_major_jobmut">
		<text>I can help you with mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobmut2">
		<text>So listen. There are so many mutants in the area getting on our nerves, that I can't take it anymore. I just can't stand them, okay. The authorities aren't willing to organize a sweeping operation, I can't send out my boys, so my hands are tied. And I've decided to take the initiative. Can you do this job for me? I will supply you with ammunition and equipment we have in the warehouse, and of course you will be paid well!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobmut2z">
		<text>I'll take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobmut2a">
		<text>Excellent. There's a lot to do. First you need to kill a herd of flesh, not far from our checkpoint. This herd is unusually large, about 7-10 of them. These mutants don't usually gather in groups so large, that it is better to sweep them now, until others will join them. I marked the approximate location on your map. Here's some equipment. Get started.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobmut3">
		<text>Although the fleshes are a source of annoyance, they don't pose a big threat, unlike a pack of psy dogs... One psy-dog has found its place near a large anomaly, don't know how you stalkers call it. It's a huge pit with lots of fire. You'll find the target around that area. Here, take some more ammo for the "Vepr".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobmut4">
		<text>Next target on the list is a Chimera. Made itself a lair in the tunnel, the only way to travel by car. Fearsome beasts they are, these chimeras. During daytime it's probably sleeping somewhere else, so you can't find it, but it spends nights in the tunnel, so you know where and when you can find it. Here, take some extra equipment, this won't be an easy hunt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobmut6">
		<text>There's an extremely powerful controller who made its home near the road. He takes control over all mutants who happen to pass by, as well as stalkers. That's why it's important to eliminate him. With it gone, we will have less problems. Let me mark in your PDA where to find him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobmutt">
		<text>Alright, I'm on my way..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobpers">
		<text>Got any special tasks for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart">
		<text>What about the artifacts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart1">
		<text>We've got a contract for a specific artifact. Stalkers call it "Snowflake". To be honest, I have no idea where that thing can be found, be we really need one. The pay is 15 thousands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart2">
		<text>The next artifact you need to find is called "Bubble". As far as I know, they're formed in acid anomalies. As usually, I pay well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart3">
		<text>Need to find an artifact - "Liver". You'll do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart4">
		<text>Need to find an artifact for me, "Fungus". Rare one, they say, so the search will be hard, but the pay will be good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart5">
		<text>Need to find an artifact, called "Jewel".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart6">
		<text>The situation is complicated: it's not so easy to assemble the whole lot - unlike going shopping to the deli. Let's start with something simple: three artifacts from the "Burning Fuzz" anomaly. The names they have are quite gastronomic: "Bagel", "Cupcake", and "Doughboy".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart7">
		<text>The next order is not quite standard: stalkers usually pass by these and but I, in spite of their uselessness, need them - five green and blue "Parasites". I think you won't struggle finding this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8">
		<text>For the following order you don't have to run far: a very bright glow is seen from the side of the local cemetery at night - and when it's cloudy, it is visible even in the afternoon. It's strange that so far no one has taken this artifact... though there are no people to.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart9">
		<text>There is something unusual for you: the artifact seems to be simple but, perhaps, it has transformed into something more interesting. The scientists told me that psi waves change the structure of artifacts from the "Funnel", and, according to my information, there's one "Goldfish" at the concrete factory territory. Will you manage it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart10">
		<text>What's next on the list... yeah. Half the work is already done: a loner found what was needed, and I have an agreement with him - you just have to go and pick up the order... but it's not very close - you'll have to get to the Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart11">
		<text>The last and most important artifact: it's is not on the list, but I would like to get it to compensate such a delay with the order - the "Compass". Nobody knows where these come from for sure, although there is some information on this matter: some say such artifacts are born in the "Spatial Bubble" - which would be strange because it protects from those "bubbles". Anyway, you better look for it in powerful clusters of anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job11">
		<text>Okay. Got to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish0">
		<text>I did it.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="country_major_job_finish1">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_job_finishmut2">
		<text>Killed all the fleshes, there were a lot.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_job_finishmut3">
		<text>Killed the dogs, they almost got me, barely managed.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_job_finishmut4">
		<text>The chimera is ready for a funeral. Fearsome beast. When I killed it, another chimera appeared and started to chase me. Seems like they were mates. The second chimera wasn't going to forgive me for killing the other. So, now both are lying dead.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="country_major_job_finishmut6">
		<text>That's it, I killed the controller. As I engaged him, I was attacked by other monsters. Seems like the controller had really good skills, tried to get me by a surprise, bastard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish11">
		<text>Nothing yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish111">
		<text>See you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish1111">
		<text>Wait, I wanted to ask you something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finishmuttt2">
		<text>Nicely done, Stalker! I think it wasn't too difficult? Anyway here is your reward, and come back for more jobs! You may keep the "Vepr".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finishmuttt3">
		<text>Those dogs were driving me crazy. Thanks a lot for dealing with them. Come see me for more jobs!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finishmuttt4">
		<text>Well, I've heard something about chimeras dating, so to say. It's great news that you managed to get away alive, because I have more jobs for you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finishmuttt6">
		<text>Yep, I told you that he's a powerful one. It's good that youýìó got rid of a big problem. Here's your reward, well earned... /n What's that noise? Let's go take a look...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finishwow">
		<text>What the...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finishartt1">
		<text>Oh, finally! Great job, Stalker. There will be more orders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finishartt2">
		<text>Here we have it! A rare trinket. And a useful one. I don't want to know how you found it though. Here's your money, and come back again!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finishartt5">
		<text>Perfect, you managed to find it! Here's your "salary". That's the last contract for now.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Griboyedov's courier service-->
	
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_0">
        <text>I'm ready to start my job. What are the current contract?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_0_0">
        <text>We do have a contract but none of the artifacts! The order isn't complete yet, there's no sense in delivering it now. Get the artifacts, and then you'll go to the Cordon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_0_1">
        <text>Îkay, I'll get you the artifacts, don't worry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_1_0">
        <text>I've just got all the artifacts and packed 'em for delivery.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_1_1">
        <text>So, what's still to be done?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_1">
        <text>Firstly, don't tell anyone: all of this is kinda secret - the local traders don't know a thing!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_2">
		<text>Well, that's clear. But don't even try to intimidate me - that's useless. Now let's get to work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_3">
		<text>And secondly, there's an old UAZ near the road as you exit the checkpoint. You can take it, I don't mind. So, the task isn't hard: you only have to get this case to the Cordon - to the head of the checkpoint. Though you work for us, the rules haven't changed: you can't snoop around the checkpoint here, and on the Cordon too. Try to dawdle around - and you'll be killed. So, back to the business: go there, come up to the head, and give him the case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_4">
		<text>I see. But does he know that I'll come?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_5">
		<text>Yeah, but stalkers look the same to him. So you'll have say the code phrase: "The hogs are flying low today, aren't they?"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_6">
		<text>Are you kidding me? Alright, let it be. I don't even care.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_7">
		<text>That's all, go now - and be fast! I'm waiting for the results.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done_0">
		<text>The hogs are flying low today, aren't they?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done_1">
		<text>Stalker, are you crazy or something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done_2">
		<text>Um, what? I'm from...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done_3">
		<text>Relax, I'm just kidding! I'm a joker, got it? Ha-ha! It was me who came up with that phrase. Have you brought it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done_4">
		<text>Sure - why would I even come here if I haven't?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done_5">
		<text>True that. Now give it to me. There are no peepers here at my place, so don't you worry. Ha-ha!..</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done_6">
		<text>I'm not at all: I'm already a criminal. You are the ones who could have problems, aren't I right? Anyway, take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done_7">
		<text>What are you talking about? What problems? Nobody cares, and those who do are getting their money. He-he-he! And yours waits for you at major Griboedov's place: he hired you, he pays.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done_8">
		<text>Yeah, you've definitely found yourself a young one to do all the legwork...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done2_0">
		<text>I've delivered it. All's safe and sound.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done2_1">
		<text>Safe and sound? That's good. What will you take besides money: SVD, Vintorez or some armor? I can even give an RPG!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done2_2a">
		<text>Well, give me a Vintorez. Good thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done2_2b">
		<text>Armor is always useful, give me that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done2_2c">
		<text>I could make some use of an SVD.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done2_2d">
		<text>I'd better have some more money - I don't need a weapon right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done2_2f">
		<text>Well, why not. I'll take the RPG.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done2_3">
		<text>Here you go:</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done2_4">
		<text>Will there be more jobs?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case1_done2_5">
		<text>Yeah, visit me when you have time: we've got something serious to discuss.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_start_0">
		<text>What's up with the next order?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_start_1">
		<text>It'll be a bit easier this time. Before I hired you, another stalker had taken a job. And... the package never made it to the destination, damn it! However, the asshole's PDA signal is strong so I can send you his location.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_start_2">
		<text>He could just have thrown away the PDA and got off with the artifacts, couldn't he?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_start_3">
		<text>Yes... but it's not that easy to open the container, so he would be seen with it anyway: I'm sure he'd ask the local technicians. So, either something happened to him... or he won't just get away with it!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_start_4">
		<text>Understood. Well, send me his coordinates - I'll search for him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_start_5">
		<text>And by the way, there's a new UAZ around the corner. You can take it - it's a present.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_0">
		<text>I've checked the signal - what a mess that was!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_1">
		<text>What happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_2">
		<text>The stalker's PDA was just lying on the ground and I was ambushed by either military or even military stalkers! I don't know what's the deal, maybe they've waited long for me, but I was better and had killed them off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_3">
		<text>Did you get the PDA?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_4a">
		<text>No, I left it in a hurry...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_4b">
		<text>Yes, I took it, but the squad leader has gotten off, so I've got no info from the bodies - they've only had weapons.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_4c">
		<text>Yes, I took the stalker's PDA and the one the squad leader had.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_5a">
		<text>Really?! Go get it - I need this device!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_5b">
		<text>What a mess... Well, I need your help now more than ever. Firstly, we've got to get the artifacts again: I have some but it's not enough. The order is on fire, I can even lose the client! I'm doubling the pay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_6b">
		<text>And secondly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_7b">
		<text>Secondly, we have to find the one who set it up. There are many options, ranging from Sid and Barman to my colleagues... I have no idea who could do that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_8b">
		<text>Well, I'll start looking.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_5c">
		<text>Now that's interesting! Let me take a look... of course: all the data is encrypted, and the stalker's PDA is completely empty - we need a good hacker. What a mess... Well, I need your help now more than ever. First of all, we've got to get the artifacts again: I have some but it's not enough. The order is on fire, I can even lose the client! I'm doubling the pay. As for the PDA - I'll try and decrypt it meanwhile.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_case2_done_6c">
		<text>Well, good luck with the decryption.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_finish_art1">
		<text>Phew, I've found it, at last. Here's your "Snowflake".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_finish_art2">
		<text>Got the "Bubble".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_finish_art3">
		<text>I've found the "Liver".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_finish_art4">
		<text>Here's what you were looking for - "Fungus".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="country_major_job_finish_art5">
		<text>Found it. Here's your "Jewel".</text>
    </string>	
	<string id="country_major_job_finish_art6">
		<text>I found your "edible" artifacts. Here you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish_art7">
		<text>Got all "Parasites". It was easy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish_art8">
		<text>And here is the source of the glow: "Supernova" - they say it's very rare. I had to sweat hard to find it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish_art9">
		<text>Psi "fish" - as you ordered.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish_art10">
		<text>Here is the package. It was not without difficulties, but I've still brought it. And by the way: I was given three artifacts at once, instead of one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish_art11">
		<text>The "Compass" - do not ask where I got it, but I'm waiting for a huge reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobpers1">
		<text>Well, there is something, quite simple. I'm interested in ecolog suits and the good ones that stalker have. I'm not allowed to have them, naturally... but I've always wanted to break 'em down. Maybe I'd be even able to upgrade the military SKAT after that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobpers1z">
		<text>Understandable. So what do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobpers1zz">
		<text>I need the ecolog suits and the Seva. Get them for me and I'll pay you good for delivery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobpers2">
		<text>Have you seen those guys in the exosuits? I want one! I could get such suit, but I haven't gotten to it yet. Get one for me, and I'll pay for exo and its delivery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish_pers1">
		<text>I've got your suits, here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish_perss1">
		<text>Oh, great, come to daddy! I've got another job, come to me when you've got a moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish_pers2">
		<text>I've got your exo. Heavy stuff!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_job_finish_perss2">
		<text>Great work! Here's your reward. That's all for now, I've got no more jobs for you.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--Controller attack-->

	<string id="country_major_kontr_atack_0">
		<text>And what on Earth was that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_kontr_atack_1">
		<text>How the hell should I know... did you see how many of them were there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_kontr_atack_2">
		<text>I've never seen so many mutants in one place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_kontr_atack_3">
		<text>It was a controller who did that. Came up with an attack, and there were so many of them that he couldn't handle it: did you see the mutants attacking each other sometimes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_kontr_atack_4">
		<text>And how often do things like that happen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_kontr_atack_5">
		<text>Not often at all. He had a certain target - it was a revenge... for all the mutants we killed before, probably.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_kontr_atack_6">
		<text>Yeah, stuff like that happens here. I think we should stop wiping out the mutants, otherwise we'll be drowning in mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_kontr_atack_7">
		<text>How did you survive the mental attack?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_kontr_atack_8">
		<text>I'm immune to that, that's not the first time I face 'em.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_kontr_atack_9">
		<text>You've helped us plenty. Here, take some ammunition and supplies. And we'll stop clearing out the mutants: no way we can handle another wave like that.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- 5947 adventure task -->
	
	<string id="country_hermit_5947_0">
        <text>I wanted to ask you something.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_5947_1">
        <text>Yes what is it stalker?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_5947_11">
        <text>There's a legend of a stash in a code locked place. The code was lost and the only person who could possibly know anything about it ran away to these hills. You wouldn't happen to be that person would you?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_5947_111">
        <text>Hmm, well I guess I can trust you. Yes, I do know about the stash. Actually better than that, I have half the code. I found the code on a dead body, and ever since I took it, I've had bad things happen to me and bad people looking for it and arguments with good friends. I say the stash is cursed, because anyone who tries to find it or the other half of the code has some nasty things happen to them.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_5947_1111">
        <text>Well, I'm not superstitious, why don't you just give me the half of the code and I will search for the other half. Any idea who may have it?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_5947_11111">
        <text>You know what, you can have it, I'm done with all the bad luck its brought me, I might even be able to return to society at some stage, here it is. As to who might have the other half, it was a good friend of mine. We each kept half the code so all would be fair, but we had an argument and that's when all the bad stuff starting happening regarding this damned stash. Last I heard he ran off and joined the military and actually stationed not too far from here, but I'm done with him..</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_hermit_5947_111111">
        <text>Nice, thanks, and so my quest begins.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_0">
        <text>Something you need stalker?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_1">
        <text>I'm not going to beat around the bush here sir, so I will just come out and ask it. Do you have half of a code to a mystery stash only legend speaks of?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_11">
        <text>Do you know Hermit or have been speaking to him?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_111">
        <text>Hermit? No never heard of him.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_1111">
        <text>Hmm, but how can I trust you?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_11111">
        <text>You can ask Sidorovich or Barkeep for a reference, ask about "Marked One."</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_111111">
        <text>Marked One hey, I've heard of you, quite the stalker, let me see the mark. Hmm ok so it's true. well to be honest , yes I have half of the code. A friend of mine "Nomad" has the other half, we split the code to keep things fair, but we since had a huge argument and went separate ways. To tell you the truth, I haven't been happy since then. I don't even know where this damn legendary stash is or have the other half of the code and it feels all pointless these days, sometimes I just want to burn it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_111112">
        <text>"Marked One?" You are wanted by the military in more than one area, get him boys!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_1111121">
        <text>But... wait... I...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_1111111">
        <text>I have a crazy idea. Why not just give it to me. That way it is off your hands. Out of sight out of mind so they say. And who knows, maybe one day I will find the other half of the code and stumble on the stash and unlock the mystery?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_11111111">
        <text>Hmmm... screw it, here, take the blasted thing I don't want to lay eyes on it again. Take it far far away from here and don't ever bring it back!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_111111111">
        <text>Your wish is my command, and thanks.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_112">
        <text>Hermit? Sure I've met him, but what does that have to do with the question?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_1121">
        <text>Everything!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_11211">
        <text>Well he never mentioned anything about a code.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_112111">
        <text>I'm not sure if I can trust you...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_11212">
        <text>He might have said something about a code but not that he had it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_112121">
        <text>I don't believe you, get him boys!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="country_military_leader_5947_1121211">
        <text>But... wait... I...</text>
    </string>
</string_table>