<!-- string_table -->
	<!-- Dialogs 'what you gona do'? -->
	<string id="dm_action_info_0">
		<text>Leave me alone. Just trying to stay alive, that's all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_1">
		<text>Eh.. still waiting for breakout for this idiots in shoulder straps.. Staying here is nothing,  we need to go to big land, and this bitchy don't wana walk us thourgh! Not only me wana to exit, but still we can't get from them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_2">
		<text>I want to rest. Let's go to the camp, you will find out rumors there. Everybody first time, - newbiews like you - walk to us: to take experience or to rest little. Under sideways there are militaries, don't affraid them too much, but don't be on their sight too long, - they kick you, this is for them as two fingers... There is a trader nearby - to hell this reseller, - there is a place also where you can halt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_3">
		<text>We have a business here again. There is one factory nearby, so we will get rid of bandits from it, but they return again every time! Even one month didnt last, and they are already here. Be carefull there...</text>
	</string>

	<!-- Dialogs-anecdotes -->
<string id="dm_jokes_info_0">
	<text>To bar enters ostrich and  stalker and wet cat. All surprised, but silenced. Whom ordered a bottle of vodka, drink it and walked to dark coner of bar; sit there and cry. So barmen walked to there and asking, how its all going.\n- You understand, i was on NPP, in sarcofag, found wish giver.\nBut i guess was totaly gone mad without women society and ordered to be always with my baby chicken with long legs and wet cutty.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_jokes_info_1">
	<text>Two loosers bandits sitting near fireplace and dreaming:\n
-Eh, shit, if we could only reach Monolith. That i will rise! Eh, shit, i could wish.. five thousand rubles!\n
Pause. His company asking with misunderstanding:\n
- Hey, bro, maybe better... six thousand, eh?\n
Again pause. Then answer:\n
- No, but you kidding! Six thoursands?! It's UNREAL!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_jokes_info_2">
	<text>Agroprom. Some bandits goes to stalker base.\n
- I am here walked away, saw stalker grave. You know, guys, what's ritted on cross?\n- "Died, protecting back anus".</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_jokes_info_3">
	<text>Stalker veteran learning newbies:\n
- So here it is! Stick together, one for another, don't betray mates, don't take shit to month... I had one "partner" here, silly. We were caught by bandits one day, put us to wall, choose: make us pleasures or shoot us down.\n
- And what y answered? - asking newbies.\n
- What, what! This bastard agreed, and i... i was shot down.</text>
</string>
	
	<!-- amk stories -->
	<string id="dm_story_info_0_1">
		<text>It's boring here in Cordon.. tell me another story maybe...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_story_info_0_2">
		<text>I remembered one anomaly.. walked to Sidor once and he tells that some foreigner arriving here.. we need to meet him.. show places, anomalies, and etc. And i am almost naked - no ammo in ak, sawn-off gun broken long time ago, only pistol, and it has blank cartridge.. stupid, but still i want to eat. So i agreed to take this foreigner around in zone. around village of course.. He came. In dark glasses, with camera. Talking smth on his american language, and smiling, bastard. Like he came on safari. So we went... not far - our guys already cleaned this territory to mill not long time ago before, to the village. So we walking, foreign is smiling, fixing his hat, and making photos.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_story_info_0_3">
		<text>Eheh. Aha, tourist...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_story_info_0_4">
		<text>So we went to hangar not big, you remember, where Fedor Constructor died. Keep silence i told to this foreign, or we will go to zombies. He felt it, eyes like glasses and taking, tourist, from backpack magnum. Shit, i think! Whom i took on my head.. Told him to hide his gun. Showed him by gestures and told to walk after me. And dark... nothing seen good. So we walking, water dropping, glass trembling(wind going). Tourist shaking... And suddenly from the dark in camouflage goes zombieeee. I wanted to shout to foreigner to get rid away, but he already wasnt there. So we with zombie can't take it long and start laughing, uff laughing! Petrovich really frightened client.. to much even. I wanted for view to shoot with blank ammos... was not fast enough! tourist, i guess heard about zombied, and as hear scream and saw this guy going on us with straight hands.. We worked well and got enough profit.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- /string_table -->
