	<string id="find_hermit_text">
		<text>Doc contacted me and sent to Radar - I'll need to meet some Nomad who will help me disable the Scorcher. But how exactly? Well, there's only one way to find out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hermit_belonings_job_text">
		<text>Nomad asked to get his belongings which were stolen by a creepy monster. They are hidden in a small village near the Monolith base which was sometimes used to hide from the Monolithians before they took over. According to my new mate, there's a safe containing the passkey which opens the bunker under the Brain Scorcher; his supplies will help me get into the epicenter of the anomaly, the safe is located inside of which.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith_task_text">
		<text>It seems like the local Monolith base leader wants to see me... I think it'd be better to follow this guide guy while he's adequate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_heli_text">
		<text>One of the fanatics' outpost is under attack by the military, however, I don't think the "enemy of my enemy" thing will work here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_mutants_text">
		<text>Another Monolith outpost is in danger: some mutants are heading there - and I don't think they just want to give the soldiers a hug. Since I've come this far, I must play it till the end; let's help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hermit_x10_lab_task_text">
		<text>Yeah... despite that Nomad character clearly doesn't look like a human, he still has the human trickery: it appeared that there was no anomaly blocking the way and he just used me like some bellboy. Well thank you, Doc... but screw it. Now I need to find the safe (the combination is 2-1-8), get the passkey and return to the exploiter so he'd activate it by using some magnet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hermit_x10_bunker_text">
		<text>Alright, now it's finally the time to get to Lab X-10 and disable the Brain Scorcher. As always, I'm strongly risking my life... however, this time I might be able to help all stalkers in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="rad_safe_combination">
		<text>Nomad's safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_safe_combination_text">
		<text>The combination opening Nomad's safe is 2-1-8.</text>
	</string>