	<string id="find_waterdam_text">
        <text>Deedee sent some field workers to the North Hills not so long ago - and the fully functional psi-helmet I'm looking for is held by these guys. I'll have to find them, and should start searching from the underground tunnels next to the old dam: that's where the last communication session took place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_entrance_text">
        <text>That entrance the Professor told me about has turned out to be collapsed. There's a stalker by the nickname of Hermit in these parts, and he should know other ways of getting into the underground tunnels - therefore, I need to find him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_dead_scientist_text">
		<text>Alright, here's the entrance to the local underground. I need to find the field workers - and something's telling me I don't have to hurry; the only essential thing now is finding the psi-helmet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_emitters_text">
		<text>I feel sorry for the Professor's guys... but this is the Zone after all. Anyway, I have the helmet and now should head to Lab X-16 under the Concrete Factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_karlik_text">
        <text>There's a new petty thief in the North Hills region: a local Dwarf got used to stealing things from soldiers at the military checkpoint. Major Griboyedov asked me to eliminate the thief and bring some of his personal stuff back. According to the approximate data, that annoying Dwarf lives in the village located near the church.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_personal_text">
        <text>Major Griboyedov from the North Hills asked me to find any information possible regarding a great stalker named - or nicknamed - Garik. I have no idea on where to start from, so I'll have to improvise.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_mutant2_text">
        <text>Comrade Major is seriously concerned about the beasts nearby - thus, the decision of hiring stalkers to do the dirty job was made. The first task is destroying a large pack of fleshes located near to the checkpoint.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_mutant3_text">
        <text>Comrade Major is seriously concerned about the beasts nearby - thus, the decision of hiring stalkers to do the dirty job was made. The next task - is to get rid of a pseudodog flock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_mutant4_text">
        <text>This time Comrade Major has entrusted me to kill the Chimera settled in the tunnel, blocking the communication by the main road. To successfully kill the beast, I need to arrange my raid at night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_mutant6_text">
        <text>Comrade Major is seriously concerned about the Controller occasionally hanging out near the checkpoint. The mutant enslaves the local fauna and rarely bypassing stalkers, therefore it needs to be done with as soon as possible.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="major_wave_atack_text">
        <text>A mutant attack is incoming on the checkpoint, so it's necessary to protect the military positions and deflect all the waves of mutants.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="major_wave_kontr_text">
        <text>Goddamn it! The Controller's taken out all the soldiers. I must eliminate it until all the boys' brains are cooked! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_job_case1_text">
        <text>Griboyedov got me to deliver a package of artifacts to Cordon. I have to remember the code phrase so the checkpoint leader - who I need to bring the case to - wouldn't think I'm a stranger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pers1_text">
		<text>Comrade Major has a personal request: he wants me to bring him a green Ecolog suit and a "SEVA". I have no idea on where to get these but I'll work it out, I guess.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pers2_text">
		<text>Comrade Major has a personal request: he wants me to bring him an Exosuit. Griboyedov promised to pay sell, thus it's worth a shot.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="major_art1_text">
        <text>Taking advantage of his high rank, the Major sells artifacts on the black market without any remorse... at least he pays well. I need to find the "Snowflake" artifact and bring it to him.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="major_art2_text">
        <text>Taking advantage of his high rank, the Major sells artifacts on the black market without any remorse... at least he pays well. I need to find the "Bubble" artifact and bring it to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_art3_text">
        <text>Taking advantage of his high rank, the Major sells artifacts on the black market without any remorse... at least he pays well. I need to find the "Flesh Chunk" artifact and bring it to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_art4_text">
        <text>Taking advantage of his high rank, the Major sells artifacts on the black market without any remorse... at least he pays well. I need to find the "Fungus" artifact and bring it to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_art5_text">
        <text>Taking advantage of his high rank, the Major sells artifacts on the black market without any remorse... at least he pays well. I need to find the "Jewel" artifact and bring it to him.</text>
	</string>
	
^	<string id="country_karlik_pda">
^		<text>Thermal artifacts</text>
^	</string>
	<string id="country_karlik_pda_text">
        <text>Artifact Studier's Journal. Note One: Thermal Artifacts.\n\n\n\nRecord one. In large clusters of the "Burner" anomaly, the chance of more rare artifacts to be born increases - however, the number of produced artifacts is reduced.\n\nRecord two. I heard a story about the "Flame" artifact which is allegedly born in extreme temperatures and has no equal in healing wounds. Of course, I decided to check it out. On the third week of searching I found something similar to the "Fireball" artifact but much brighter and a lot warmer. Irradiating much but really, when I'd taken it in my hands, all the scratches dragged on - amazingly. It's almost impossible to find such a miracle: the chance of its occurrence is minimal, these things are only born in very large clusters of thermal anomalies of various kinds, and only close to the Zone center - past Radar.\n\nThis artifact does not leave me alone: it can be so useful! I found something startling: in the most strong fire anomalies, at a depth of 15-20 meters, an unseen kind of "Flame" is born - I called this artifact "Hell". I saw a similar place to the East of the Radar... but is not possible to get out of that anomaly, nor to survive inside of it.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="country_military_code">
        <text>Military's code part</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_military_code_text">
        <text>I still haven't found the other half of this damn code. The only thing that I know is the number 47.</text>
	</string>