<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

    <!--Sid start-->
	
    <string id="esc_sid_start_00">
        <text>Don't look so surprised marked one, I checked your PDA and saw the entry about Strelok. Look, I don't know what living hell you've come from or who you are for that matter, but if you help me, I'll help you. What do you say Marked One?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_01">
        <text>Well, at this moment in time, you seem like my best or only hope of finding this "Strelok" guy. Doesn't seem like I have much of a choice...</text>
    </string>
     <string id="esc_sid_start_011">
        <text>So, should I spoon-feed you like I usually do with all the rookies or maybe I can treat you like a real stalker and give you a mission straight away?</text>
    </string>
     <string id="esc_sid_start_0111">
        <text>Treat me like a rookie, I don't remember anything.</text>
    </string>
     <string id="esc_sid_start_0112">
        <text>I don't remember anything about myself, but I certainly do remember how to carry a weapon. So, how can I help you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_002">
        <text>OK, thanks. How can I help you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_00221">
        <text>Thanks. What should I do now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_002221">
        <text>I see your pockets are empty, it's not a good idea to walk through the Zone without any equipment. So first, go back downstairs and get your stuff from the dresser.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_0022221">
        <text>Ok, I'll be back right now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_20">
        <text>Done, so how can I help you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_30">
        <text>Hurry up please, I have my own business to do...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_31">
        <text>One minute.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_020">
        <text>Any luck?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_00021">
        <text>I have also uploaded the Personal Digital Advisor 2.0 application to your PDA. It will give you tips from time to time, teach you the basics for survival out there.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_sid_start_02">
		<text>That's the spirit stalker! I'm starting to like you already. You got out of that Death Truck in pretty good shape too. Can't say the same for your PDA, there are some corrupted files, maybe due to some external damage. Oh, it still works, as you have seen, well, mostly. The maps are intact, you can check your notes and online contacts and whatnot. And at least you can still receive incoming messages - isn't that what counts, eh? Anyway, I haven't got a replacement for you so you're stuck with this one. Now, let's get down to business shall we? I don't know anything about you, boy, and I want to see if you're able to run some simple errands before I trust you with any real work. There's this artifact I need to close a business deal. Some rookies informed me that they saw one in this little bog not far from here - could be just the one I need. Check it out for me will you? Bring back the artifact and then we can talk some more.\n\nAnd one more thing: I also found this hickey of yours... a handcraft device that helps you detect artifacts. These used to be popular in the Zone, and now nobody gives a crap about them: everyone's trying to get something more decent. I've already dredged the detector up - and there's one thing I can say for sure: the database is deep inside. But it can still detect the simplest artifacts - so be glad! However, I'd actually recommend you to buy an "Echo": it's a lower class detecting device, yet it's way better than the thing you're holding right now. And there will be a discount for you - you got me for that.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_03">
        <text>I guess I can do that. I'm on my way!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_04">
        <text>I think I found what you were looking for.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_sid_start_05">
        <text>Good, very good! You know, most guys would've run away with the swag and left me to the mutants! Now I see I can trust you.\nSpeaking of the devil, I think one of my contacts is in danger - probably spotted by the Military dogs. I would be grateful if you helped him. I really need the flash drive he's carrying, and I can't let it fall into the wrong hands.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--Proverb 1-->	
	
	<string id="proverb_start_0">
		<text>If it isn't the survivor! If you want to ask something - go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_start_1">
		<text>Stalker! You finally woke up! I thought you would never get back to your senses!</text>
	</string>		 
	<string id="proverb_start_2">
		<text>Ohh... Such a headache... And who are you?</text>
	</string>		 
	<string id="proverb_start_3">
		<text>I'm Proverb, a local stalker. I found you in that truck a week ago.</text>
	</string> 		 
	<string id="proverb_start_4">
		<text>What truck? Where is it now?</text>
	</string> 		
	<string id="proverb_start_5">
		<text>It was a Death Truck but now it's a complete wreck. It's on the far side of Cordon, close to the Garbage. I dragged you out of there all by myself and brought you to Sid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_start_6">
		<text>That must have been a long way. You are a tough fellow!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_start_7">
		<text>You know, it's always good to help someone if you can. You never know from who and when you may need help, you know? What goes around comes around. Today I'm helping, and maybe I will need help tomorrow, and may God have mercy there will be someone to help me in time. And those bastards who don't care about anyone other than themselves usually join the ranks of the bandits. Who keeps company with pseudodogs, will learn to howl. Therefore, no one will would help such as those.</text>
	</string>			
	<string id="proverb_start_8">
		<text>Thank you very much for saving me! I am in your debt.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="proverb_start_9">
		<text>Thank you as well, a kind word is better than any wealth, right? Although earning money in the zone is also necessary. Sidorovich gave me a couple tasks to clear out some mutants, and I think your assistance could be a good opportunity to recollect your hunting skills. If you help me now, that will square us with your debt to me.</text>
	</string>		 
	<string id="proverb_start_10">
		<text>Well, in this sort of outfit and with that gun I will not be able to take care of the mutants, which unlike everything else, I remember well.</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="proverb_start_11">
		<text>What's wrong with the outfit? Not every newcomer has such. The eyes are afraid, but the deed is done by the arms. As for the weapons, I could help you with that. But it seems you've have some task from Sidorovich to complete. Get that job done first and then we'll talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_start_12">
		<text>Well, see you later, then. Although the Zone isn't a place where it's easy to make plans for the future, so let it ride. Well, I have to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_start_13">
		<text>Not really, I just wanted to say thanks again for saving me. Alright, see you later.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Proverb 2-->
	
	<string id="proverb_first_task_start_0">
		<text>Well, business before pleasure. Time for some work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_start_1">
		<text>Are you asking me to help or to do everything for you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_start_2">
		<text>Monolith favours the brave. And he always rushes to the fore... and gets into the whirligig. Just help me; it's not like a little warm up will hurt. I think I've told that before... Don't count your crows before they are hatched.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_start_3">
		<text>You know I've just recovered from an amnesia, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_start_4">
		<text>Oh come on, don't get mad... By the way, hunting mutants with a pistol will get you killed fast. Every stalker knows that a shotgun is your best friend when dealing with them. Here, take my sawed-off for now, I don't use it anyway. Now, just follow me. Oh and don't be afraid of mutant. You know what they say - "He who fears every Burnt Fuzz must never go artifact hunting"!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_start_5">
		<text>This will be useful... but Sid asked me to find one of his contacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_start_6">
		<text>That guy?.. he never saw the heli coming! It's to late for him already, his body will be there later... rotting probably, ha! So help me first.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_start_7">
		<text>OK, onward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_1_0">
		<text>Pretty beasts you've got here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_1_1">
		<text>That's not all, let's clear out another place. What rookie's eyes fear is a piece of cake for a seasoned stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_1_2">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_2_0">
		<text>Looks like we've done it. Man, these stink, making my eyes water.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_2_1">
		<text>If you can't stand the heat get out of the burner! So be strong. Yeah... that was some great teamwork.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_2_2">
		<text>So what's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_2_3">
		<text>Treat me as a friend - we're even now. Go now, do the thing Sidorovich asked you to do and here is a little something for your efforts. What? Yours look like something Sidor found on the bottom of a garbage bin.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="proverb_first_task_2_4">
		<text>Thank you and see you next time.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Get 1st drive-->
	
    <string id="escape_trader_heli_attacks_00">
        <text>Alright, I'll go and check. But remember, I scratch your back...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_heli_attacks_01">
        <text>Yes, yes! Now please hurry up. I marked his last known position on your PDA map.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_heli_attacks_02">
        <text>By the way, did I have some equipment with me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_heli_attacks_03">
        <text>Ah yes, you had some things. I put them in the top of the wooden drawer downstairs. Take them. And remember, you are welcome to store your goods here anytime.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_heli_attacks_04">
        <text>Ah, thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_heli_attacks_05">
        <text>On my way.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--Give 1st drive-->
	
    <string id="escape_trader_got_drive_00">
        <text>Your contact was dead, but I found his flash drive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_got_drive_01">
        <text>Phew, I needed this. Was there only one dead guy over there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_got_drive_02">
        <text>Yes, there was only one body.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_got_drive_03">
        <text>Then I've got another job for you. There's a second guy that's probably in the factory above the hills - you've at least seen it in the distance, I'm sure. It's crawling with bandits, so he's surely dead by now, but I need his belongings as well as the place cleared of bandits. Talk with Wolf, he might be able to spare a few men for such a mission.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_got_drive_04">
        <text>OK, I'll go see him.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_trader_got_drive_31">
        <text>Actually I went there already and killed all the bandits in sight.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_trader_got_drive_311">
        <text>Oh, ok well excuse me Rambo...Did you happen to spot a fallen stalker there with a special artefact on his person?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_trader_got_drive_3111">
        <text>No, never found anything like that there.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_trader_got_drive_31111">
        <text>Ok, please you must go back and find him and retrieve the stuff.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_trader_got_drive_311111">
        <text>Ok, I'll go back there and see what I can dig up.</text>
    </string>
	
    <!--Wolf factory assault-->
	
    <string id="escape_wolf_assault_00">
        <text>Sid says you might be able to help me deal with the bandits at the factory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_assault_01">
        <text>If information and coordinates are helpful to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_assault_02">
        <text>Can't you spare a few rookies? It would make for a nice learning experience.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_assault_03">
        <text>Petruha and his team can help you, if you insist. They've been raring to go and flush the scum out for awhile. I heard there is some kind of deal going down between the Bandits and this Merc named Mad Dog, hopefully you can take him out too! I can't spare anybody else though, so tough shit. Those Military bastards keep us on close watch - if they notice an opportunity, they'll storm our camp and slaughter us. Tell you what, if you kill those banditos, I'll give you a little reward as my personal thanks. How does that sound?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_assault_04">
        <text>Wonderful, I'll go meet them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_0">
        <text>Hey! What can I do for you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_00">
        <text>The bandits at the factory are dead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_01">
        <text>Great job. Sorry that I underestimated you mate! Did you get Mad Dog too? Here, take what I promised. Now we may be able to hold the factory for a while!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_02">
        <text>I saw Mad Dog, but he got away, looked like they were trading some artifact...Anyway, thanks for the reward, see you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_3">
        <text>Can you answer some of my questions?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_4">
        <text>Sure, why not.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_41">
        <text>So you're the leader of this rookie camp?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_411">
        <text>Yes. I've been for a while now. It's tough sometimes since everyone seems to rely on you, but it's worth it. As long as the Zone exists, there will be someone taking care of the rookies here. I'm just another one.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_4111">
        <text>Well, you`re doing a good job.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_42">
        <text>Why are you here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_421">
        <text>Wasn`t anything left for me back home. Came here like any other rookie and made it all the way to the Army Warehouses. After making a little fortune for myself, I decided to come back here and coach the next generation of stalkers. I took it upon myself to take the position when the last leader died. He was a good man, that Valerian...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_4211">
        <text>I see.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_43">
        <text>Who do you think will take up your mantle once you're gone?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_431">
        <text>Who knows? I've got a few candidates in mind, but in the end it's the rookies who decide. They are the ones who acknowledge a leader's power, after all. A leader without authority is as worthless as a dull razor.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_4311">
        <text>Yeah that's true.</text>
</string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_44">
        <text>Do you have any family here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_441">
        <text>I have a brother, Hound. He was always fascinated with the Zone and ran off to help the eggheads with their tests and experiments. Haven't seen him for long. I assume the Zone has him now.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_4411">
        <text>Sorry to hear.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_5">
        <text>Do you wana know something else?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_45">
		<text>Do you know something about mercenaries? I saw one at the factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_451">
		<text>Really bad guys: maniacs, sadists and murderers. They killed a lot of stalkers for their own mercantile goals. Better not to deal with them, but if you'll meet this one from the factory, feed him with bullets for all our murdered comrades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_4511">
		<text>Got it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_46">
        <text>I have another question...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_6">
        <text>I got into a tussle with the bandits at the factory and killed them all, hope you don't mind.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_61">
        <text>Yeah, Sid mentioned he sent you to me but I guess you were too eager to stop. Anyway, good job, here is a gesture of our appreciation.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_611">
        <text>Appreciate it, see you around.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_62">
        <text>Heh, a regular renegade eh? Well, we like people like you, here's a little something for you and from now on call me friend!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_factory_greetings_621">
        <text>Appreciate it, see you around.</text>
    </string>
	
    <!--Petruha assault-->

	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_31">
		<text>Hi, Wolf has already sent word of you. Do you have any questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_311">
		<text>Yes. How many bandits are in the camp?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_3111">
		<text>Five or six. Most are inside the main complex, but I guess someone is patrolling the north entrance. Shall we say a prayer and go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_31111">
		<text>Yes, round up your men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_31112">
		<text>No, we'd make too much noise, I'll go on my own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_311121">
		<text>Hey, if you wanna play Rambo, go for it, I wont stop you. Just cry for help when you need it, ok hero?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_41">
		<text>We went hunting as a pack of wolves, and hunt we did! I bet Wolf will be pleased. Heh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_51">
		<text>There's more of 'em! Find the bastards and take them down!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_61">
		<text>Whoa, man! Now that was something! You wiped them out and left nothing for us. I'd never believe it if I hadn't seen it with my own eyes! That blew me away, man...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_71">
		<text>So, where are the piles of enemies you killed? You talk the talk, but you don't walk the walk. Get lost!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_81">
		<text>I don't know who you are. Go and speak with Wolf at the village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_factory_assault_start_82">
		<text>Ok, will do.</text>
	</string>
			
	<!--Sid: Save Fox-->
	  	
    <string id="escape_trader_factory_greetings_00">
        <text>Your second contact was dead too. I found an artifact and PDA on his body.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_factory_greetings_01">
        <text>Ah, come to Papa - the client was getting impatient over the artifact. As for the PDA, well... that's only for my lecherous eyes. Oh, and Marked One, when you've got the time I have something I'd like to discuss with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_fox_rescue_0">
        <text>What was it you wanted to discuss?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_fox_rescue_1">
        <text>If you insist on knowing, I have a delicate situation that needs tact. Still interested?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_fox_rescue_2">
        <text>Explain, old man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_fox_rescue_3">
        <text>One of my contacts got himself in a pickle. His name is Fox. Maybe you've seen him before. For some reason, these "Sin" bastards have got him hostage. These guys... they look like zombies, but even worse. They talk, eat, drink and shit in the bushes like your normal guys, but they've got a ferocious glare to them - spooky stuff, even to veterans. Word of advice, Duty hates these guys with a passion... go there and see what they want, if you want to kill them, go ahead... Duty will probably let you in their ranks someday. If you see what they want and help them out, then Duty may never let you in. Try not to have a heart attack when you eyeball those Sin bastards!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_fox_rescue_4">
        <text>I'll see what I can do about them.</text>
    </string>
		
	<!--Fox hostage-->
	
	<string id="escape_deal_fox_dstalkers_00">
		<text>What do you want, stalker?!</text>
	</string>
    <string id="escape_deal_fox_dstalkers_0">
        <text>Can you tell me why you're holding Fox hostage?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_deal_fox_dstalkers_1">
        <text>Why the hell should you care? Got anything to say about it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_deal_fox_dstalkers_2">
        <text>Sidorovich sent me to cut a deal with you, so chill.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_deal_fox_dstalkers_3">
        <text>Hah! So the bigoted fat idiot wants a deal? If he means it, then tell him our Boss wants the flash drive he has with "that" information. He'll know what we want. Now scram, before we just split your spine in half, twerp.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_deal_fox_dstalkers_4">
        <text>I'll try to ask him in nicer terms.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--Get info from Sid-->
	
    <string id="escape_dealing_fox_info_0">
        <text>I've talked to them. They say you have a flash drive with "that" on it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_dealing_fox_info_1">
        <text>Hah-hah, should've known! I've heard that other traders are being coerced into handing them that kind of info. Hell, even when Duty is redoubling their efforts on finding their hideout, they have the balls to show up... Determined brats.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_dealing_fox_info_2">
        <text>What type of information would Sin want from you guys?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_dealing_fox_info_4">
        <text>About the hidden underground labs and experiments, that kind of shady stuff. They're obsessed with them. I've heard from Barkeep that they are searching for something in particular within them. The traders think it has something relating to their... condition. Maybe it's just makeup on their faces; I can't really say for sure. See, there's an unspoken rule around here to keep the whole "secret labs" thing minimal, unless it can help us head further North, past the Brain Scorcher. Otherwise, we've got to start asking ourselves some rather uncomfortable questions regarding the Zone and the experiments that were once performed here. It's Pandora's Box... \nAh, just forget about that boring old stuff, I'm just talking to myself here... Take the info back to our lovely friends and get Fox outta there. I got everything I needed out of it anyway. Tell 'em to stick it where the sun don't shine too if you can.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_dealing_fox_info_5">
        <text>Oh sure, I will tell them that... if you want Fox back in pieces that is.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--Sin give info-->
	
    <string id="esc_giving_sin_info_0">
        <text>Here's what you wanted. Sid gives his "sincerest" greetings and wanted you to know it's useless to him anyways.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_giving_sin_info_1">
        <text>If he thinks we get teary-eyed over a sarcastic quip, then he's got another thing coming - that bunker door of his isn't impenetrable. Now, take that stalker out of here and don't come back, unless you like the taste of lead!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_giving_sin_info_2">
        <text>...OK, got it.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--sin ward-->
	
	<string id="esc_sin_ward_1">
        <text>Nothing, I'll be back.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="esc_sin_ward_2">
        <text>Nothing, just passing through. I'll be on my way.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!-- sin fox dead -->
	
	<string id="esc_sin_dead_fox_1">
        <text>You have no more business with us. Piss off!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_sin_dead_fox_2">
        <text>Fine, see you.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--Saved Fox-->
	
    <string id="escape_trader_fox_done_0">
        <text>I saved Fox, so what now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_fox_done_1">
        <text>Hey, good job with that. He came by to say hi and I didn't even see a hole in his body!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_fox_done_2">
        <text>No big deal. So, have you found out anything about this Strelok character?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_trader_fox_done_21">
        <text>No big deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_fox_done_3">
        <text>Indeed I have my friend. There is a stalker out there that goes by that name. Some say he has found a way North - a passage we traders have been seeking ever since we arrived here. I'd like to find out how he got there myself along with Barkeep and others. It's in an unexplored area,  full of artifacts no doubt. Barkeep and I will help you find him, then maybe you will discover the hidden pathway too. It's a win-win situation for all of us: You will find Strelok and do whatever you have to, and we will open up a way to the northern reaches of the Zone. Personally I don't think you will find him, but there is a chance that you'll succeed where most have failed. Nothing ventured, nothing gained. Don't disapoint us, Marked One.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!-- seriy task text -->
	
    <string id="escape_trader_fox_done_4">
        <text>OK, so where can I start?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_trader_fox_done_5">
        <text>Seems a stalker named Seriy knows about him. He's hanging around the hangar in the Garbage. You should go talk to him.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_trader_fox_done_6">
        <text>OK, great, I'm on my way.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--Fox thanks-->
	
    <string id="escape_fox_greatings_0">
        <text>Hey, thanks for dealing with those Sin guys, real ugly bastards!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_greatings_1">
        <text>I've seen worse before... I think.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_greatings_2">
        <text>Anyway, the name is Fox. I'm the mechanic around these parts. If you need anything repaired or fine-tuned such as suits and weapons, I can do it for a price. Though I'll be sure to give you a nice discount after what you've done for me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_fox_greatings_3">
		<text>Well, thanks... sounds good.</text>
	</string>
		
	<!--Fox the fixer-->
	
    <string id="perfor_fix_0000">
        <text>Hey, Marked One! What can I do for you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="perfor_fix_0001">
        <text>You are able to fix weapons and suits, right?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="perfor_fix_0002">
        <text>Yes, I will repair everything you will bring me. Of course, you have to pay me, minus the discount I'll give you. I can also tweak your gear and install upgrades to better whatever you have.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="perfor_fix_0003">
        <text>I see.</text>
    </string>
        <string id="perfor_fix_0004">
        <text>Hi Fox!</text>
    </string>
		
	<!--Sid: Save Nimble-->
		
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_0">
		<text>So how many contacts do you have?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_00">
		<text>Oh, since you mentioned contacts, I need you to find one guy - name's Nimble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_1">
		<text>Why do your contacts always get into trouble?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_2">
		<text>This guy isn't exactly my contact... Let's say, he does a special job for me: that kind of job which you can't give to the usual boneheads. That's why I value him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_3">
		<text>I could search for him if you gave me more information on where to do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_4">
		<text>Last time he had contacted me, he was already here on Cordon, near the bridge. He has good relations with the military at the bridge - they always let him pass, - so I don't think there could be any trouble. But he'd disappeared anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_5">
		<text>I'll do my best, but I have no idea where could he have gone... thus, no guarantees.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_6">
		<text>I really hope you'll find him... Alright, go look for him. I'll be looking forward to hearing news from you.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Rescuing Nimble-->
	
	<string id="esc_shustriy_first_talk_0">
		<text>People! Is there anyone around here?!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_first_talk_1">
		<text>Who are you? Why are you sitting in there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_first_talk_2">
		<text>I'm just a Stalker! A poltergeist got me locked, it holds the door. I can't get out. Help, please! Kill this monster so I can open the door!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_first_talk_3">
		<text>There are many poltergeists around here. Alright, wait a little, I'll take care of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_second_talk_0">
		<text>Howdy, stoller, feeling better already? How long have you been here? Is it you who people call Nimble?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_second_talk_1">
		<text>Yes, that's me! I've been here for 2 days already. Still have some food left, but it got hard to breathe. The vent isn't working down here. Are you the guy who was brought unconsciouss right to the village?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_second_talk_2">
		<text>Yes, it's me. We better talk about this later, don't want to be locked here together, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_second_talk_3">
		<text>Yeah, that's right, God knows what else may creep around here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_0">
		<text>Phew, seems like we're out. It's good news for Sidorovich, he was getting worried about you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_1">
		<text>Did you seriously believe the old man that he worried about me? Ha! His only interest is money, he has no care about human life. Yes, maybe I'm more important to him than other stalker that work for him, but it's because I always get things done. But he sends me to such shitty places, it's hard not to shiver when I think about them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_2">
		<text>But he did send me to find you after all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_3">
		<text>He just needs the results of my last task, that's all. I won't tell you the details, I'll just say that I stole lots of information, from the military and a little from other places. Hacked several computers...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_4">
		<text>Why wouldn't you stop working for him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_5">
		<text>That's not your business, alright? You believe I want to work for the old man? Life can be complicated so I don't have another choice. I won't find better money than Sidorovich pays.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_6">
		<text>You could go after rare artifacts, you are Nimble after all! Or join mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_7">
		<text>I've big issues with anomalies. I don't feel their presence. I'm using my detector all the time and keep damn far distance between me and those damn traps. And I'm never going to kill people just for money! I have an old idea though, but I can't get it working on my own...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_8">
		<text>Your own business?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_9">
		<text>You could say so. For now, here's what we are going to do: you go tell Sido that I'm fine and unharmed while I go get some decent sleep. After that, come talk to me, we'll discuss my business plan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_after_talk_10">
		<text>Okay, just don't get into another shitty situation on your way back.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Nimble saved-->
	
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_done_0">
		<text>I've completed the task: Nimble is in a safe place, alive and in good health. Or not exactly in good... anyway, you can ask him yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_done_1">
		<text>Yeah, very funny. I know Nimble is already here. Thanks - and here's your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_nimble_task_done_2">
		<text>See you.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Sid: steal the military case-->
		
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_0">
		<text>You said something about a special task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_1b">
		<text>Yes, I did... but you're not the guy to get it done: you already had a beef with the military - while I need to do everything as quiet and under-the-radar as possible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_2b">
		<text>Couldn't you have said it before? Yeah, I just lost my time because of you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_1">
		<text>Yeah, there is something special: it's about the flash drive you brought. That data isn't so interesting... but if the Sinners are interested, then it seems like the information is correct and the military laboratories actually do exist. Besides, a group of military stalkers have brought a case from somewhere deep in the Zone. I don't know what's inside the case but I really want to find out. There's a chance the case may have important documents about the labs or something like that. It's a task of high importance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_2">
		<text>I understand, but how can I steal something from a place that is swarming with military?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_3">
	   <text>You'll have to go during the night, along with the fence. Only that way! There's a breach in the fence, go through it and climb into the barracks through a window. That way, you will sneak in swimmingly. You'll get out the same way, got it? I drew the map from words of my contact specially for such case - I'll upload it to your PDA. And another thing: I won't help you if you'll get caught or if you kill some of the military. Do it quiet and there won't be any trouble.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_4">
	   <text>Alright, wish me luck then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_done_0">
	   <text>That was quite dangerous. Here is the case, really heavy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_done_1">
	   <text>Excellent, Marked One! Well... let me take a look. I've just seen a glimpse of it and already getting goosebumps from reading it! Everything is mixed together so it's impossible to make a clear picture out of this, but they always mention Agroprom in these documents. It's written: "According to the experiment results in Agroprom Research Institute it seems..."</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_done_2">
	   <text>What do you think to do now with this data?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_done_3">
	   <text>I could say, there's no "information". Almost every second page is missing. Besides, from what's left, half of the records are damaged, no way you can read them. But I'm eager to find more, perhaps it will help us to solve this problem with the Center of the Zone.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_done_4">
	   <text>What's our next move?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_black_work_done_5">
	   <text>We will do it this way. You go where you were headed while I try to make something out of these documents. I'll contact you once I arranged a new task.</text>	
	</string>
	
	<!--Sid: Agroprom documents-->
	
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_0">
		<text>I'm here to talk about the Agroprom docs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_1">
		<text>Anything wrong?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_a">
		<text>I haven't found anything. And I won't look anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_a1">
		<text>Why's that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_a2">
		<text>I don't have time for it: there's some business, like finding Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_b">
		<text>I haven't found anything yet, but I'm working on that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_b1">
		<text>That's good, Marked One, I'm waiting for the results.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_done1">
		<text>Um... that's not much. Well, It's better than nothing. We - Barman, Petrenko and I - have already discussed this matter. So go to them for further instructions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_done2">
		<text>Good, I see. Wait, will there be any other task from you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_done3">
		<text>No, that's all. These Sinners made clear that I should keep away from this business; I'll give them everything you've found. But you can still bring me some artifacts, if you want. I'm currently in need of these: "Battery", "Shell", and "Spring".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_done4">
		<text>Great, I can bring you them - for a good reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_done2no">
		<text>Alright, I've got to go. Bye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_done4no">
		<text>No, I don't want to do this, I have my own stuff to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_not_done5">
		<text>Well, as you want. Alright, go do your business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_done0">
		<text>Here's everything I found.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_done1">
		<text>Well yeah, that's really interesting. And... there's nothing specific. Almost. It only says they've got some materials from another facility. Very interesting. We - Barman, Petrenko and I - have already discussed this matter. But there are many gaps... seems like all the Zone was just a testing ground of military and scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_done2">
		<text>What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_done3">
		<text>First off, bring the case to Barman. And then... I've digged much, but the Sinners made clear that I should keep away from this business. So I'll stop that, but there's just one place I want to check before that - the old mine in the Forest; perhaps there are some documents left. So, head there and grab everything you can... but don't bring it here - to Petrenko instead; he'll be pleased.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_done4">
		<text>I see. Well, at least the info is much more clear this time. I'll search for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sidor_doc_work_done41">
		<text>Alright, I'll look for somebody else to do the job.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Sid: artifacts delivered-->
	
	<string id="esc_sid_task_arty_done_0">
		<text>Just like ordered - the three artefacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sid_task_arty_done_2">
		<text>Good, Marked One. Well, I can offer you either good ammo or money. What do you choose?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sid_task_arty_done_3">
		<text>Give me the ammo - I have enough money for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sid_task_arty_done_4">
		<text>What type ammo will you take?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sid_task_arty_done_a">
		<text>Give me 5.45 - old but gold.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sid_task_arty_done_b">
		<text>5.56 is just what I need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sid_task_arty_done_c">
		<text>I would take 9x39.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sid_task_arty_done_d">
		<text>I need something different, give me the 7.62x54.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sid_task_arty_done_5">
		<text>Here you go:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sid_task_arty_done_e">
		<text>Just give me the money - I have enough ammo.</text>
	</string>

	<!--Nimble: tell me about-->
	
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_0">
		<text>Hey. I'd like to ask you about something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_00">
		<text>Yes, go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_000">
		<text>You're not military, are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_1">
		<text>Yes, mate, you got that right. Not in the military, and I never wanted want to join the regular army back in the day: I was hiding from authorities. What's to hide? It's not like I feel bad about it, to be honest. Of course I'm not a former Spetsnaz since I managed to evade national military service; neither I'm one of the hunters - I've never slept in a tent - not even starting on resting in a sleeping bag in the base of a fallen tree. I know most of stalkers here got some sort of background and a load of skills which help them survive, but I - don't.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_2a">
		<text>So, you're sort of wunderkind, am I right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_3a">
		<text>No, that's a miss. I'm a waif with a lot of thieving experience and some criminal records; had to run here to avoid the jail - the last job wasn't done properly, left lots of trails... No one here knew about my past, and it wasn't hard to look like a nice guy to others. And then I got into this trouble... I could never get rid of this 'nice funny young guy' appearance, damn it. I had to keep myself that way: nimble, wingbag, friendly, and always ready to help the troublesome comrades. I chose this "skin" and it got stuck on me, like I was hypnotized, infected with some virus. I don't feel myself the same way as before; I'm really ready to help someone out: have a talk about the life, listen to people...</text>
	</string> 
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_4a">
		<text>So you sort of decided to start another life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_5a">
		<text>I wouldn't say I did - there was no decision; it all just... happened. I'd be glad to say my conscience woke up, but I'm still having nightmares: the past doesn't let me go, I run but can't get away... I'd gladly say I went here to redeem my sins, but damn - it never was like this: I entered as one person - but became a different one for some anomalous reason. The stalkers keep saying it must've been the Zone that changed me, they keep brainwashing me for almost a year now: "Look, the Zone accepted you and made you a better man". Well, that is my story, maybe it will give you something to think about. I didn't change, but came out entirely different man...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_0a">
		<text>You got some other questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_2b">
		<text>What can you tell me about the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_3b">
		<text>It's a strange place. What can I tell you? I'm a great example of why is is strange. Seems like I was supposed to find my death on the day of arrival; I got a rest in an old bus on the Garbage vehicle junkyard... starting to make sense, right? No doubt I was supposed to rot the day after with such doze of radiation stalkers measured there later. However, only my Makarov pistol and my flip-knife went nuclear. My old companions, always kept them close. Had to throw them away...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_4b">
		<text>Ever went deep in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_5b">
		<text>Yeah, I did - accidentally: wandered much. For example, I happened to see the Pripyat sign with my own eyes - I was wandering in its vicinity. When I got some artifacts from there and took them to Sid's desk, our chief haggler nearly died of surprise. The folks started to think of me as some kind of a charm: they got the habit of shaking hands with me before going out there. I don't watch them, but they are all living to this day, or so they say. Well, it's pretty simple actually: the mindset does it all. You're not a fan of mystics, I hope? I don't need another newbie squeezing my hand again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_6b">
		<text>All the strange stuff aside, what the Zone is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_7b">
		<text>It's a place where you have to appear humble and poor: good gear is seen from afar. Sooner or later, you'll get yourself robbed and naked in some shithole - and maybe even get a bullet in your head. I said that because you really need good equipment. With our local fauna and the frickin' bandits you won't last long without the decent gun and armor under the jacket. Screw the criminals, but sometimes even a good friend of yours can backstab you... The thing is, you shouldn't show your gear off. Like, never. All the strange things apart, the Zone is the place where you should get your things off in the bushes, and then go to the folks around the campfire. I already have a dozen of such bushes around - I should set up a shop... an idea of which I already have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_2c">
		<text>What are your thoughts on Sidorovich?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_3c">
		<text>Seasoned dealer. He won't let his profits go - well, it's pretty usual for a trader who won't let his business down. You should have a knack for trading, so to speak. I'll tell you what, nick down: behind a good-natured windbag, there is a shadow of a sneaky bastard. He can get rid of somebody as easy as pick his nose... don't even ask me how I know that - just remember what I've said. Sooner or later he'll be put down, but I think it'll more likely to happen much more later than sooner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_4c">
		<text>Why did you get hired by him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_5c">
		<text>I can't say I've been hired: I work for anyone who gives tasks with reasonable rewards. To be honest, Sid turns out to be just the man for that, most of the time. Also, there's a tactical move - and I didn't come up with it - that you should keep your enemies closer. The tasks themselves tell much about his business: how far his arms reach out, and where they haven't been yet. The most interesting thing is who he is afraid of. There is one well-known person, with whom he is careful to the bootlicking. If you hang around for a longer time, you'll get who I'm talking about.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_2d">
		<text>Do you know anything about Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_3d">
		<text>It's more interesting to ask you why would you even care about him. But I'll tell you about him, not much though. Just don't have anything to do with fanatics such as Strelok, those guys who always circle around the Center of the Zone, and some even say they were lucky to get to the center. You can't expect that such a story will end well, right? If the Zone has these barriers which prevent people from going to the Center, they mean it isn't welcoming anyone who gets that far. Strelok was one of those uninvited guests, a fanatic. Forget about him for your own sake - this is all I know about Strelok and his group, fanatics and those who cheer for such individuals.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_2f">
		<text>And what do you think about the factions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_3f">
		<text>Oh, that's another story. I'm not interested in that, and I wouldn't advise you to join any. It's easier to be a loner. There were some guys; they said, "We want to study the Zone from the inside". Took me in, despite my past. Turns out, they just needed the cannon fodder - their entire top brass are complete psychopaths: ruined the whole faction, although there were many good men... So, I'm not into that anymore. Came here, to the Cordon, when the faction was no more, and made myself quite living. I'm afraid to meet someone of them, won't tell you why.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_20">
		<text>I don't have any more questions, thanks for the answers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_about_talk_30">
		<text>You are welcome, come around to have a talk if you want.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Nimble's tasks introduction-->	
	
	<string id="esc_shustriy_work_start_0">
		<text>Hi! Rested well? I'd like to discuss this "business plan" of yours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_work_start_1">
		<text>Yes, Marked One, I wanted to talk about it as well. The risk isn't longer worth the rewards, so I won't work for Sidorovich. I got plenty of contacts around the Zone, found out a lot. Now it's time to take action, but I need a partner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_work_start_2">
		<text>I'd gladly help you, as long as I get my part of the profits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_work_start_3">
		<text>So, the plan is quite simple. I can't compete with Sidorovich but I know his weaknesses. He always sells common goods of lower quality. But you can never buy something really worthy, reliable or rare. That's why I want to take a part of his clients - experienced Stalkers who want decent gear for their money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_work_start_4">
		<text>You won't find many experienced Stalkers in the rookie village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_work_start_5">
		<text>Yes, I know, that's why I'm first going to populate my stock with wares, and then move on to a place with people who can pay well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_work_start_6">
		<text>And what do you need of me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_work_start_7">
		<text>Rare weapons and armor. Any self-made or professional modifications are good, the only condition is that it should be better than the usual stuff. You are confident with the weapons, you're more experienced than anybody in this camp. So we do everything simple: I give you a job to find a weapon, you get'em. Sometimes it'll be hard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustriy_work_start_8">
		<text>I see. Well, yeah, that suits me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_a_esc_shustriy_has_no_job">
		<text>There are no contracts now, sorry.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="tm_a_esc_shustriy_job_ask">
        <text>What did you want to talk about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tm_a_esc_shustriy_job_complete">
        <text>Here's the payment:</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tm_a_esc_shustriy_job_what">
        <text>What about the job?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tm_a_esc_shustriy_list_job">
        <text>Now we have these contracts:</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--Nimble: contracts-->
	
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_0">
		<text>What'll the first job be?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_1">
		<text>Yeah, there is one. Listen carefully: There are military quarters on the territory of the former Research Institute, to the west of the Garbage. I don't understand what they're doing there, although I have some thoughts on that. But that's not what interests me. I precisely know that their leader, who knows his rank, has an interesting gun. Like the common "Groza", but adapted to the 5.45 ammo and with an extended clip. Very handy thing. We'll discuss the payment later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_2">
		<text>Well yeah, it's just the matter of three minutes: steal the favourite gun of the military outpost's head, considering I don't even where it is. Alright, I have to go.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task1_stop_0">
        <text>Listen, Nimble, I don't want your tasks anymore.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task1_stop_1">
        <text>I see. Have you thought it through? If you refuse, there's no more work for you. But know this - I'll establish my business even without your help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task1_stop_21">
        <text>Yes, I refuse!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task1_stop_22">
        <text>Although... No, I changed my mind. I'll look for that Groza of yours...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_0">
		<text>Take your "Groza"! I've decided not to keep it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_1">
		<text>Wow, finally! Oh well, I have to fix it up. But there's one problem... I don't have the money to pay for it, we have to find a buyer first. So you can chose: \n Either trust me and get your payment later. \n Or keep the gun, but I won't work with you anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_2a">
		<text>Alright, damn you. Take it, but remember that you owe me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_2b">
		<text>Nah, that's not going to work. No money - no gunney. I'm sorry, but it's impossible to work on pure trust.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_3a">
		<text>Great. So, will you go with me? I know where to stash it. And the other stuff that I have. Well, I'll go in any case, you can join me if you want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_4aa">
		<text>Well yeah, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_4ab">
		<text>No, I've got something to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_3b">
		<text>Good luck then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_5ab">
		<text>So what about the next task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_yes">
		<text>I don't mind working some more. What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_done_no">
		<text>Nah, that's enough for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task2_1">
		<text>Then listen carefully: there's one criminal bigshot, the one called Borov. Huge guy. Always carries a big revolver around. That's the gun I need. He's at the bandits base in the Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task2_2">
		<text>One task harder than the other. At first, the gun of the military head, then the bandit leader's gun. Alright, I'll go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_item_0">
		<text>Well, what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_item_1">
		<text>That's the place, where I stash the things. Nobody goes here, and I've spiced up the whole thing after that poltergeist accident. Even if somebody comes here, he won't find anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_item_2">
		<text>So what, you'll be trading here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_item_3">
		<text>No, I'll get some more goods, and then I'll go to the Bar. I have enough contacts already, everything's set up. Alright, let's get out of here, it's creepy here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_item_4">
		<text>Yeah, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_item_5">
		<text>Wait... Will you take a job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_item_yes">
		<text>Alright, why not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task1_item_no">
		<text>Sometime later, I've got something else to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task1_reward_0">
		<text>Well, can you already pay me for "Groza"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task1_reward_00">
		<text>Nah, sorry, there was no buyer yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task1_reward_1">
		<text>Yeah,I just wanted to tell you. I've found the buyer, he has already made a prepayment. So that money is yours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task1_reward_01">
		<text>Alright, I'll come later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task1_reward_2">
		<text>Great, it's good to have a spare cash.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task2_stop_0">
        <text>Listen, Nimble, I changed my mind about looking for that revolver.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task2_stop_1">
        <text>Chickened out? Your circus, your monkeys. Refuse and I won't work with your again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task2_stop_21">
        <text>My pride won't suffer, I won't work anymore.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task2_stop_22">
        <text>Your know what... I think I changed my mind, I'll finish what I started. Maybe...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task2_done_0">
		<text>Here's the revolver! It wasn't easy to get it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task2_done_1">
		<text>I already got tired of waiting. We are working under the old scheme. There will be no money yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task2_done_02">
		<text>Well, then I'll keep it for myself, that's a great revolver.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task2_done_03">
		<text>Good luck to you then and farewell.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task2_done_2">
		<text>Take it. Money is good, but friendship is better.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task2_done_3">
		<text>Come visit me later then. We'll make it even. So, do you want more work?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task2_done_4">
		<text>Yeah, of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nimble_work_task2_done_04">
		<text>That's enough for me, I'll go get some rest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task2_reward_0">
		<text>So, can you already pay me for the "Magnum"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_reward_0">
		<text>So, can you already pay me for the "SP-100M"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_0">
		<text>I'm ready for another job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_1">
		<text>Okay. I'll be brief: my intel says that besides the suits scientists wear now, SSP-99 and SSP-99M, there's another version of that suit, designed before the Blowout. You should look for it at Lake Yantar. Ask Sakharov, he can surely help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_2">
		<text>I hope that I won't have to get to the radioactive spots to find the mythical suit.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_stop_0">
        <text>I want to stop working for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_stop_1">
        <text>Why's that? Remember: if you refuse, I'll stop trusting you, and consequently stop giving you jobs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_stop_21">
        <text>Yes, I understand that, but I have to refuse.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_stop_22">
        <text>I changed my mind, I'll continue searching for that suit.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_done_0">
		<text>Here's the suit. That was the hardest one to get! You'd be surprised if you was the things from the lake's underground!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_done_1">
		<text>And you'd be surprised by the reward... when I get the money for it. Deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_done_2">
		<text>Yeah, I know the drill.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task3_done_3">
		<text>Come later then, we'll get even.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task4_0">
		<text>What's the next task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_nimble_work_task4_1">
		<text>There's nothing at the moment: I need to sort something out now. I'll let you know once I've done. Oh, there was some key in the pocket: take it - might be useful.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Nimble: about Garik -->
	
	<string id="shustriy_about_garik_0">
		<text>Hey Nimble. Could you tell me something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shustriy_about_garik_1">
		<text>Why not? Ask away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shustriy_about_garik_2">
		<text>Do you know anything about Garik?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shustriy_about_garik_3">
		<text>To be honest, I don't. Can you imagine how many stalkers are there with such nickname? That's just a name, though, not a nickname.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shustriy_about_garik_4">
		<text>Yeah, you're right, but I have to find him anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shustriy_about_garik_5">
		<text>Good luck then.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Sid: tell me about-->
	
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_2">
        <text>Tell me about...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_20">
        <text>What do you want to know?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_21">
        <text>Anything you know about Strelok?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_211">
        <text>Nothing much, mostly rumors and speculation. They say he's one tough customer and has a few mates. Personally, I've never seen the guy, or maybe he wore a gas mask if I did - wouldn't really know. Seems like a VIP type of person with good contacts, so I doubt he's seen on a regular basis, or that people would even know who he is if they did catch a glimpse.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_22">
        <text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_221">
        <text>One day, years ago, back in 2006, it popped up here in Chernobyl. That's what everyone knows. Here's my free advice: Do your best to avoid mutants, stay out of anomalies, and don't come close to stalkers you don't know, especially those in dark uniforms - never a good sign.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_23">
        <text>I need weapons and equipment, where can I get these?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_231">
        <text>I can sell you those. I feel great potential in you... So, for you, as my friend and partner, I will make a concession and sell them cheaper. Be happy that Uncle Sid's got your back - people usually pay for that...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_24">
        <text>I need money. How can I earn it in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_241">
        <text>Fulfill my tasks, bring me artifacts, or do odd jobs for the local stalkers - factions as well, they've got resources thus bigger pays. I will pay you well though, not like some others hucksters and wannabes. There are other traders around like Barkeep in the deeper parts of the Zone, even secret ones with special liaisons. That is, if you even get there!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_25">
        <text>Who are those Freedom guys?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_251">
        <text>They are anarchists and thugs with a hint of style, for the most part. A few decents folks in there like anywhere, but try avoiding them if possible. That's my suggestion though. Bunch of depraved potheads and sodomites...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_26">
        <text>What do you know about Duty?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_261">
        <text>They hunt down mutants and Sin stalkers alike, and aren't really interested in newbies. If Freedom is chaos, they are order. They are militaristic in their ways and believe it is their "Duty" to protect the Big Land from the Zone's horrors. Which means that they harass artifact smugglers, which makes my job that much harder, and that gets me quite irate. The price you get from the Ecologists is nice, but black market deals are twice as lucrative! Lucky for us traders, Duty still take bribes and they've slacked off on those type of ventures. Heh-heh.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_27">
        <text>What the heck is this Death Truck thing, and who got me out of there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_271">
        <text>Death Trucks are kind of a mystery to everyone. They just drive themselves from the Zone's center all the way to Zone's borders. Almost nobody get out of these alive. By the way, the guy who saved you was a nice one: bodies with a tattoo like yours are usually sold as research material - the eggheads want these for some reason... what a bunch of maniacs!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_28">
        <text>Where's the old factory?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_281">
        <text>It's right here, a little jog from this den. I'll highlight it on your map.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_3">
        <text>Thanks, that'll be it for today.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_29">
        <text>I remember a strange word - "transmutation".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_tell_me_about_291">
        <text>Yeah. Advanced Stalkers use a specific device to change artefacts somehow, though I am not sure what benefit it can give... My old friend at the Bar knowns more about it. Ask him.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--Sid: about Garik-->
	
	<string id="sidor_about_garik_0">
		<text>Hey, fatty. I need info.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_about_garik_1">
		<text>You're risking to lose my loyalty, frickin' joker! Alright, relax. So you want to get it for free? Well, that depends on what you want to ask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_about_garik_2">
		<text>Do you know something about some stalker named Garik?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_about_garik_3">
		<text>Well, I can tell you something: I've heard that he's a experienced stalker, though he's young. Doesn't like to stand still; always looking for new paths and passages. I'd even worked with him a couple of times: if you need to get a rare artifact fast - he's the one to do the job. But I don't know how to contact him - he used to just come here occasionally. And what has actually happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_about_garik_4">
		<text>He's missing and I'd want to find him: it's a personal matter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_about_garik_5">
		<text>Huh.. that's not good. Then look for him in the center of the Zone; in some dangerous places.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sidor_about_garik_6">
		<text>Well, thanks for that.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!--Milbridge-->
	
    <string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_11">
        <text>This area is off limits, stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_12">
        <text>But I need to go there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_13">
        <text>Tough luck. Unless you REALLY need to go, then the price is 500.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_14">
        <text>Here you are.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_15">
        <text>Now listen up. We'll pretend for a moment it's nothing but mosquitoes and butterflies around here. What happens beyond this point is your own damn business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_21">
        <text>Alright, keep moving! Get your ass outta here, before we change our mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_24">
        <text>I don't have that kind of money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_25">
        <text>Then go back where you came from and get it. And don't you try and sneak past us, you hear? Trust me, it's not worth dying for.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--Escape-Rostok checkpoint-->
	
	<string id="esc_military_warning_dialog_0">
		<text>Stalker, we don't let anyone go through right now! If you don't want any trouble, turn and walk away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_military_warning_dialog_1">
		<text>Got it, I'm leaving.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- wolf first meeting -->
	
	<string id="escape_wolf_first_dialog_0">
        <text>Hi, can you tell me a bit about where I am?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_first_dialog_1">
        <text>Hey, you seem new around here, welcome. I am Wolf, leader of the stalkers in these parts. This is the exclusion zone`s cordon. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_first_dialog_2">
        <text>Hi, thanks Wolf. So this is the start of the 'zone' so to speak?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_first_dialog_3">
        <text>Yes, if this were a mountain, you would be at it`s base, and believe me, it`s a long climb to the top!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_first_dialog_4">
        <text>Thanks, I`ll keep that in mind. See you around perhaps.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_0">
        <text>Hey, do you have any other jobs for me?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_1">
        <text>I do have a little job for you if you are interested.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_find_key_2">
        <text>Give me the run down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_find_key_3">
        <text>I lost a key in the underground tunnel near Petruha's old camp. I was sleeping in one of the rooms close to the entrance and when I woke it was gone. Must have fallen out my pocket. It opens a wagon in Garbage near the entrance to the Bar. I stashed a whole lot of stuff in boxes in the wagon. Find the key and the stash is yours. Return the key to me and I will give you an added bonus. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_find_key_41">
        <text>Sure, I'm up for it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_42">
        <text>Sorry I have important things I need to do.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wolf_find_key_5">
        <text>So, you found the key?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_51">
        <text>Not yet, still looking.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_52">
        <text>Sure did.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_521">
        <text>Did you go get the stash?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_5211">
        <text>Not yet, I'll get it soon.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_5212">
        <text>Not yet, but take the key, I don't have time to go there.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_52121">
        <text>Ok, well, if you're sure. Oh and here is what I promised for returning the key.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_521211">
        <text>I am, see you later.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_5213">
        <text>Yes I did, thanks for that.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_52131">
        <text>No, thank you for finding my key, and here is the added bonus I mentioned.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="escape_wolf_find_key_521311">
        <text>Sweet thanks, see you later.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!-- Wolf: about Garik -->
	
	<string id="wolf_about_garik_0">
		<text>Hey Wolf. Can I ask you something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_about_garik_1">
		<text>Yeah, go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_about_garik_2">
		<text>Do you know anything about the stalker called Garik?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_about_garik_3">
		<text>Yeah, I think that's one of Barman's bodyguards... or not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_about_garik_4">
		<text>Yeah... no, that's not the one I need. Thanks anyway.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Fox: toolkits etc. -->
	
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_0">
		<text>So, you're the one who can repair everything?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_1">
		<text>Well, "everything"? Not really. I am an amateur when it comes to repairs. Been fixing things and building stuff since I was a kid. One day my grandpa showed me his shotgun, told me how to maintain it - I've been repairing guns since then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_2">
		<text>So can you repair any gun?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_3">
		<text>Actually, no. I don't even try to tamper with NATO guns. And, if you think of it, the Abakan is not as simple as it looks. But what I can repair are shotguns and pistols: I have become very proficient with those actually, can upgrade them so you wouldn't recognize them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_4">
		<text>And what about outfits?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_5">
		<text>It's not so simple either... You might have noticed that everybody around here wears simple jackets, and patching up a jacket is no big deal. But I don't have the materials for suits. My prices aren't high, the business isn't developing and I can't afford to stack up on materials. What we do, is if anyone wants me ro repair his suits, he orders materials, and I set them aside in the storage for him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_6">
		<text>Yeah, that sounds a bit complicated... Do you have any other issues here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_7">
		<text>I also lack tools to make upgrades. As you have surely noticed, the folks around here don't really want to upgrade their gear, so the demand isn't high. Again, it's all down to money - I won't charge a lot - that's my principle - so I am in the black. But I can't afford buying expensive tools, and folks ain't gonna credit me. I did offer Wolf to chip in, but he refused.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_8">
		<text>What if I help you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_9">
		<text>Then you'll get a huge discount! But keep in mind: the tools are very expensive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_10">
		<text>I need to think about it. I'll let you know if I make up my mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_0">
		<text>I am here for repairs...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_1">
		<text>Yep, what you got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_2a">
		<text>I want to order materials for suits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_3a">
		<text>Ok, I'll forward the order to Sidorovich as he is dealing with that. I don't think it'll take long, not more than a day. That's gonna be 7500.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_4aa">
		<text>Alright, here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_5aa">
		<text>Affirmative. When the materials come in, I'll be able to fix and upgrade your suits.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_4ab">
		<text>Wait, I don't have so much on me right now. Let's try another time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_5ab">
		<text>Well, it's you who wants something. In any case, I'll always help if I can.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_4ac">
		<text>I changed my mind, today is not the time for this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_2b">
		<text>I want to order materials for weapons.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_3b">
		<text>Okay, I'll send the order to Sidorovich. He is responsible for it. It does not take a lot of time, especially if he already has these materials. You owe me 5750.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_4ba">
		<text>Here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_5ba">
		<text>Affirmative. When the materials arrive, I'll be able to fix and upgrade your weapons.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_4bb">
		<text>Eh, it seems I don't have enough dough on me. I'll see you another time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_5bb">
		<text>Your circus, your monkeys. In any case, I'll always help if I can.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_4bc">
		<text>Wait, I changed my mind. That's little too expensive for me now, let's try later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_2c">
		<text>I would like to discuss the situation with your tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_3c">
		<text>The situation is simple, I need tools for fine work and for calibration. I couldn't buy them myself, I need an associate. Let's just say it's a risk that I am willing to go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_4c">
		<text>And you'll give me a discount if I'll help you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_5c">
		<text>Yes, a great discount. If you're going to use my services, it'll pay off anyway, right? We'll chip in 50-50.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_6ca">
		<text>Let's buy the tools for fine work then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_7ca">
		<text>Great. According to my calculations, the complete set will cost no less than 55 thousand, so your part would be 27500.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_7caa">
		<text>Here's 27500.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_8caa">
		<text>Here's 27500.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_9caa">
		<text>Good. Thanks for very much for all your help. Come back later when the tools arrive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_8cab">
		<text>Wait, 27500... I don't have that much, I'll tell you if I'll scrape enough together.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_9cab">
		<text>Understood. But thanks anyway.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_8cac">
		<text>Wait, I changed my mind. I can't afford such an expense now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_6cb">
		<text>I'm offering to buy the tools for calibration.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_7cb">
		<text>Yes, that would be nice... but very expensive. This set will cost at least 100 thousand rubles. Split in half, that'll be 50 grand each. What do you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_8cba">
		<text>What's there to think? A needed purchase. Here, my share, 50000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_8cbb">
		<text>So expensive. I don't have that much now. Maybe later, you can't get so much immediately.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_10cab">
		<text>Buying from Sidorovich is not always a good decision. Do you have any other ideas?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_11cab">
		<text>Hmm... actually, there is something: I heard that bandits had their own mechanic at the factory. They've been wiped out, right? You should go and look there for tools - maybe they'd left something in a hurry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_12cab">
		<text>Yeah, now we're talking! And there you were ready to throw 55 grand away.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_9cbb">
		<text>That's a shame, but I understand: that's a lot of money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_10cbb">
		<text>Perhaps I can get them somewhere else? Like, another way? Do you have any ideas?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_11cbb">
		<text>I've got none. But I'd be grateful, if you found the tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_0">
		<text>Hi, I've got something for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_1">
		<text>Yeah, what is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_2a">
		<text>Got you the advanced tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_2b">
		<text>Here are the calibration tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_2c">
		<text>Here's some data on military armor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_2d">
		<text>Here's a schematic for modern suits with a closed cycle breathing system.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_2e">
		<text>I've got you something special: everything you've wanted to know about the last generation military SKAT suits.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_2f">
		<text>Here's some Exosuit documentation. Useful stuff.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_3a">
		<text>Great! There are just calibration tools left.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_3b">
		<text>That's good! Now I need advanced tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_3ab">
		<text>Well, that's all. I've got the full set. Now I can start work for sure!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_3c">
		<text>Wow! Valuable data. Thanks a lot!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_3ca">
		<text>It's simple: there are just advanced tools left. I can't afford them myself, so I need a partner. That's a risk I'm willing to take, so to speak.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_3cb">
		<text>It's simple: there are just calibration tools left. I can't afford them myself, so I need a partner. That's a risk I'm willing to take, so to speak.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_4ca">
		<text>I already have the advanced tools - here you go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_4cb">
		<text>I already have the calibration tools - you can keep them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_9cac">
		<text>I see. Try to find tools at the factory, alright?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_2x">
		<text>I already have everything I needed. Thank you very much! And, as promised, now everything is half-price for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_6cab">
		<text>Well, screw these searches! I couldn't find advanced tools - let's just buy them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_6cac">
		<text>Special delivery: the advanced tools.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_6cbb">
		<text>I couldn't find advanced tools - let's just buy them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fox_repair_main_dialog_6cbc">
		<text>Just for you: the calibration tools.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_2g">
		<text>I have some info on G-36 and F-2000: schematics, descriptions and so on - all illustrated. Take a look if you want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_2h">
		<text>Here's some info on Abakan: you wanted to make it clearer, didn't you? Here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_2i">
		<text>Hey, I've got the whole schematics on the Gauss rifle! Don't ask where I got it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_info_dialog_3i">
		<text>The Gauss rifle? Are you serious? Thanks for the help, but I won't be able to figure it out.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Upgrades by the technician -->
	
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_dialog_0">
		<text>You've said that you can help me with repairs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes, of cource. I don't like to stay in debt. I will help with repairs but won't help with upgrades because my toolkits have been stolen. I have no idea who did it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_dialog_2">
		<text>But what if I'll help you with the toolkits?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_dialog_3">
		<text>That would be great. With the toolkits I can upgrade your stuff as long as you can pay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_intro_dialog_4">
		<text>Deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm here about the toolkits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_1">
		<text>What have you got?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_2a">
		<text>I've got a toolkit for rough work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_2b">
		<text>I've got a toolkit for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_2c">
		<text>I've got calibration tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_3a">
		<text>Great! It would be awesome if I'd get a toolkit for rough work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_3b">
		<text>Great! I'd like to have a toolkit for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_3c">
		<text>Great! But I really need some calibration tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_3ab">
		<text>Great! But I still need toolkits for rough and fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_3ac">
		<text>Great! But I still need toolkits for rough work and calibration tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_3bc">
		<text>Great! But I still need toolkits for fine work and calibration tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_3abc">
		<text>That's it! Now I have a complete tool set, so we can upgrade everything you want!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_repair_bring_dialog_20">
		<text>Nothing, you have such tools already.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- fanatic -->
	
	<string id="esc_fanatic_dialog_0">
        <text>Hey stalker, how goes it?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="esc_fanatic_dialog_1">
        <text>Hi, haven't seen you here before.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fanatic_dialog_2">
        <text>Yes, my name is Fanatic, I am taking over leadership from Wolf since he has moved back to the factory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_fanatic_dialog_3">
        <text>Ah I see, ok, good to meet you.</text>
    </string>
    
</string_table>
