<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- second meet with doc -->
<!-- actor recieved circuit boards -->
<!-- military warehouses task -->

 	<string id="swamp_doc_start_11">
		<text>Oh goodness, I thought your mind was gone there... I put you to bed and gave you a strong dose of my herbal remedy, hoping all would be well when you woke up... What happened? Did you dream at all?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_111">
		<text>I... I saw something really strange... I think what you gave me scrambled my brain for a moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_1111">
		<text>Strange dreams can occur with what I gave you. Don't let them get to your head. I've got some other types of herbs for you, but if you feel something's off, visit me later. By the way, about why you are here... for your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_11111">
		<text>What do you need me to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_111111">
		<text>I've been keeping in touch with our group, so I know where you can find them. I'll get in contact with Fang and try to find where Guide is hiding too. This could be a good chance to reconnect with Ghost as well. There's some nasty business relating to this special Crystal artifact - a rare kind, its shards are used to fix circuit boards, transistors... hardware like in a PDA. Such an artifact was looted off some Bandits I heard. Ghost was on the case, but he got wounded. Some Merc idiots are responsible for the whole thing. How about you head over to your old hideout and talk with Ghost so he can fill you in? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_1111111">
		<text>Fang is alive? I heard he was dead! And a Hideout? I don't even remember it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_11111111">
		<text>Yes, Fang is alive! The damn brainwashing! I guess you'll need time before you remember everything. We can discuss the matter later. No worries, I will mark Ghost's position for you on your map. Oh, and here are the circuit boards Sakharov needed, you can return them to him later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_111111111">
		<text>Thanks... Doc. I'll go see Ghost immediately and you can tell me more about "me" when I return.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- doc chitchat -->

	<string id="swamp_doc_start_12">
		<text>Strelok, welcome back. So, how are you feeling? Speak to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_121">
		<text>Tell me everything Doc. About Ghost, Fang, Guide and going to the center... I've heard all sorts of thing about Strelok – well, myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_1211">
		<text>That's a long story my friend. I'll leave out the minor details and get to the meat of it, so forgive me. Our group has been tight-knitted from the beginning, all the way back in 2009 - me, you, Ghost, Fang. We worked together on mundane tasks and kept each other company, though we had a common interest: the origins of the Zone. We wondered how this could all come to be. We spent years gathering bits and pieces together between odd jobs for money's sake, and what we concluded was shocking: the Zone was, at its deepest roots, a creation of humanity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_12111">
		<text>I figured as such from things I've read and seen. But I have to ask: how could the Zone have been created with man-made interference?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_121111">
		<text>Don't be so surprised. Reality seems like fiction at times. The underground labs, you know about them, right? Horrible things they did back then - when they were still active that is. The experiments ranged from application of mutagens, to altering the very fabric of reality! However, that was only a wild theory us four thought up from some torn papers we found in a lab somewhere. As it was, to find evidence to prove or disprove our assumption, we needed to go to the center of the Zone. Emissions come from there, right? Then there must be an answer waiting for us there. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_1211111">
		<text>But getting there would be a problem. Then... it was Guide that led us there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_12111111">
		<text>Indeed. Guide, the man-of-myths who can go anywhere in the Zone, came to us. He said that if we wanted, he'd bring us North. Not for a single second did you doubt that he could get you past the Scorcher unharmed, despite what Fang and Ghost thought. A few days later, in early '012, I saw you off when you, Fang and Ghost trekked to the center, with Guide leading the way. Hours later, I got a PDA message from you, saying you were safe and setting up camp in a Pripyat hotel room.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_121111111">
		<text>That's starting to jog my memory...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_1211111111">
		<text>You came back the next day with a bagful of artifacts, along with something else. You gave me a photo of something Guide had shown you, hidden behind the Nuclear Power Plant's backwoods.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_12111111111">
		<text>The Generators... I'm starting to remember now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_121111111111">
		<text>Yes, and our theory was indeed correct. This is the complex that keeps the Zone alive and ever-expanding - the crown jewel of the experiments gone amok. You managed to get there, but an encrypted door prevented you from entering the lab below. So, you figured out a plan: Fang, being the technical genius he is, would build a proper decoder for the door; you, Strelok, would go into the lab below when the time came and switch it off; and Ghost would gather the plastic explosives needed to blow the Generators sky high. You made another trip - alone with Guide this time - while Fang and Ghost did their own thing. With Guide's help, you discovered on this second trip that the Generators have built-in defenses that couldn't be deactivated unless you have specific override codes for the Generators' main controls. You returned and brought Fang and Ghost for a third trip, so that they could help you find the override codes. Fang would assemble the decoder on-site at your Pripyat hotel room.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_1211111111111">
		<text>It didn't quite go like that I guess.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_12111111111111">
		<text>The Monolith swarmed Pripyat when before there were none. They managed to split you from Guide and Ghost, right as a massive blowout occurred. Fang and Ghost managed to survive with Guide's help by running to the Pripyat Underground, but you... You were simply gone. We never heard from you again, Strelok. Even Guide couldn't find a lead on you or any evidence of the Monolith capturing you for indoctrination. No body. Nothing. We searched the Death Trucks that came after, but nothing. We gave up on this adventured and Guide vanished. The way North was sealed yet again along with its dark secrets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_121111111111111">
		<text>Well Doc, thanks for all this. Try to get in touch with everyone else, because if we get the opportunity we're going to shut the Generators down like we planned before. I'll be going now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_13">
		<text>Please speak with Ghost soon, it's important!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="swamp_doc_start_131">
		<text>OK, I'm on my way.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>