	<string id="sakharov_talk_text">
		<text>Sidorovich sent me to Yantar saying the local scientists could help me fix my PDA and restore the removed data - which might help me find Strelok faster... or at all. Since it doesn't look like Sid's getting something from it, I'm pretty sure he's currently laughing at the running man inside of his den...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_after_duty_talk_text">
		<text>Comrade General sent me to Yantar saying the local scientists could use some help. Since us, Duty, want to destroy the Zone and so do them - I surely will help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientist_package_text">
		<text>The head of the Yantar scientific laboratory, Professor Sakharov, offered me a job: I need to head to some town nearby, find the Mercs, and retrieve a package containing some research material. I don't know why, but I don't feel good about it... however, it's not the first and surely not the last time for that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientist_parts_text">
		<text>Sakharov said he could fix my PDA, but some spare parts are needed. I've been sent to the underground to find a copper wire, and I wonder where else he'd send me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_doc_text">
		<text>Well, I don't need to search for no Strelok now, however, it's better to get my PDA fixed that not. I need to meet Doc at the Great Swamps, talk to him, and borrow a printed circuit board while I'm there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientist_kruglov_meet_text">
		<text>So, while the Professor is fixing my PDA it's time to take a walk - talk to a local scientist Kruglov, to be specific.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_help_duty_text">
		<text>Petrenko's requesting backup: the Bar is under attack by Mercs. I need to help kill the killers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_scientist_text">
		<text>I came to Professor Sakharov to get a psi-helmet, but he only gave me a weaker version of it and said the normal one can be found at the Concrete Factory scientific lab. There's no other way to disable the Scorcher, hence I'll need to get to those parts anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sakharov_artefact_bring_text">
		<text>To finish fixing my PDA I need to bring the "Crystal" artifact - which is commonly used when fixing electronics - to Sakharov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bloodsucker_den_text">
		<text>A guy by the name of Oleg Rugov had run into some bloodsuckers at the Yantar underground and lost his rifle. I feel sorry for him, therefore I'll need to get down there and find the shooter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandits_territory_task_text">
		<text>Greben and his guys are having a bad time: the local bandits are constantly attacking them. I need to walk around the turf and play shooting range... with live targets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandits_stolen_text">
		<text>Bandits stole a few Greben's things: a guitar and some case. I've agreed to retrieve the possessions to the possessor - not a stingy one I hope...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="music_task_text">
		<text>Professor Kruglov asked me to find a composer's house at the Forest and bring some memorable thing - like a music sheet - from there. I'm note sure why'd he need it... but he pays.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="pribor_task_text">
		<text>In exchange for papers, Sakharov offered me to join an expedition: we'll need to perform some measurements and gather any electronics from the Yantar territory. It'll be a team of multiple people, hence I'm hoping I won't have to measure...</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="nimble_task_brain_text">
		<text>The brain's psi-rays block the way, but if I perform some measurements and configure the helm I'll be protected from the emission, able to get through, and finally obtain the outfit. According to Sakharov, I'll have to take the device in my hand to measure.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="docs_task_sid_text">
		<text>Petrenko sent me to get some docs at Yantar: like, "The eggheads are always looking for people to clear out the local hangars and basements". I need to talk to Sakharov, to start with.</text>
	</string>