<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<!-- Wounded stalker -->

	<string id="psycho_wounded_dialog0">
		<text>Stalker! Quick! My friend needs help urgently, he's there - in the mine! What are you waiting for? He won't last long, but I will manage somehow. Hurry up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psycho_wounded_dialog1">
		<text>Okay, don't worry, I'll find him.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Mercs gop-stop -->

	<string id="fore_killer_talk0">
		<text>Lookie here, and who's that? What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fore_killer_talk1">
		<text>Nothing, just looking around. Can I go now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fore_killer_talk2">
		<text>Bullshit! I know you came after the data we got to get - there's no other reason for you to be here. Now give me everything you've taken - and we'll let you go.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="fore_killer_talk3">
		<text>What are you talking about? I don't know anything about your data.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fore_killer_talk4">
		<text>Alright, I don't want no trouble; take it. That's all I found.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fore_killer_talk5">
		<text>Alright, now stand still here and don't move! When my guys let you, you can go. Got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fore_killer_talk6">
		<text>Yes, I got it.</text>
	</string>	
	
<!-- Paul Stew -->

	<string id="forest_looser_first_talk0">
		<text>Hey man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talka">
		<text>Why the hell are you sitting in this radioactive shit? Quick, let's get out of here! A friend of yours sent me to find you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talka1">
		<text>Oh, no wonder why I don't feel so good... Now let's get out of here: I know a safe place nearby. You can go, and I need a moment to stretch my legs; they hurt...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talka2">
		<text>Let's go, we'll talk later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkb">
		<text>So, why have we stopped?</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkb1">
		<text>Well, I don't have a gun, and there's a bunch of these fleshes... Kill them - and then we'll move on.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkb2">
		<text>Alright, just a moment. You wait here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkc">
		<text>What now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkc1">
		<text>We have arrived: I've got a stash with some gear here. Now let me tell you what happened to me. I'd got a job along with another guy: we had to sweep some zombies in the village. When we had got close to the place, the buddy pointed his gun at my back; forced me to give him all of my stuff - even the jacket... bastard! And then he ran away. I can't stand zombies, so I'd got into that house and was hiding there all that time.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkc11">
		<text>The Zone is not a walk in the park: there's danger around every corner, and humans can be the most dangerous.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkc12">
		<text>You think I don't know that? But there are some people... you can't realize they're rats until they've set you up. Alright, we don't have time for this now. I'll get to my stash and take some equipment from there - but you stay here, don't you take a sneak peek at my stuff. And if you try to, I won't get into the stash; I'll wait until you are gone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkc2">
		<text>Alright, I'm waiting here, just be quick.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkd">
		<text>Alright, take your gear and let's go already.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkd1">
		<text>You do realize that I won't get to my stash while you're here? Walk away please and wait outside, alrighty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talkd2">
		<text>Alright, got it, I'm going out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="forest_looser_first_talk00">
		<text>See you soon.</text>
	</string> 
	<string id="forest_looser_main_talka">
		<text>So, changed to fancier clothing? Where are we headed now?</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- Paul Stew saved -->
	
    <string id="forest_looser_main_talk_a">
         <text>Well, geared up? Where do we go now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="forest_looser_main_talk_a1">
         <text>Yeah, that's much better. Let's go to the Duty's outpost, these guys are solid - it's safe there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="forest_looser_main_talk_a2">
         <text>Let's go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="forest_looser_main_talk_b">
        <text>So, what can you tell me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="forest_looser_main_talk_b1">
        <text>I'm staying here: I can't move further - have to rest. And then I'll go to the Bar. Thanks a lot, man! Take this as a reward, I don't have anything else. I've had it in my stash for a rainy day. It's pretty rare, take care of it. I'll try and contact my friend myself, but if you see him, tell him I'm alright. I'll contact you later, after I get some info on the guy who set me up.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="forest_looser_main_talk_b2">
		<text>Alright then, bye.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="forest_looser_main_talk_b3">
         <text>Well, geared up? Where do we go?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="forest_looser_buy_talk_0">
        <text>So, what can you tell me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="forest_looser_buy_talk_1">
        <text>I'm staying here: I can't move further - have to rest.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="forest_looser_buy_talk_2">
        <text>I see. Well, bye.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>