	<string id="pda_npc_know_darkvalley_anom">
		<text>There is an anomaly field at Dark Valley. They say it creates an artefact everyday. Problem is, no one wants to go there. And before you ask - if you enter Dark Valley, you never come back. Some say it's because of the Monolith and Bandits. Some say it's because of the evil that dwells there. I'd be cautious if I were you.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="pda_npc_know_esc_military_cmdr">
		<text>You know that commander from the Cordon military outpost? The one who's yelling through the megaphone? Yep, that's the one. So, once when he was drunk, he spilt that special group of military stalkers up and dispatched them to different areas around the NPP. Their main goal is to secure the perimeter of the NPP. Nothing special you say? Well, if you see them, hide, run or fight... if you have the guts. Remember, they are well equipped and trained, they shoot on sight. So if you are insane enough to visit the ChNPP area, be careful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_npc_know_darkvalley_stash">
		<text>I've heard the bandits have a nice stash in their base at Dark Valley. Anyone crazy enough to go there and infiltrate their base can surely come out with a lot of goodies.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="pda_npc_know_garbage_zombies">
		<text>Be careful if venturing around the old car scrapyard on garbage. It is infested with the un-dead!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_npc_know_agro_artefacts">
		<text>Agroprom is a great place for hunting artefacts. Especially in the catacombs, but beware, evil lurks down there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_npc_know_bar_duty">
		<text>At the bar in Rostok you will find the HQ of the Duty clan. They are always looking for recruits. Go and see them if you're looking for a change.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_npc_know_bar_arena">
		<text>There is an arena in the bar area. A good place to make some money and earn respect. If you're crazy that is...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_npc_know_forg_trader">
		<text>There is a neutral trader on Forgotten who sells the basics for reasonable prices. There is also an informer there who knows a few more things than I do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_npc_know_forg_mercs">
		<text>There is a mercenary bar on Forgotten. These guys are trigger happy, but if you happen to know their password, they turn a blind eye, no questions asked. Perhaps one of the stalkers around there know the password.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_npc_know_forest_anom">
		<text>There is a very rare and special anomaly formation in the Forest. Some say it has a stash right in the heart of it that contains something unusual. It's also been said that somehow this formation shields you from blowouts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_npc_know_prip_trader">
		<text>It is rumored that there are some travelling secret traders in the zone that only keep high end equipment at very good prices for those in the know. Unfortunately I`m not..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_npc_know_mil_fixer">
		<text>There is an equipment fixer on Military Warehouses you can find inside of a local basement. It's pretty good to have such a fellow at those parts!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_npc_know_country_wc">
		<text>There's an interesting place at North Hills - a huge crater filled with anomalies. They say you can find some valuable stuff inside of a WC located on one of those "islands"...</text>
	</string>