<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<string_table>
	<!-- village leader -->
	<!-- give us location of good hemlet in countryside -->
	<!-- after visiting labx16 we disabled backup brain scorcher -->
	<!-- we get message to meet nomad at radar after labx16 -->
	
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_2">
        <text>Oh dear, you don't look well. Take this, it will help with the symptoms you're experiencing. Headaches, tinnitus , whispers - and in about 15% of cases, a strange craving for alcohol. P-Please don't drink in here though - forbidden by regulations. Stick to antirad and other proven medicines.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_21">
        <text>Uh, yeah... thanks for the meds. What's your name?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_211">
        <text>Deedee. Not my real name; opted for a codename to avoid complications. It's good that you're holding up, stalker and lucky that my search party found you in the North Hills, but I must ask, what brings you to such a craven place? I can count the number of non-Military visitors I get monthly on a single hand.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_2111">
        <text>Your colleague Sakharov sent me to fetch a fully functional psi-helmet. He must've mentioned me.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_21111">
        <text>Ah yes, I did get a notice about you. Marked One, right? Never thought you'd make it here with the Monolith and Scorcher around. That unadjusted psi-helmet served you well. Unfortunately, I don't have what you want... I sent some field workers to the North Hills to take some measurements for further fine-tuning, but they never returned, the search party were out looking for them. You never saw them by some chance did you?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_211111">
        <text>No, I never saw them. Never had a chance when that blowout came out of nowhere. Don't worry, I'll keep a lookout for your men while I search for the helmet. I'll be keeping the helmet if I find it as Sakharov promised. Just point me in the right direction.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_2111111">
        <text>Yes, of course. The last sign of them was at the old water dam, in the underground tunnels. I will mark the area for you. Here, take these, they will help a bit. But you must hurry, that helmet is far superior than that old prototype you have, and look after it because it's thrice as expensive!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_21111111">
        <text>OK thanks, I might bring it back when i no longer have any use for it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_3">
        <text>Did you find the psi-helmet yet?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_31">
        <text>Nope, still working on it.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_4">
        <text>Then I wish you good luck out there.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_talk_41">
        <text>See you later.</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_0">
        <text>Can you answer a few questions?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_2">
        <text>Sure, what would you like to ask?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_21">
        <text>Tell me about yourself.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_211">
        <text>Err, it isn't really anything special. If you know Professor Sakharov well enough, you'll know he was called upon to take lead of the Yantar science bunker by the Military. Although he did accept, not many wanted to follow along - even less to head another science bunker. After much thinking, and on the insistence of the good professor, I took up the responsibility for this lab. Stressful, but thrice as fruitful as sitting in a sterile lab away from ground zero.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_2111">
        <text>Yeah I know him. Oh well good for you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_22">
        <text>What are the real-world applications of studying psi-emissions?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_221">
        <text>Very broad, remarkable even. From what we've concluded, the psi-emissions from anomalies and mechanical devices such as X16 operate and affect the human mind with a combination of electromagnetic waves and infrasounds that can alter key neural processes. However that potential is wasted because of how erratic and volatile the psi-emissions are. As of now, either you die on the spot, lose your mind and become a willing pawn of the Monolith sect, or your brain activity regresses to primal levels, turning you into a gibbering zombie without self-awareness. If the potential of psi-emissions were to be harnessed and regulated, slight doses could help ease, even cure, complex mental pathologies with proper methodology. Interesting prospect.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_2211">
        <text>Ok, you lost me at hello.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_23">
        <text>What do you know about the Monolithians?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_231">
        <text>They are quite puzzling individuals. It seems that the few who don't succumb from complete neural regression caused by the Brain Scorcher instead develop an intense spiritual connection with a so-called Monolith. How this happens, and why it happens repeatedly over and over again, isn't something I comprehend. The chances that all those who don't suffer complete neural regression suddenly see the same evident truth... is completely improbable if only simple psi-emissions are involved. The fact is that such a consistent outcome shows that there might be some sort of intelligence behind this. I don't think I could find any evidence to support such a theory with the sensors we currently have.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="lost_scientist_ask_2311">
        <text>Right, yeah, thanks for the info.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!-- Garik's PDA Decode -->
	
	<string id="about_pda_talk0">
		<text>Professor, I've got a personal question for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_pda_talk1">
		<text>Yes, I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_pda_talk2">
		<text>I have this PDA with encrypted data which I want to retrieve. It's not like I stole it - I found it. I don't know who owned it, but the data might help me find him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_pda_talk3">
		<text>Alright, let me see... You're quite lucky today: it's the standard password, so the encryption is quite basic. Here's all the data from the PDA, but I'll keep the device itself. Isn't it Garik's PDA? I knew him personally. He disappeared a long while ago... which generally means one thing in the Zone. But let's hope for the best.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_pda_talk4">
		<text>Thanks a lot! If I find something about him, I'll let you know.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- The resisting artifact -->	
	
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_0">
		<text>Professor, I need your help! I wanted to get an artifact but it seems to resist.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_1">
		<text>I'll need more information to be able to help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_2">
		<text>It looks like a "Fireball", but lights everything up within 50 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_3">
		<text>To be honest, this is something I've never seen nor even heard about. You said it resisted, didn't you? How exactly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_4">
		<text>I didn't understand it myself, but apparently, it emits psi rays: I had got punched in the brain as I was approaching it - I don't even remember how I got away from it, like I was teleported.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_5">
		<text>Now that's what I call interesting! An artifact with its own defenses... Two possible things come to mind: it either creates wormholes around itself or uses psi attacks to "command" the victim to go away. That's an excellent example for a study on artifact evolution!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_6">
		<text>Do you have any ideas on how to get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_7">
		<text>Well, I don't know what to do about the wormhole part but we can calibrate the protection helmet - which, I believe, you already have - to defend from psi attacks: we'll need to tune the frequency for that. I suggest you do the measurements.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_8a">
		<text>Alright. How do I do that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_9a">
		<text>Here you go: the device is old but still reliable. Good luck to you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_8b">
		<text>I already have a measurement device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="country_major_jobart8_help_9b">
		<text>Great! I'm looking forward to getting the results.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>