	<string id="barman_meet_text">
		<text>Due to the Merc attack, Barkeep and the other big bosses had moved to Pripyat Outskirts and equipped a new bar. Petrenko told me they need help, so I should meet Barkeep there.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ivancov_meet_text">
		<text>Voronin told me it's been decided to shut the Brain Scorcher down and I am the best disabler they know. I need to visit the Duty shelter and talk to Ivancov: he should explain the details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="get_psy_bad_task_text">
		<text>Ivancov's cleared this up a bit: prior to shutting the Scorcher down I need to disable the reserve emitter located inside Lab X-16, but to get there I'll have to obtain a psi-helmet. I should head to Yantar and borrow one from Sakharov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="veronoin_after_radar_text">
		<text>After I'd shut down the Scorcher, Voronin contacted me: he offered to meet and have a chat. What's the deal this time?..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="get_to_lab_text">
		<text>Another day - another lab: these Outskirts earthquakes caused by a military installation located inside of the local underground facility. I need to get into X-7 and find a way to disable the damned thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_guide_text">
		<text>Comrade General handed me a note in which someone invites me to meet at the old church located nearby. This handwriting seems very familiar, and I'm sure that it's Guide. I need to meet the old pal as soon as possible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="keep_flash_text">
		<text>Comrade General wants me to sneak into the Freedom bar and get any intelligence info. I'm pretty sure that some flash drive or a CD will contain it.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="lukash_task_text">
		<text>The Freedom leader, Lukash, offered me a paid job: I need to find some machine for him. First off, I need to steal the key that opens the door, which the machine is locked behind; that key is held by the Construction Site Merc barman, but to freely walk into their base I'll have to get a password from the local kindly habitants. After all the preparation, I'll need to pinch the key at night, take it to the Radar, find the door it opens, grab the machine and finally bring it to Lukash.</text>
	</string>