<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

<!-- meet with outpost leader -->

	<string id="rad_outpost_hello_0">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_hello_1">
		<text>Halt, stalker! You are treading on holy ground. What is your business here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_hello_2">
		<text>I'm passing by for some personal business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_hello_3">
		<text>While we have no problem with such matters, an offering to the Monolith is needed. 5,000. No more, no less.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_hello_4">
		<text>Here. Can I go now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_hello_5">
		<text>Go on ahead and tread lightly. The Monolith watches you from the Zone's depths.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_hello_41">
		<text>Thanks, y'all take care now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_hello_6">
		<text>How about I just spend that money on giving you proper funerals?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_hello_7">
		<text>I'll come back later then.</text>
	</string>
		
<!-- meet hermit on radar -->
<!-- get hermit belongings task -->
		
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_0">
		<text>Who goes there? Please don't kill me, I'm not a mutant!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_1">
		<text>I know, you're the Nomad Doc talked about.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_2">
		<text>The Doctor? Ah, good man, good man... Why has he sent you here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_3">
		<text>X10. I need to go down there and shut down the Scorcher so the way to Pripyat and the NPP is open.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_4">
		<text>That cursed place! You had to bring that damn lab up, didn't you?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_5">
		<text>Is it that bad of a subject?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_6">
		<text>I once worked there! Just look at me! Does it look like a subject to bring up!?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_7">
		<text>...See this helmet on my head? It allows me to block the Scorcher's brainwashing and not turn into a zombie, or worse, a Monolith goon. You're the only one that has proper knowledge about how to access X10. I'm sure you want it shut down as much as the next guy. I can do it, but you have to help me out here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_8">
		<text>I... I guess you're right. I should value my honor. There is a way down there by the bunker in the hills, though it's been locked down. You need a passkey to enter. I had one of those back then, locked in a green safe in my house. You know that dump? It's the one behind me here. That's where the workers' houses were before everything went awry with the 1986 disaster. Scientists took them up when the labs were established, and then when the experiments were ended, they were buried under the trash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_9">
		<text>Then I just have to go there and get the passkey then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_10">
		<text>That won't work. There's an anomaly - a really strange one around the garbage hills. It's a sure-kill type that no artifact nor suit can protect you from. Except...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_11">
		<text>Except...?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_12">
		<text>My special belongings. If you carry them with you, you'll survive the anomaly. But they have been stolen from me by a monster! I had to give it up or it would've turned me insane. Get my belongings back and I will give you the safes combination so we may shut this place down!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_13">
		<text>I'll go hunt down whatever monster stole it from you old man.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- hermit chitchat -->
	
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_0">
		<text>Can I ask you some questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_1">
		<text>Go ahead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_11">
		<text>How do you know Doc?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_111">
		<text>I help him by gathering some radiated herbs from this place, due to the Monolith being a big hassle. In exchange, he gives me brews and supplements to outright remove any pain these mangled limbs cause me. I even managed to have tea with him at his swampy dwelling once. We are good friends.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_1111">
		<text>I see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_12">
		<text>Tell me more about yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_121">
		<text>I once worked on the experiments carried out here before the Zone emerged. Other than that, there is nothing of value in my being. No notable family, no wife, no life - science was the only thing that ever cared about me one bit. I immersed myself in it with pure abandon, and as you can see, I now suffer the consequences.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_1211">
		<text>Yes, I see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_13">
		<text>Do the Monolithians leave you alone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_131">
		<text>Yes, strangely enough. For the most part, they ignore me outright. Knowing what kind of treatment they reserve for others, I consider it a blessing. Those stalkers donning green uniforms don't dare breach the Monolith perimeter, so I consider this place a safe haven.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_questions_1311">
		<text>Good to hear.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- follow outpost leader to monolith commander -->
	
	<string id="rad_outpost_follower_1">
		<text>Halt, stalker! An elder has requested your presence. You need to come with me. No questions asked. There is no negotiations here, Marked One. The Patriarch has requested your presence - there are no "buts". Stay close to me and do not try to leave the area!</text>
	</string>
	<!--string id="rad_outpost_follower_2">
		<text>What are you talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_follower_3">
		<text></text>
	</string-->
	<string id="rad_outpost_follower_4">
		<text>...Fine. Take it easy I'm coming.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="rad_outpost_follower_5">
		<text>I don't think so, lunatics.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- help to monolith outpost -->
	
	<string id="rad_outpost_mutants_help_0">
		<text>They are all dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_mutants_help_1">
		<text>Few come all this way and remain ignorant of the Monolith's call. Even rarer is someone who puts up a better fight than the Monolith's servants. Just... who are you, stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_mutants_help_2">
		<text>Nobody special. I only seek to understand the morbid secrets of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_mutants_help_3">
		<text>Is that so? That must be why the Patriarch seeks you. He would ravish the opportunity of speaking with an interesting person such as you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_mutants_help_4">
		<text>No, I changed my mind, now you will die like those mutants!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_mutants_help_5">
		<text>Let's move...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outpost_mutants_help_6">
		<text>Take me to him then.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- meet monolith leader -->
<!-- chitchat -->

	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_0">
		<text>Marked One, or should I say Strelok? Either way, my sincerest greetings to your admirable person. You must have many questions, and I am willing to answer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_1">
		<text>Cut to the chase. Tell me why you brought me here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_2">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_21">
		<text>I am the Patriarch that carries out the theology and will of the Monolith. No one is higher than me next to the Monolith. Consider me the Pope and the Holy Monolith as God. That's how it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_3">
		<text>How do you know my real name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_31">
		<text>We know, because the Monolith knows all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_4">
		<text>Who are the Monolith exactly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_41">
		<text>It is what Tainted Ones refer to us as - 'stalkers of all affiliations'. In truth, the proper name for us is 'Children of the Monolith'. The Monolith is, by itself and only itself, the Zone's creator - an omnipotent, self-aware, wise Holy Artifact that crashed on Earth, sent to test the human race and its resolve by the depths of the cosmos. We are the Children who have acknowledged it and its powers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_5">
		<text>So what now? Why did you bring me here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_6">
		<text>You have great potential, child. Your quest for knowledge and truth have brought you here. It is fate. Join us to learn the Zone's truths. I beg you, Strelok! You want to understand, don't you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_7">
		<text>Well, yes, but...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_8">
		<text>Think about it. We have all the... Oh no, not now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_commander_9">
		<text>...Huh?</text>
	</string>	
	
<!-- get hermit belongings task done -->
<!-- get the passkey in safe near deadly anomalies -->
	
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_done_0">
		<text>I brought something special for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_done_1">
		<text>You found my belongings?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_done_2">
		<text>I ran into some Monolith goons on my way, but here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_done_3">
		<text>Thank you, thank you! I thought I'd never see this again! So, the code to the safe is 2-1-8. And yeah... I was only kidding: you don't need this old thing to help you navigate the anomaly... hehe. I just needed it back! Go to the safe in my old house now, then return - and I'll activate the Lab X-10 passkey by using my special magnet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_hermit_belonings_done_4">
		<text>Um... sure... OK, I'll be back as quick as I can.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- passkey task done -->
<!-- let's move to radar undeground -->
	
	<string id="rad_hermit_x10_documents_0">
		<text>I want to talk about the passkey.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="rad_hermit_x10_documents_1">
		<text>Do you have it yet?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="rad_hermit_x10_documents_2">
		<text>Here is the stuff from the safe, and the passkey. What now?</text>
	</string>		
	<string id="rad_hermit_x10_documents_3">
		<text>Let me tinker with it... There, I reactivated it. It should work now. My work is done, stalker. Go... avenge those who died. I think I can die in peace now, knowing that the errors of my colleagues and I will be corrected. Hopefully all this can be forgotten in due time...</text>
	</string>	

<!-- not implented -->	
<!-- chief chitchat -->
	
	<string id="rad_chief_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_chief_start_dialog_100">
		<text>Hey!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_deputy_dialog_1_0">
		<text>Where's the money for the mission?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_deputy_dialog_1_100">
		<text>Find my deputy and you'll get your money!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_deputy_dialog_1_1000">
		<text>OK, but don't lie to me this time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_10">
		<text>Leha the Jaw is my name! These rogues are my crew!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_100">
		<text>What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_20">
		<text>My boys and I are resting! When we're done we'll head to Pripyat!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_0">
		<text>What do you know about Pripyat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_10">
		<text>It's an old abandoned city from the communist era - from history! I reckon it's full of monsters and hordes of Monolith fighters now! No one who has gone there before ever returned!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_100">
		<text>You think it's dangerous?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_20">
		<text>No doubt about it - nobody has ever come back from there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_0">
		<text>You seen any soldiers around?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_10">
		<text>No, I ain't seen any soldiers for a long time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_100">
		<text>What about Military Stalkers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_20">
		<text>Rumour has it that they showed up right by the Red Forest, by the antennae! When they were turned off many people went to the Red Forest and further into Pripyat! We've been here for a day and we haven't seen anyone. Someone probably blocked the road here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_200">
		<text>You think the Military blocked the road to the Red Forest?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_30">
		<text>I don't think it was the Military, I haven't seen any for a long time, but Military Stalkers could have done it! They don't waste any time. They're the no-nonsense types, they work quickly and efficiently in their teams or solo... It's weird that they didn't block the road here earlier.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_300">
		<text>Why did they not go to Pripyat or block the road there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_40">
		<text>I don't know. Maybe they're afraid or they're getting ready for something. I can only guess.</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- not implented -->
<!-- find mates or their weapons from dead bodies task -->

	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_0">
		<text>Maybe you've got a mission for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_10">
		<text>Well, I have one but it's not easy... Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_100">
		<text>Saying it's not easy doesn't scare me at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_101">
		<text>Nah, no way. I don't have the time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_11">
		<text>I understand. I'm afraid myself... Would prefer to spend some money instead of sending my guys or going myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_20">
		<text>Good! The job is to find my scouts, Crowbar and Log! They went to Pripyat since I decided not to rush in and sent my best guys instead! Find them alive and bring them here. If they're dead, bring me their weapons! Do this for me and you'll get 2,000!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_200">
		<text>OK, deal!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_201">
		<text>Not enough. How about 4,000 and we have a deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_21">
		<text>That's all I can offer you for this job!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_30">
		<text>OK, I'll wait for you here!</text>
	</string>
	
<!-- not implented -->
<!-- find mates or their weapons from dead bodies task done -->

	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_0">
		<text>Mission accomplished!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_100">
		<text>Great, give me his PDA!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1000">
		<text>Here. Now the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1100">
		<text>You're trying to pull a fast one on me. He didn't have anything!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1200">
		<text>I'm gonna waste you right now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1300">
		<text>If I see you again you're a dead man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1400">
		<text>OK, I understand. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_200">
		<text>I can't give you anything, I don't have any money. You can keep his stuff if you want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_300">
		<text>I don't have any money! Go away!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_2_0">
		<text>I couldn't find him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_2_10">
		<text>Find him fast if you want your money!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_0">
		<text>I found your boys. They died, but here are their weapons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_100">
		<text>Thanks, they're dead then. I don't think there's any point going to Pripyat now! There's a problem though - I don't have your money. My deputy disappeared and he had all the money!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_1001">
		<text>OK, I'll find him. Tell me where to look for him. And don't even think about trying to cheat me out of my cash this time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_200">
		<text>I don't think he got very far. He's probably here or here, I'll mark it on the map for you! When you find him, bring him or his PDA back here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_2000">
		<text>OK, wait for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_2_0">
		<text>I couldn't find them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_2_10">
		<text>Find them and fast! I can't wait forever! Good luck.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
