<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="af-ameba-mica">
		<text>"Mica"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-slime">
		<text>"Slime"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-slug">
		<text>"Slug"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-blood">
		<text>"Stone Blood"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-cristall">
		<text>"Crystal"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-cristall-flower">
		<text>"Stone Flower"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-drops">
		<text>"Droplets"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-battery">
		<text>"Battery"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-dummy">
		<text>"Shell"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-glassbeads">
		<text>"Brown Beads"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-pellicle">
		<text>"Pellicle"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-spring">
		<text>"Spring"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-flash">
		<text>"Flash"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-moonlight">
		<text>"Moonlight"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-sparkler">
		<text>"Sparkler"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fireball">
		<text>"Fireball"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fuzz-bagel">
		<text>"Horn"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fuzz-cupcake">
		<text>"Sphere"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fuzz-kolobok">
		<text>"Kolobok"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-gold-fish">
		<text>"Goldfish"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-gravi">
		<text>"Gravi"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-medusa">
		<text>"Jellyfish"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-mincer-meat">
		<text>"Meat Chunk"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-night-star">
		<text>"Night Star"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-kristall">
		<text>"Crystal Thorn"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-sea-urchin">
		<text>"Urchin"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-thorn">
		<text>"Thorn"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-soul">
		<text>"Soul"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-vyvert">
		<text>"Wrenched"</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Ameba">
		<text>"Witches' Jelly"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bald">
		<text>"Springboard"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Buzz">
		<text>"Buzz"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Electra">
		<text>"Electra"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fuzz">
		<text>"Burning Fuzz"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fuzz_Bottom">
		<text>"Lying Fuzz"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Grabber">
		<text>"Grabber"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Gravi">
		<text>"Vortex"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Liana">
		<text>"Liana"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Lift">
		<text>"Elevator"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Meat">
		<text>"Whirligig"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Radioactive">
		<text>"Source of Radioactivity"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Storm">
		<text>"Storm"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Time_machine">
		<text>"Time Machine"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zharka">
		<text>"Burner"</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_ameba">
		<text>An anomaly of unknown nature. On contact inflicts injuries similar to the effects of a strong acid. Forms several types of artifacts: "Slime", "Slug", "Pellicle", "Soul", "Stone Bile", "Flesh Chunk", "Mica", and "Bubble".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_bald">
		<text>One of the first anomalies ever recorded - an unstable gravitational field inflicting shock damage to anyone within its radius. Remains active for a week on average. The amount of damage inflicted changes during its lifetime, ranging from minor bruises, through serious wounds, to instant death. Easy to spot in daylight. Accompanied by air fluctuation above the anomaly, dancing leaves and distinctive crimson-colored stains on the ground. Picked up by all types of detectors, the Springboard can also be revealed by throwing objects into it. Forms the following types of artifacts: "Jellyfish", "Crystal Flower", "Stone Flower", "Shell", "Spring", "Night Star", and "Hedgehog".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_electra">
		<text>An anomalous formation, roughly 10 meters in diameter, accumulating large quantities of static electricity. When triggered, the anomaly bursts out in dozens of miniature lightnings, causing electric shock nearly always lethal to all living beings. Recognizable by the bluish fog hovering above it in daylight. At nighttime, the Electro can be revealed using any type of detector or by throwing metal objects into the anomaly. Forms a lot of artifact types: "Sparkler", "Accumulator", "Twinkle", "Flash", "Jewel", "Lightning", "Discharge", "Snowflake", and "Moonlight".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_fuzz">
		<text>One of the Zone's examples of mutated vegetation. Reacts to rapidly approaching living beings by discharging a cloud of projectiles severely injuring uncovered or lightly protected skin upon contact. Does not react to slowly moving targets. Forms the following types of artifacts (possibly its seeds): "Horn", "Kolobok", "Ivory", "Sphere", "Blue Beads", "Firefly", "Chestnut", and "Spine".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_gravi">
		<text>An anomaly of presumably gravitational nature. When triggered, the tremendous power of the Vortex drags everything within the radius of 10-15 meters towards center. Victims drawn into the core have no chance of survival: their bodies are quickly constricted into a tight lump, only to be blown up in a powerful discharge of energy a moment later. The anomaly remains stationary throughout its lifetime (a week on average). Easily recognizable in daylight by the air fluctuation above, dancing leaves, fragments of dismembered corpses lying around and a distinctive dark stain in the center. Highly dangerous at night since it can be revealed only by means of a detector or by throwing metal objects into it. Forms seven types of artifacts: "Wrenched", "Gravi", "Brown Beads", "Knot", "Chert", "Soother", and "Goldfish".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_lift">
		<text>A harmless anomaly, temporarily negating normal gravity. Manifests itself as an area - usually several meters in diameter - where Earth's gravitational pull is greatly reduced. No data regarding artifacts formed by the anomaly is available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_meat">
		<text>The anomaly snatches its victims up in the air and spins them at a breakneck speed. The exact nature of the Whirligig remains unknown. The anomaly can be recognized by a light whirlwind of dust above and by body fragments scattered in the vicinity. Victims caught on its outer rim - far enough from the maximum effect zone at the center - can escape the Whirligig with relatively minor injuries. Forms these types of artifacts: "Stone Blood", "Meat Chunk", "Cuttlefish", "Heart", "Gold Beads", "Pupil", and "Giblets".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_radioactive">
		<text>An area of increased radiation - over 50 mR/h. Staying in a radiation zone for longer periods of time without proper protection is strongly discouraged.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_time">
		<text>A true miracle of an anomaly: an area several meters in diameter where the time flow is significantly slower than usual. Appears to have no negative effect on human health. However, the Time Machine can be very difficult to get out of. Interestingly, removing Mama's Beads - an artifact usually found in the center of the anomaly - causes the "Time Machine" to disappear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_zharka">
		<text>While inactive, the anomaly manifests itself as a barely visible cloud of hot air. When triggered by an object or a living being it instantly heats up to lethal temperatures approaching 1500K. At nighttime, it can be revealed by powerful detectors or by throwing metal objects into the trigger area. Forms the following types of artifacts: "Droplets", "Quartz", "Red Beads", "Eye", "Mercuryball", "Flame", "Fireball", and "Crystal".</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-medusa">
		<text>Formed in the "Springboard" anomaly. The artifact creates a weak protective field which can slowly absorb radioactive particles, thus deriving radiation from the owner's organism. The artifact is widespread and not very valuable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall-flower">
		<text>Born in the "Springboard" anomaly. The artifact is found in many areas of the Zone. The bits of metallic compounds create a beautiful light play. It is very calming to study this artifact at night by the fire as it creates a little bit radioactive field protecting the owner from influence of the psi-emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-night-star">
		<text>This wonderful artifact is formed by the "Springboard" anomaly. The use of the artifact demands the neutralization of a small radiation, however, the owner's tissues become way stronger instead. Expensive and rare, this artifact is extremely interesting for scientific expeditions and other research activity in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-dummy">
		<text>Born in the "Springboard" anomaly. When wearing this artifact, about one-fourth of all the radioactive particles around doesn't hit the owner; in other words, the rad. protection increases. It's an expensive and rare thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-spring">
		<text>Formed in the "Springboard" anomaly. According to the opinion of some researchers-theorists, this artifact is a hybrid between "Batteries" and "Shells". It's a known fact that the artifact is radioactive and reduces the damage from any impact the owner suffered.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-vyvert">
		<text>Located in the "Vortex" anomaly. When it touches the body it disseminates a little bit radioactive field protecting from scratches or wounds made by weapons. This artifact isn't hard to find, that's why they don't pay much for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gravi">
		<text>Can be spotted in anomalies such as "Vortex". While wearing it a certain amount of radiation is stored in the body while the rest of it is scattered in the radial direction away from the body which slows down small metal objects; in other words, it increases the owner's bullet resistance. The price is standard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gold-fish">
		<text>Formed in the "Vortex" anomaly. Activated by the body's heat and emits quite some radiation, partially protecting the owner from gunshot wounds. The artifact can be sold to scientists for good profit.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-glassbeads">
		<text>Wonderful artifact born in the "Vortex" anomaly. Heavily speeding up the owner's digestion and polluting their body with radiation, it helps carry more weight. Scientists can't figure out how to create such an artifact in laboratory conditions.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-drops">
		<text>Formed in the "Burner" anomaly at high temperatures. From the exterior looks like a tear-like shade compound with a glossy surface, covered in cracks. It helps the owner survive more bullet hits than usual, polluting their body with radiation instead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fireball">
		<text>Crystallizes in the "Burner" anomaly. It helps the owner stay near the parental anomaly longer as it emits some field maintaining constant temperature. It's a known fact that the artifact emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall">
		<text>Is created when heavy metals fall into the "Burner" anomaly. This artifact recovers the owner's neural system wonderfully, emitting radiation instead. It's highly valued by stalkers and pretty hard to find.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-blood">
		<text>This artifact is found in the "Whirligig" anomaly. It is quite an ugly reddish object made out of pressed together and curiously bent polymerized remnants of plants, soil, and bones. This artefact is used to reduce damage caused by blast wave; however, the owner also needs to neutralize the radiation emitted by it, though it's not really a big issue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-mincer-meat">
		<text>Formed in the "Whirligig" anomaly. The artifact consists of body parts caught by the parental anomaly, and protects the owner from explosive impact; on the other hand, it pollutes their organism with radiation. The artifact doesn't show up very often, but it's hard to call it rare.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-sparkler">
		<text>Found near the "Electro" anomaly. Quite widespread and inexpensive artifact which protects the owner from electrical discharge, emitting radiation instead. Valued among the researchers in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-flash">
		<text>"Electro" sometimes births this artifact. Stalkers readily use it because of its ability to protect the owner from electric current of high amperage. Its price and a good external look make this artifact appealing to collectors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-moonlight">
		<text>Degenerate case of the activity of the "Electro" anomaly. It seems that such a wonderful round form is created when the anomaly is subjected to thermal influences. Expensive artifact valued for the ability to neutralize quite a high psi-emission, thus protecting the owner from its influence.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slug">
		<text>Formed by the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. The radioactive qualities of this artifact are compensated by the fact that it increases the owner's resistance to any mental attacks. It also is paid well for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slime">
		<text>It is certain this artifact is created by the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. When it's carried on the belt, the owner's organism is being polluted by radiation, however, it becomes less vulnerable to rupture. The artifact is widespread and pretty cheap.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-mica">
		<text>The "Witches' Jelly" anomaly is able to create such an artifact at the rarest, most extreme collection of physical conditions. The result is a semi-transparent, hard object protecting the owner from chemical burn, polluting their body with radiation instead. The artifact is quite rare and expensive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-soul">
		<text>Rarely found near the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. Only a very few manage to find this artifact, and few have even seen it, therefore its qualities are only known from unproven rumors. It has a nice shape, however, not a nice price despite its rarity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-pellicle">
		<text>Born in the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. This artifact is so rare that many researchers can't even imagine that such a substance can exist in a natural setting. The artifact creates a constant temperature field which lets the owner stay near the "Burner" anomaly longer, polluting their body with radiation at the same time.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-thorn">
		<text>The result of the interaction between the anomalies "Rusty Hair" or "Ameba" and a careless stalker's body. The artifact pokes the body of its owner, but also helps protect their body from alpha and beta-particles. Quite widespread and cheap.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-kristall">
		<text>Crystallizes in the "Rusty Hair". The artifact emits radiation but makes the owner's skin withstand more bites or cuts. Not widespread and quite effective, which is the cause for the stable price in the market.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-sea-urchin">
		<text>The anomalies "Rusty Hair" and "Ameba" very rarely gives rise to this artifact. It's valued for the ability to block quite massive radioactive particles and the lack of any disadvantages. In his fundamental work titled "Ionization and polarization of the components of rare artifacts", Sakharov noted that the content of this formation has a critical stability, and it's not realistic to create such an artifact in lab conditions in at least ten next years.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-battery">
		<text>Born in the "Witches' Jelly" and "Ameba" anomalies. The origin of this object is shrouded in scientific mystery. It's a known fact that the artifact can somehow reduce the damage from impacts, polluting the owner's body with radiation instead.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fuzz-bagel">
		<text>Born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. The artifact is widespread, its effects are poorly studied, but it's radioactive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fuzz-cupcake">
		<text>Rarely born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. The artifact was named so as its shape resembles a sphere, and respected for the ability to highly increase the owner's blast resistance. There also are rumors claiming that these artifacts are used by minesweepers outside the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fuzz-kolobok">
		<text>Only rarely born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. When you hold this mystery of the Zone in your hands, you feel how your organism gets better. The disadvantage of such a health regeneration is sped up digestion of the owner; in other words, they get hungry faster than usual.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Escape">
		<text>Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Garbage">
		<text>Garbage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Agroprom">
		<text>Agroprom Research Inst.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Darkdolina">
		<text>Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bar">
		<text>Great Metal Factory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Yantar">
		<text>Lake Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Military-loc">
		<text>Military Warehouses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Deadcity">
		<text>Dead City</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Swamps">
		<text>Swamps</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Radar">
		<text>Radar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Pripiat">
		<text>Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Stancia">
		<text>V.I. Lenin ChNPP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Generators">
		<text>Generators</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Rostok">
		<text>Rostok Factory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Darkscape">
		<text>Darkscape</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Concrete Factory">
		<text>Concrete Factory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Pripyat Outskirts">
		<text>Pripyat Outskirts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="North Hills">
		<text>North Hills</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Construction Site">
		<text>Construction Site</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Forest">
		<text>Forest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Old Road">
		<text>Old Road</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_deadcity">
		<text>A small town previously inhabited by the workers of the NPP and nearby facilities. There's a Lenin monument in the central part of the town; the rest territory is filled with houses - concrete and wooden. There are some villages and a cemetery in the vicinity. According to some rumors, the town's territory is occupied by Mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_swamps">
		<text>Almost endless swamps divided into two parts by a driveway. There are a few villages around: some are occupied by bandits, some - by someone worse. Stalkers rarely visit those parts as the territory is often patrolled by military helicopters. It's a good question why is the military interested in these swamplands, however, some say they are ordered to guard the long pipeline of an unknown purpose located at the South and going deep into the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_generators">
		<text>Strange looking machines located to the North of ChNPP. The Generators are not known about by the most stalkers, though they're clearly seen on the satellite map. It's worth mentioning that there are some white spherical structures around the Zone, which veteran stalkers associate with the mysterious Northern machines.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_rostok">
		<text>An old factory located in the Zone's South. What kind of things it'd been manufacturing is unknown, but whatever it was it's already stolen or illegally exported. There are a few houses around; apparently the factory workers lived there. Although it's fairly close to Cordon, a novice's first stay, stalkers don't like those parts due to frequent mutant attacks. The North-Western part of the territory is controlled by the military as it's close to the borders of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_darkscape">
		<text>A very rocky territory located very close to the Zone's borders. There's a road crossing the whole Darkscape, and a railroad bridge above it. There also is a bus stop located to the perimeter and some kind of harbor with a few vessels - that's where the heaviest radioactive trace was recorded on the first post-accident day. Just like everywhere, a couple villages have remained. Stalkers are not generally met in those parts as it's easier to get from Dark Valley to Cordon through Garbage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_lost_factory">
		<text>An extremely obscure territory sometimes claimed to be located outside the Zone - and old concrete factory abandoned shortly before the events of 1986. The notable places are the mobile scientists' bunker and the factory itself, along with some underground communications of unknown purpose.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_outskirts">
		<text>A Pripyat suburb adjoining to its South. An old concrete factory is located there; there also is a settlement down the road appurtenant to the energetic workers' town. An extremely small-sized military base is located close to the district center, and it's worth mentioning that it'd been working until the current century. There are usually some bandits in the settlement, and the Freedom base at the factory, thus it's very hard to meet any fair stalkers at the Outskirts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_country">
		<text>The main trait of North Hills is a long motorway taking its start far beyond the Zone. It was built along with the NPP, however, it's never been used frequently. One of the most mysterious Zone places is also located there - a huge crater which had appeared after the second disaster at a small lake that, according to the official information, helped the radioactive water from the NPP's cooling pond circulate. Another lake located to the North was dug after the accident - and the water canal was demolished. Despite the place's abandonment, a group of field investigators can be met at North Hills once a week.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_forgotten">
		<text>A huge industrial area which was abandoned back in the summer of 1986. The place is truly forgotten: stalkers rarely visit those parts, but bandits are usually found there. The notable places are the site itself, a lake polluted with wastes and a garbage consisting of radioactive junk. It's not recommended to visit the North-Western part of the Construction Site: a bar occupied by the Mercs is located there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_forest">
		<text>A woodland with a motorway passing through it. There are some villages, but an industrial complex with mines is the most notable place of those parts. A huge anomaly is located in the Forest's center, and there are lots of rumors spread about it. The Great Metal Factory side is guarded by the Duty soldiers; stalkers rarely visit the Forest, however, bandits are frequent guests there as they won't stop coming from Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_oldroad">
		<text>Quite a long driveway connecting the Forest and Radar; who, when, and why used it is a good question. The vicinities are pretty empty, yet there are a few notable landmarks: an old swimming pool, a pump station, a rather big village... however, the most interesting places are two big anomalies resembling stranded trees. The Old Road habitants are bandits - some even say those don't even mind stalkers around - and a Freedom squad sent from Pripyat Outskirts.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_agroprom">
		<text>A strange, heavily contaminated area. There are only two landmarks worth mentioning: the factory and the Institute itself... or actually, three - also the catacombs widely known by the Zone diggers. Stalkers have been dreaming about making a base of both facilities for a long time, but the Institute is occupied by the military, and the factory is being purged once a week by spetsnaz; all of this leads to some thoughts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_bar">
		<text>The Duty faction cleaned an old pre-perestroika industrial area once to make a base, and had invited stalkers to hold the empty buildings. After some time the place became the most populated territory of the Zone: the 100 Rads bar - a meeting point for stalkers from all over the Zone - was the reason. The bar is run by the local trader, so if you're interested in selling or buying wares apart from the local gossip - that's the place to go to. However, the Western part of the factory can't brag with the same serenity: it's populated by bandits coming from the Construction Site, Duty isn't concerned about it, but the robbed stalkers sometimes lose everything but their sweater.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_darkdolina">
		<text>Stalkers venturing into the Dark Valley are likely to find valuable artifacts, instant death, or both. The place is not really populated by stalkers due to the fact there are the bandit base in the North. Experienced stalkers use the Valley as a fast way to the Forest or Darkscape.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_escape">
		<text>Think of it as the Zone's antechamber - it's a good place for rookies to get their head around. You'll find a trader in the vaults at the back of the village, next to the army outpost; don't miss the chance to talk to him. You'd be advised to steer clear of the outpost itself; however, some say the soldiers can even let you through if the commanders are not around. Attacking the soldiers is not recommended, unless they pose a direct threat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_garbage">
		<text>A vast machinery graveyard: right after the first accident whole heaps of radioactive waste were dumped there. Mostly ruins of old buildings infested with mutants or some other Zone inhabitants. Much like the outskirts of the Zone, the place swarms with rookie stalkers, with an occasional bandit loitering around, always on the lookout for freebies. Some artifacts to be found here, but most of them are just not worth the effort. Going North, you will get to the Great Metal Factory; East lays the entrance to Dark Valley, with the road to the Agroprom Research Institute to the West.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_military-loc">
		<text>A deserted army base next to a dilapidated hamlet and a small marsh. The village is an eerie place literally swarming with mutants - the bloodsuckers alone are legion. Stalkers do their best to keep away from it, even if it means going extra kilometers around it. The base is occupied by either military or some other serious people. The road connecting the base to the Zone is guarded by the Brain Scorcher, which blocks the way to Pripyat and the Chernobyl NPP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_pripiat">
		<text>This used to be a town built for engineers working at the Chernobyl NPP. Quite a big place once, it is a ghost town now with mutants and zombies as the only residents. There seems to be no way to get in there: the Brain Scorcher is blocking the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_radar">
		<text>A dreadful place. Easy to vanish without a trace there, no matter how lucky you have been in life so far. Whoever gets close to the Brain Scorcher immediately goes insane, turns into a zombie and starts stalking the Zone restlessly. A human shell is all that's left. No-one has ever returned with a sound mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_stancia">
		<text>The site of the world-famous nuclear power plant. This is the heart of the Zone. If you believe the legends, this is also the site of the Monolith - a mysterious thing capable of granting any wish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_yantar">
		<text>The legendary lake in the sector of the same name dried up a long ago, leaving a shallow swamp in its place. The lake territory is morbid and sodden with death. Great dangers await any adventurous soul foolish enough to get near it. Anyone who dares to go too far - or deep - well, you can guess. If you walk around the lake, you'll end up at the scientists' camp, where the eggheads brought there by choppers are doing some research. If you're lucky to grant a permission to enter, you can have a chat with them; they buy artifacts and could even send you on a mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_escape_military_case">
		<text>Detailed map of the army outpost from Sidorovich, which he drew according to his contact's words. It won't be difficult to get there for an experienced stalker.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Story-2006">
		<text>2008, April 12, 14:33</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-2008">
		<text>Year 2010</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-2010">
		<text>Year 2011</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-raid">
		<text>Army raid into the Zone. Year 2011</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2006">
		<text>The contaminated zone was aglow with the brightest of lights, almost unbearable to the human eye. You could virtually see the clouds in the sky turning into vapor. After a moment of dead silence there came rattling thunder, and then the earth shook. People fell to the ground, screwing up their eyes and covering their ears. Those who could still stand ran for their lives. It looked as though all the nuclear fuel buried under the Sarcophagus had suddenly exploded. The next day the army cordoned off the new Zone. The satellites helped to establish that the epicenter of the explosion was not actually in the vicinity of the NPP reactors, but about half a kilometer away. It is believed that the personnel of the station died at once, though many people still remained within the cordoned area. The rescue operation soon proved a pointless endeavor, as all the people and machinery sent deep into the area would die or malfunction immediately. A little while after the disaster, the Zone diameter hopped out by a few more kilometers. Most of the government troops guarding the border line and the research teams stationed there perished instantly. Panic stricken, people took to flight. The residents of nearby towns and villages were hastily evacuated. An enormous danger is looming over the world and we can only guess what its full impact may be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2008">
		<text>Two years have passed since the disaster in the contaminated zone around Chernobyl NPP. Skyrocketing deathtoll, countless people missing, dead cattle, decaying buildings, maimed forests... Until this day scientists have no explanation as to what exactly happened in Chernobyl. Meanwhile, some inconceivable anomalies were discovered in the area, and the Zone keeps expanding. Rare expeditions encounter mutated species of animals exhibiting unbelievable abilities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2010">
		<text>Following in the tracks of those foolhardy loners who call themselves the stalkers, research expeditions are once again embarking on an in-depth study of the Zone. However, the perimeter guarded by the army has other, dangerous inhabitants now - from common poachers to the worst bandit scum. Most of the stalkers roam the Zone in search of anomalies and the so-called artifacts for which they gain quite a profit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-raid">
		<text>The army, including special forces headed by paramilitary stalker detachments, launched a massive raid deep into the Zone. Their objective was to break through to the Chernobyl NPP and wipe out the cause of anomalous fields or at least obtain first-hand information on the current state of affairs. This endeavor, involving over a thousand people and heavy machinery, was a complete failure. Isolated groups of survivors were forced to settle within the Zone with slender hopes of rescue.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Anomalies">
		<text>Anomalies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Artifacts">
		<text>Artifacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Locations">
		<text>Locations</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Military-post">
		<text>Sidorovich's Map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zone">
		<text>The Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zone-story">
		<text>History of the Zone</text>
	</string>
</string_table>