<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="pda_actor">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_actor_tutorial">
		<text>Welcome to S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Lost Alpha DC! These hints will guide you through the basic controls. In case you forget something, all the information you've received will be stored in your PDA's encyclopedia. Thanks for using our Personal Digital Advisor!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="combat">
		<text>Combat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="combat_tutorial">
		<text>During combat be careful: enemies prefer to sneak or shoot you from behind if possible. To increase your chances in open fight, try aiming your weapon ($$ACTION_wpn_zoom$$) or crouch ($$ACTION_crouch$$). You can also peer out from cover by pressing ($$ACTION_llookout$$) or ($$ACTION_rlookout$$).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo">
		<text>Ammo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo_tutorial">
		<text>If you want to stay alive - add some ammo boxes to your belt. It's simple: just go to your inventory and click on a box of ammo for your weapon twice (or drag and drop it onto the belt).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binoc_tutorial">
		<text>To use the binoculars, select them using ($$ACTION_wpn_5$$) and press ($$ACTION_wpn_fire$$) to zoom in. As the story progresses, you'll be able to obtain other kinds of binoculars - each one having its own perks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scavenge">
		<text>Scavenge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scavenge_tutorial">
		<text>Don't forget to explore the world around you, stalker! You can find many valuable items if you search the buildings around you... though it can be a dangerous adventure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crouch">
		<text>Crouching</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crouch_down_tutorial">
		<text>To crouch lower press ($$ACTION_crouch$$) and ($$ACTION_accel$$) at the same time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crouch_tutorial">
		<text>To crouch press ($$ACTION_crouch$$). To crouch even lower, press ($$ACTION_crouch$$) and ($$ACTION_accel$$) at the same time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hide_weapon">
		<text>Weapon select</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hide_weapon_tutorial">
		<text>Some stalkers won't want to talk if you stick your weapon in their face. To hide your weapon you can simply select the bolt ($$ACTION_wpn_6$$) or press the current weapon's key once more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bolt">
		<text>Bolt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bolt_tutorial">
		<text>Anomalies are quite dangerous for stalkers without a protective outfit, which means you need to move carefully! Select the bolt by pressing ($$ACTION_wpn_6$$) and throw it ($$ACTION_wpn_fire$$) in front of you to find out the anomaly's presence or position.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jump">
		<text>Jumping</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jump_tutorial">
		<text>When you're stuck in anomalies, you can try to jump out of them - though the chances are pretty small; it's also possible to climb on top of small to medium size barriers. To jump press ($$ACTION_jump$$).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="move_tutorial">
		<text>Movement types</text>
	</string>
	<string id="overload">
		<text>Overloading</text>
	</string>
	<string id="overload_tutorial">
		<text>You're not a mule, so there's a limit to how much you can carry. When the weight of your gear exceeds your limits, you will start losing energy very quickly. Nevertheless, raising the "Endurance" skill can help you carry more weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radiation">
		<text>Radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radiation_tutorial">
		<text>When you wear a radioactive artifact or enter an area with a high level of background radiation, the health starts to decrease, and signs of radiation poisoning appear. Effects of radiation can be countered by using antiradiation drugs or wearing a proper artifact; you can also use the Radioprotectant drug to temporarily increase radiation protection - but you'll need to do so before entering a danger zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="relation">
		<text>Attitude</text>
	</string>
	<string id="relation_tutorial">
		<text>By helping other characters, you improve their attitude towards you as well as your reputation. Better attitude and higher reputation help you when interacting with the people you meet: for example, traders will sell you things cheaper if you're in their good books. On the other hand, if you open fire at someone, their attitude towards you will quickly turn negative and they will attack you back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sprint">
		<text>Speeding-up</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sprint_tutorial">
		<text>Sometimes your life will depend on your speed. To run press ($$ACTION_sprint_toggle$$). When sprinting you also jump further but tire more quickly and are unable to shoot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial">
		<text>Training</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weakness">
		<text>Fatigue</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weakness_tutorial">
		<text>Running for a prolonged period of time causes fatigue. When you become exhausted, you aren't able to run or even move at walking pace. The more you're carrying, the faster you tire. Nevertheless, standing still for a few seconds or drinking an energy drink is enough to recuperate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weapon">
		<text>State of the weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weapon_tutorial">
		<text>All weapons have a durability parameter: the lower it is, the more often weapon jams. To unjam, reload the weapon by pressing ($$ACTION_wpn_reload$$). The weapon's durability decreases with use, and it may become completely useless if struck by bullets. To fix a broken gun you can use a repair kit (if you have other weapons ready to be disassembled) or visit a technician.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wound">
		<text>Open wounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wound_tutorial">
		<text>When you're hit, you may start to bleed. The more serious the bleeding is (the severity is indicated by the icon near the health bar), the more health you lose per unit time. Bleeding will eventually stop, but even serious hemorrhages can be stopped by using bandages or proper artifacts; the Vinca drug can also help speed up the blood coagulability - if used in advance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda">
		<text>Diary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_diary_tutorial">
		<text>You can find some observations, personal notes and valuable information in deceased stalkers' PDAs. All of this can be read in the "Diary" section of your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="diary_tutorial">
		<text>When you see a flashing book icon, it means that you've learned some new information. Open your PDA and check the "Diary" section to read it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_blocker_diary">
		<text>Sometimes you won't be able to access some territories: it's only made for your own safety and benefit. However, these areas will be unlocked eventually.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="faction_tutorial">
		<text>When a contact's marker is red, it does not necessarily mean they will shoot you on sight. If you approach with caution and assess the situation before attacking, you may find them willing to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="faction">
		<text>Faction relations</text>
	</string>
</string_table>