<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="bandit_cloak_description">
		<text>Regular black leather trench coat with light bulletproof. Has no special purpose other than to keep the wearer warm at night or protect him from a blind dog bite. Although the trench coat is not particularly comfortable, it is often used by bandits in the Zone - either because it allows them to hide in the dark or simply due to its "cool" appearance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_cloak_name">
		<text>Leather trench coat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Reinforced armor donned by the most adventurous of the Adidas worshipers. It features bullet protection comparable to armors of other factions, with a rather light weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit heavy armor BP-c "Viper"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_heavy_outfit_name_s">
		<text>BP-c "Viper"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_description">
		<text>Traditional outfit of bandits - a leather jacket with no sign of being bulletproof. According to rumors, the black skin is more reliable, however, such protection is woefully inadequate in the harsh conditions of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_description_m">
		<text>Common weak bandit body armor with mail plates sewn in its backing. Almost everyone can do it, but not everyone by far will have enough patience to.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_description_m2">
		<text>Common weak bandit body armor with two mail plates sewn in its backing. The real measure of patience and perseverance!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_name_m">
		<text>Mail jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_name_m2">
		<text>Double-mail jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Once used as standard by Clear Sky assault squads. The armor is capable of stopping a pistol bullet, while the wearer is also well protected from anomalies. After the collapse of the faction it's almost impossible to get a sample of the costume.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>"CS-3a" body armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_heavy_outfit_name_s">
		<text>CS-3a</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_light_outfit_description">
		<text>This body armor was once used for conducting search operations in areas of low anomalous activity. It's able to stop a pistol bullet, while also providing minimal protection from anomalous exposure. After the collapse of the faction it's almost impossible to get a sample of the costume.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_light_outfit_name">
		<text>"CS-1b" body armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_light_outfit_name_s">
		<text>CS-1b</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_regular_outfit_description">
		<text>The "CS-2" body armor was once used as a standard by Clear Sky patrols. It consists of a military bulletproof vest with a load bearing vest over it. After the collapse of the faction it's almost impossible to get a sample of the costume.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_regular_outfit_name">
		<text>"CS-2" body armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_regular_outfit_name_s">
		<text>CS-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_ultraheavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Once used as standard by elite Clear Sky assault squads. The armor is capable of stopping a pistol bullet, while the wearer is also well protected from anomalies. After the collapse of the faction it's almost impossible to get a sample of the costume.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_ultraheavy_outfit_name">
		<text>"CS-3b" body armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky_ultraheavy_outfit_name_s">
		<text>CS-3b</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>This early model of the Duty bodysuit is the Spetsnaz "SKAT-10" body armor modified for the Zone. The suit is capable of stopping a rifle bullet, however, this level of protection comes at the cost of its weight, bulkiness and virtually non-existent anomaly protection. The suit can be upgraded with a combat support system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9d "Duty Armor"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_heavy_outfit_name_s">
		<text>PSZ-9d</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Duty armor suit with enhanced parameters of protection against bites and cuts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Hunter's "PS5"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_reglar_outfit_description">
		<text>Produced by one of Kiev defense research institutes and commissioned by the Duty faction. It's as simple and reliable as the standard "PS5" model, but due to the new materials, it provides good protection from various harmful impacts, including firearm damage. The vest still needs some work because it has no breathing protection system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_reglar_outfit_name">
		<text>PS5 "Duty Suit"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_reglar_outfit_name_s">
		<text>PS5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>Wonderful protective suit for the Zone. Stalkers appreciate it because it combines excellent anomaly- and bulletproof qualities. It includes the PS5 suit and a closed cycle breathing system; provides quality bullet and splinter protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>PS5-M "Universal Protection"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_name_s">
		<text>PS5-M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_black_description">
		<text>Prototype of the "SSP-10" protective suit. There are rumors claiming it was in the Zone before the second explosion, however, there are many artifacts integrated; for example, the outer layer of the suit is covered in "Pellicles". Might've been used by employees of X-labs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_black_name">
		<text>"SSP-10" protection suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_black_name_s">
		<text>SSP-10</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_description">
		<text>"SSP-99" chemical protection suit specially designed for the Zone conditions. It is used by scientific expeditions and the stalkers who cooperate with them. It has integrated air-filtering and air-conditioning systems. It is heat and electricity resistant; provides good protection from radiation and biological anomalies. Not designed for combat, so it provides neither bullet, nor splinter protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_name">
		<text>"SSP-99" scientific suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_name_s">
		<text>SSP-99</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_freedom_outfit_description">
		<text>Modernization of regular exoskeleton. The use of lighter materials has reduced the weight of the suit and increased its durability. A lightweight helmet is included; it has a mount for a removable night vision device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_freedom_outfit_name">
		<text>"Freedom Keeper" exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_freedom_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Freedom Keeper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_description">
		<text>Military exoskeleton prototype. It never went into serial production due to its extreme cost and some design flaws. It is, however, produced in small batches in small illegal factories outside of Ukraine. This is a third generation exoskeleton. The design defects which used to decrease its mobility were eliminated and the armor was reinforced. Provides excellent bullet and splinter protection but a low level of anomaly protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_light_outfit_description">
		<text>Old Mercenary suit. Its design is based on the suit used by the special forces of the Western armies. It was supplied to the Mercs, however, they no more use such suits. Almost the whole batch has been sold to traders and stalkers; the latter rarely use these due to the lack of qualities providing the Zone threats protection, though the combat side is much better.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_light_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>There is chain mail sewn into the lining of the coat, which raises the level of protection against explodes and monster bites.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_light_outfit_name">
		<text>BP-a "Cobra" Merc suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_light_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Reinforced "BP-a"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_light_outfit_name_s">
		<text>BP-a "Cobra"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_description">
		<text>Suit of a Mercenary. Its design is based on the suit used by the special forces of the Western armies. Due to a special treatment of the fabric, the armor has a strengthened stability during the physical movement of its plates. The protective properties are slightly better then those of the "PSZ-7" military bulletproof suits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_name">
		<text>BP-b "Python" Merc suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_name_s">
		<text>BP-b "Python"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_10_description">
		<text>Army armored suit "SKAT-10" is designed for assault operations in areas of anomalous activity, specifically for the leaders of the military or military-stalkers squads. It includes a "PSZ-13" heavy military bulletproof suit and an integrated compensation suit. It provides perfect protection from bullets, although it significantly reduces the mobility of the wearer. Has a balanced but simple system of anomaly protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_10_name">
		<text>Armored suit "SKAT-10"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_10_name_s">
		<text>SKAT-10</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_9_description">
		<text>Army armored suit "SKAT-9" is designed for military-stalkers or military assault operations in areas of anomalous activity. It includes a "PSZ-12p" heavy military bulletproof suit and an integrated compensation suit. It provides excellent protection from bullets and splinters, although it reduces the mobility of the wearer. Has a balanced but simple system of anomaly protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_9_name">
		<text>Armored suit "SKAT-9"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_9_name_s">
		<text>SKAT-9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_outfit_description">
		<text>Suit of a Monolith soldier. Its protective properties are slightly worse then those of the "PSZ-9a" military bulletproof vest. Its structure is similar to the suit popular with neutral stalkers which combines a bulletproof vest and a radiation protection suit. It provides good protection from gunfire. The level of anomaly protection is low due to the absence of an air filtering system. Not used by stalkers because of heightened sensitivity to psi-effects: the one who wears it literally turns into a psi-emission receiver.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_outfit_name">
		<text>"Adept" Monolith suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Adept</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>Suit of a Monolith soldier. It basically is a combination of a standard Monolith suit, a closed-cycle breathing system, reinforcements for anomaly protection and against mechanical damage. Not used by stalkers because of heightened sensitivity to psi-effects: the one who wears it literally turns into a psi-emission receiver.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>"Preacher" Monolith suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_scientific_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Preacher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nauchniy_outfit_description">
		<text>Regular robe worn by scientists in their laboratories.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nauchniy_outfit_name">
		<text>Scientist's robe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_description_m">
		<text>This coat was taken off of the body of one of the stalkers who died in the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. Having laid a long time in the anomaly, the coat obtained the ability to speed up metabolism.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_name_m">
		<text>Anomaly leather jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_name_m_s">
		<text>Anomaly jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_novice_description">
		<text>Ordinary thick jacket with very light bulletproof. It slightly increases bullet and splinter protection but doesn't protect from anomalies and other affects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_novice_name">
		<text>Leather jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_stalker_jacket_description">
		<text>Though anyone wearing this jacket can be easily taken for a newbie, there's no reason to underestimate it: the "Sunrise" suit parts are sewn into it, along with a polymeric lining, both helping to survive in anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_stalker_jacket_name">
		<text>Stalker jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="protection_outfit_description">
		<text>High quality modified "SSP-99" suit. It provides increased body protection from bullet and splinter damage. Designed for the guards working with scientific expeditions, it provides good protection from radiation and biological anomalies. Resistant to chemically aggressive environments and other effects dangerous to the body.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="protection_outfit_name">
		<text>"SSP-99M" protection suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="protection_outfit_name_s">
		<text>SSP-99M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This suit was produced by one of Kiev defense research institutes and represents an excellent alternative to stalker hand-made suits. It is an excellent combination of an bulletproof vest, a closed cycle breathing system and an integrated system of anomalous field suppression. Due to the perfect choice of the materials, it is a good choice. The only disadvantage is the price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>"SEVA" suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_name_s">
		<text>SEVA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="soldier_outfit_description">
		<text>Regular suit worn by the soldiers of the Zone. It protects from armor-piercing bullets rather good, however, there's no sign of any anomaly protection. All the downsides aside, it's a pleasure to wear such a suit as it's perfectly sewn. The suit is a bad choice for deep raids but can be useful during a skirmish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="soldier_outfit_name">
		<text>"Berill-1" armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="soldier_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Berill-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specnaz_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>The fabric of the suit is saturated with a streptozoidal lotion, which speeds up the healing of wounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specnaz_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Healing "Berill"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_description">
		<text>"Berill-5M" special forces suit modified for the Zone environment. It is designed for assault operations in areas with medium background radiation, thus the anomaly protection is pretty weak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_name">
		<text>"Berill-5M" armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Berill-5M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_gasmask">
		<text>Gas mask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_gasmask_descr">
		<text>Regular plastic and rubber gas mask, used for filtering air for radioactive particles and poisonous substances. Widely used by rookies and veterans of all factions due to its universal functionality. Does not provide any physical protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_hardhat">
		<text>Advanced steel helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_hardhat_descr">
		<text>Desperately outdated steel army helmet without any additions. Provides no protection against anomalies or radiation, but can deflect bullets. This helmet was never particularly popular in the Zone, except for use in brief armed conflicts between factions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_helmet">
		<text>Steel helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_helmet_descr">
		<text>Regular metal helmet. It can't protect from anomalies, but a small caliber bullet could actually be stopped. Not a popular thing in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_military_specops">
		<text>"Sphere-12" helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_military_specops_descr">
		<text>Aluminum/titanium helmet with a cloth exterior that comes with pockets for additional steel armor pieces and an armor face mask. "Sphere-12" is normally used as part of a combination for military special ops that includes "SKAT-9" body armor. Not popular in the Zone because of its cost, but this helmet provides the maximum head protection possible. Due to the unique system of metal grids and current collectors has a high protection from psi-effects. It has built-in respirator and first generation night vision device. Comes with electronics slots.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_military_stalkers">
		<text>"Sphere-12M" helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_military_stalkers_descr">
		<text>Aluminum/titanium helmet with a cloth exterior that comes with pockets for additional steel armor pieces and an armor face mask. "Sphere-12M" is normally used as part of a combination for military-stalkers that includes "SKAT-9" body armor. Quite popular in the Zone thanks to its built-in gas mask and first generation night vision device, as well as providing the maximum head protection possible. Comes with electronics slots.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_military_specops_heavy">
		<text>"Sphere-13" helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_military_specops_heavy_descr">
		<text>Aluminum/titanium helmet with a cloth exterior that comes with pockets for additional steel armor pieces and an armor face mask. "Sphere-13" is normally used as part of a combination for military special ops that includes "SKAT-10" body armor. Not popular in the Zone because of its cost, but this helmet provides the maximum head protection possible. Due to the unique system of metal grids and current collectors has a high protection from psi-effects. It has built-in respirator and first generation night vision device. Comes with electronics slots.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_military_stalkers_heavy">
		<text>"Sphere-13M" helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_military_stalkers_heavy_descr">
		<text>Aluminum/titanium helmet with a cloth exterior that comes with pockets for additional steel armor pieces and an armor face mask. "Sphere-13M" is normally used as part of a combination for military-stalkers that includes "SKAT-10" body armor. Quite popular in the Zone thanks to its built-in gas mask and first generation night vision device, as well as providing the maximum head protection possible. Comes with electronics slots.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_protective">
		<text>"Screen" helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_protective_descr">
		<text>Light helmet with an airtight visor intended for protection from anomalies. Judging by the design, the helmet is made by the same defense research Institutes as the "SEVA" bodysuit. Its intended use may very well be in combination with military suits for operations in highly anomalous areas.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator">
		<text>Respirator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_respirator_descr">
		<text>Regular plastic respirator used for filtering air for radioactive particles and poisonous substances. Widely used by all stalkers. Lighter then normal gas mask but its protection is also worse. Does not provide any physical protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_tactic">
		<text>Tactical helmet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_helm_tactic_descr">
		<text>Western model of a tactical helmet that lacks camouflage. It is not known how it made its way into the Zone. The helmet is designed to provide a squad leader with strategic superiority over the enemy via its many scanners and satellite communications devices, which have not been installed in this particular helmet. Comes with multi-layered Kevlar protection and armored elements to protect electronic components. Includes a respirator and a first generation night vision device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_exo_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Military battle exoskeleton prototype. This version has greatly enhanced armor which affects the mobility. Rarely used by stalkers because of the price, however, the level of protection is simply enormous. It provides excellent bullet and splinter protection but low level of anomaly protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_exo_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Battle exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_exo_heavy_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Battle exo</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_exo_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Experimental version of a military exoskeleton prototype. In this version, a mechanism was added to increase movement speed and jump height.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_exo_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Exoskeleton M1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Stalker suit made by craftsmen of the Zone. Being the heavy version of the "Sunrise-3" suit, it features medium-class body armor combined with rubberized plastic and Kevlar plates. Offers good protection against small arms. This is a good suit too take on a deep raid into the depths of the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_heavy_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Upgraded "Sunrise-4" suit. The former owner of this thing was a real tourist and appeared to go to very difficult hiking trips on the verge of human endurance. He knew how to correctly distribute the weight that he carried, and which things to give preference to. The coat pockets and the educated choice of the backpack allow its owner to carry a heavy weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>"Sunrise-4" suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_heavy_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Heavy tourist's suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_heavy_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Sunrise-4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_light_outfit_description">
		<text>Lighter and cheaper variant of the common stalker suit. It's a combination of a light cheap bulletproof vest and of a rubberized fabric suit of low quality. After the success of the suit "Sunrise-3" was released even more easy and cheap version. Because of its cheapness and availability it is popular among stalkers on the outskirts of the Zone, although as a whole this variant is highly insufficient even for shallow raids and operations within the outskirts of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_light_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Upgraded "Sunrise-3" suit. The former owner of this thing was a real tourist and appeared to go to very difficult hiking trips on the verge of human endurance. He knew how to correctly distribute the weight that he carried, and which things to give preference to. The coat pockets and the educated choice of the backpack allow its owner to carry a heavy weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_light_outfit_name">
		<text>"Sunrise-5" suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_light_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Tourist's suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_light_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Sunrise-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_medium_outfit_description">
		<text>Stalker suit made by craftsmen of the Zone. The third version of the successful Sunrise suit series was the base of the Duty and Freedom faction suit. It's an effective combination of light body armor and rubberized plastic, further enhanced by installing Kevlar plates. It offers good protection against small caliber bullets. A good suit overall, but not a good choice for raids deep into the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_medium_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Personal Ghost's "Sunrise-3". There is a legend that he never carries any medkits; everything heals on him like on a dog. Some say it's caused by an unusual suit which he once got from an anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_medium_outfit_name">
		<text>"Sunrise-3" suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_medium_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Ghost's suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_medium_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Sunrise-3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_protoexo_outfit_description">
		<text>Field sample of a military exoskeleton. Assembled on the basis of the suit "Sunrise-2" and parts of the exoskeleton. Due to the increase of capacity has been improved bulletproof vest. However, the low protection from anomalies, unreliable design and expensiveness in service made this model unpopular among stalkers. In spite of this, stalkers produce it in small amounts in sweatshops.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_protoexo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton prototype</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Reinforced stalker suit produced by gunsmiths of the Freedom faction. It is made up of a medium military bulletproof vest plated with reinforcing zirconium elements which provide good protection from rifle bullets and splinters from medium and long range. The material of the suit consists of two layers: specially treated leather and fabric with asbestos yarn. The suit provides good protection from radiation and various weak anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>"Freedom Shield" armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Freedom Shield</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_description">
		<text>Light stalker suit produced by the gunsmiths of the Freedom faction. It consists of a light military bulletproof vest with reinforcing Kevlar plates and can protect from weak weapons. The fabric of the suit is treated with a special mixture which increases anomaly activity resistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_name">
		<text>"Freedom Wind" suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Freedom Wind</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_medium_outfit_description">
		<text>Lightly reinforced stalker suit produced by the gunsmiths of the Freedom faction. Slightly heavier than the light suit, it offers an increased protection level, thanks to the usage of more sophisticated materials validating the need for additional kilograms.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_medium_outfit_name">
		<text>"Freedom Guardian" stalker suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_medium_outfit_name_s">
		<text>Freedom Guardian</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Metal wire mesh is integrated into the suit for protection from electric/magnetic fields and radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>"Freedom Wind" M2 suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_outfit_name_m1_s">
		<text>Freedom Wind M2</text>
	</string>
</string_table>