<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>	
	<string id="Mutants">
		<text>Animals and mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="General">
		<text>General information</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Crow">
		<text>Crow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_crow_general">
		<text>The only bird species to have survived in the Zone, enduring increased radiation levels and effectively avoiding anomalies. While the army pilots need to rely on complex detectors to avoid gravitational disturbances, the crow seems to rely on its own senses for that - a mystery that drives ornithologists and biologists mad. Various theories attempting to explain the phenomenon exist, all of them pointing to a highly specialized development of the bird's brain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_crow_meat_name">
		<text>Crow meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_crow_meat_desc">
		<text>Edible but not so tasty.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Blind">
		<text>Blind dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_blind_general">
		<text>Several generations of the dog species have lived and died since the catastrophe. Each was more affected by the Zone than the previous one. Rapid mutation lead to a vast improvement in previously peripheral abilities, frequently at the expense of primary ones. The most notable biological change was the loss of sight, paired with an uncanny development of smell. As it turned out, blind cubs survived in the Zone as well as normal ones, if not better. As a result, the common dog quickly became extinct in the Zone, giving way to a new breed - that of blind dogs. The animals instinctively identify and avoid anomalies, radiation, and other invisible dangers that plague the Zone. Like their wild ancestors - the wolves - blind dogs hunt in packs. An encounter with a large group of these animals can be dangerous even to an experiences and well-armed stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail">
		<text>Dog tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail_description">
		<text>The resistance of mutant dogs' skin to electricity and chemical agents has long been the subject of scientific attention. Since the animal's tail is almost completely free of fat tissue, it is especially suited for lab examination.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Pseudodog">
		<text>Pseudodog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_pseudodog_general">
		<text>Despite the name, the Pseudodogs evolved directly from wolves. The animals inhabiting the forests at the time of the catastrophe gave rise to one of the Zone's most dangerous mutant species. Pseudodogs are about as different from mutant dogs as wild wolves differ from poodles. The creatures mark and guard their territory carefully, attacking anyone stupid enough to venture onto their land on sight. Lightning-fast reflexes, uncanny dexterity and razor-sharp teeth make the pseudodog a formidable enemy for large mutants and well-armed stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail">
		<text>Pseudodog tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail_description">
		<text>The resistance of mutant dogs' skin to electricity and chemical agents has long been the subject of scientific attention. Since the animal's tail is almost completely free of fat tissue and this particular breed in particular is especially suited for lab examination.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Flesh">
		<text>Flesh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_flesh_general">
		<text>Like most other living creatures in the Zone, the domestic pig also underwent serious biological changes since the day of the catastrophe. It seems the genes responsible for metabolism were especially affected in this case. Mutant pigs, known simply as Flesh among the stalkers, are one of the most vivid examples of the Zone's disastrous perversion of nature. Mutant pigs developed a protective layer of scales and exoskeletal plates. Their regeneration potential increased several times, as did the complexity of their nervous system. Just like a normal pig, a Flesh is an omnivore and may attack a stalker if hungry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye">
		<text>Flesh eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye_description">
		<text>The mutated, swollen eye of the Flesh acquired a number of strange characteristics, the most useful of which is the ability to regenerate the lens. The specifics of the process are unknown, although such discovery would most certainly revolutionize modern medicine. You can play your part in scientific development by selling Flesh eyes to scientists for their experiments.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Boar">
		<text>Boar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_boar_general">
		<text>A massive, mutated animal, reaching 1.5 meters at the shoulder. The Zone boar's aggressiveness and ability to survive surpass by far those of its relatives outside the contaminated area. Radiation and anomalies left their mark on the physical appearance of the animal as well: its fur is entirely gone in some places, and long and bristly in others. The hooves have evolved into sturdy, sharp claws, the pupils became colorless, and the boar's bald head is marred by pigmentation disorders and deep wrinkles. Zone boars are quite resistant to radiation and can stay in heavily contaminated areas for longer periods of time. They usually charge at their victims, trying to knock them over and then rip them to shreds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg">
		<text>Boar hoof</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg_description">
		<text>The hoof of a wild boar is used by scientists for manufacturing of some medicines, the most widespread of which are anti radiation drugs.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Cat">
		<text>Cat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_cat_general">
		<text>Cats that have succumbed to the Zone's influence. Over the years, they have developed abilities that are very dangerous for Stalkers, namely their speed, added size, strength, and large claws. They are very aggressive and are mostly solitary. Cases of them living in small groups have also been recorded. They are somewhat aggressive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_cat_head_name">
		<text>Cat head</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_cat_head_descr">
		<text>If you kill a cat, you may remove its head, and then sell it as trophy to the traders. It makes for a fine display in mansions...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Tushkano">
		<text>Rodent</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_tushkano">
		<text>In fact these animals are not related to jerboas, although there is a distinct resemblance. Attempts at determining the exact species from which this Rodent evolved have so far been unsuccessful, although its ancestor must have been a gregarious rat. Reaching up to 40cm at the shoulder, the animal is far more dexterous, aggressive and ravenous than its cousin, the rats. Mutant ratwolves live mainly in basements of destroyed buildings, feeding on everything they can get their teeth in, from plants to careless stalkers. Occasionally a pack of ratwolves will attack and kill large animals and mutants, tearing them apart before they can escape.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_tushkano_tail_name">
		<text>Rodent tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_tushkano_tail_descr">
		<text>A tail of Rodent, one of the most annoying things in the Zone besides the lack of toilet paper. Lanky, smelly, with some spots of hair, it won't fetch a great price, provided someone will buy one in the first place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_rat_corpse_name">
		<text>Rodent corpse</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_rat_corpse_descr">
		<text>Nothing special. A cheap and easy way to get you some food. The taste is bad, and maybe it holds some radiation, but at least it's "fresh".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rat_meat_name">
		<text>Rat's meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rat_meat_desc">
		<text>Edible but not so tasty.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Bloodsucker">
		<text>Bloodsucker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_bloodsucker_general">
		<text>Experienced stalkers describe this semi-legendary beast as a tall, hunched humanoid with a mess of tentacles where its mouth should be. According to those who saw it and lived to tell the tale, the creature uses its tentacles to cling to the victim's throat, paralyze it, and suck it dry of blood. A dry, mummified shell is all that's left of what used to be a living human being. The most astounding feature of the Bloodsucker, however, is its ability to become invisible. Countless dead or missing stalkers are said to have perished in the merciless grip of a Bloodsucker. The lucky few who have survived an encounter tell spine-chilling tales of marshes and subterranean areas haunted by the Zone's version of Count Dracula.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw">
		<text>Bloodsucker tentacles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw_description">
		<text>Bloodsucker tentacles contain a special gland producing a ferment capable of dissolving the skin and simultaneously preventing blood from clotting. Discovering the ferment's composition could be the cornerstone of a whole series of great medical advances.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Chimera">
		<text>Chimera</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_chimera_general">
		<text>1.4m in length. The result of genetic experimentation. Extremely cunning, strong and fast creature; it hides, flanks, and circles around to attack its prey from behind. It has a doubled system of internal organs and an additional brain, both which make this creature problematic to kill, at the very least. It can also heal itself by regeneration of lost cells. It has almost no natural predators in the Zone and is considered the Zone's greatest hunter. Its movement and agility is reminiscent of a panther. The only worthy opponents for this creature are the Bloodsucker and the Pseudogiant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_chimera_eye_name">
		<text>Chimera eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_chimera_eye_descr">
		<text>This is a rare monster part in the Zone, and since its really hard to kill those beasts, traders will pay you a lot for those body parts. If you have time to take them to scientists, they might give you even more, if they find it useful for experimenting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_chimera_hand_name">
		<text>Chimera hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_chimera_hand_descr">
		<text>A hand cut off from one of the most dangerous beasts in the Zone - the Chimera. The paper-thin skin is covered with coarse, short hairs like on a dog, and the steel-hard claws look as if they would flail a man effortlessly.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Pseudogiant">
		<text>Pseudogiant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_pseudogiant_general">
		<text>The Pseudogiant resembles a massive, drop-shaped abdomen with a pair of disproportionately large limbs. The limbs are arms and legs at the same time. The creature uses them to move around and grab its victims. An adult Pseudogiant can weigh up to two tons and stand 2 meters tall. Their clumsy appearance might be deceiving, since they can move very rapidly if needed. Their muscles are exceptionally powerful and their bones are as hard as steel. The creature's brain is protected by a sturdy (up to 10 centimeters thick) skull, while many complex functions are controlled by the spinal medulla. Another astonishing feature of the beast is its ability to create local shock waves, which damage all living things in the vicinity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_giant_eye_name">
		<text>Pseudogiant eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_giant_eye_descr">
		<text>An intact eye plucked out of the skull of a the Zone's flesh and bone tank - the Giant. Much bigger than a normal human eye, it's capable of picking up the faintest traces of light, one a human eye would be blind to.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Poltergeist">
		<text>Poltergeist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_poltergeist_general">
		<text>Supernatural in the eyes of some, invisible creatures haunting the deeper reaches of the Zone, usually haunting old, abandoned buildings. Nothing is known about their origin, although rumors in circulation claim they are spirits of stalkers hit by a massive wave of radiation. Their mysterious appearances and disappearances seem to correspond to the Poltergeist legend, hence the name. Known encounters with Poltergeists are quite diverse in fact: from mischievous laughter and blood-chilling howling, to deadly fireballs appearing out of nowhere. Unfortunately, all information about the Poltergeist phenomenon originates from unclear and contradictory stories of questionable validity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_poltergeist_brain_name">
		<text>Poltergeist brain</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_poltergeist_brain_descr">
		<text>Brain of a Poltergeist. Very valuable stuff in the zone. It will prove that you really killed one, and also scientists will pay you a lot for it, since they are experimenting with unnatural monster bodies. They want to find out where their abilities come from.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Snork">
		<text>Snork</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_snork_general">
		<text>It seems these creatures were human at some point, though it is difficult to imagine what conditions could turn a human being into such disgusting beast. Snorks are insane creatures leading a beast's life and differing little from other carnivorous monsters in the Zone. They move on all fours in long jumps, constantly sniffing the ground in hope of picking up the scent of prey. They hunt carefully, in a calculated manner, frequently setting up ambushes. Thanks to its uncanny reflexes and powerful muscles, the snork can approach the victim, pin it down in one long, accurate jump, and tear it to shreds in a matter of seconds. Strips of army uniforms and other clothing are occasionally found on their bodies. It stands to reason that they are all that's left of missing military stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg">
		<text>Snork foot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg_description">
		<text>Snork feet contain a huge number of highly elastic tendons. This explains the beast's ability to make those unbelievably long jumps.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Controller">
		<text>Controller</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_controller_general">
		<text>A human mutated by severe exposure to psi-emissions, usually seen near to the center of the Zone. Possesses good perception and the ability to control the behavior of less developed creatures with its altered neocortex. Mature specimens are capable of assuming direct control of several human brains at a time. This is a ferocious enemy, and even the most experienced stalkers are afraid of encountering it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_controller_foot_name">
		<text>Controller foot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_controller_foot_descr">
		<text>It's the foot of the Controller. This beast has strong heels, and traders can craft strong knife blades from them. Valuable item in the Zone, since it's cheap and the perfect solution for a hunting knife. They are also exported to a few collectors who pay ridiculous sums of cash for such knives.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Burer">
		<text>Burer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_burer_general">
		<text>Ugly, red-skinned dwarves born from genetic experiments. They usually inhabit dark underground tunnels as their sensitive eyes can go blind instantly from the sun's bright illumination. In their underground lairs, they set traps for stalkers and scientists. They try to block all exits using large pieces of trash, debris, or furniture. Burers have powerful arms that they use to rip apart their prey. Their personalities are very unstable; nervousness, fear, and sudden outbursts of aggression makes them behave erratically. They have a developed sixth-sense and the ability to use telekinesis. Their sixth sense allows them to see a possible threat without direct visual contact and establish its position. Telekinesis allows it to manipulate large objects at a distance, hurl them at an enemy, and use pyrokinesis to emit blasts of intense heat at opponents when no objects can be thrown. Their abilities, personalities, and intelligence makes them one of the most dangerous creatures in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_burer_hand">
		<text>Burer hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_burer_hand_description">
		<text>The hands of Burers have obtained a myriad of attributes, most positive of which seems to be the flesh's extremely high resistance to radiation. Exactly how this is achieved is unknown; it repels gamma rays as if it were made of lead. You can do your part for the scientific community by selling all hands of Burers that you find to scientists for further research.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Fracture">
		<text>Izlom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_fracture_general">
		<text>The result of a genetic experimentation, or left-behind people twisted by the Zone's unstable environment. Supposedly has a hypotrophic limb that enables telepathy. This creature is very cunning; in most cases, it hides its telepathic limb under a cloak. From afar, it resembles a hunchbacked hermit, and it sometimes deliberately lures unsuspecting stalkers with a request or conversation. As soon as the stalker turns around, it stands up straight and attacks with its hypotrophic limb. If a stalker shares some food with this creature, then it might share some very interesting information about the Zone, or tell a story. It eats rats, dogs, Fleshes, and sometimes people. It can sometimes follow a solitary stalker, robbing him while he sleeps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_izlom_arm_name">
		<text>Izlom arm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_izlom_arm_descr">
		<text>Izlom is a half-mutated creature in the Zone, and its arm is very strong. There are legends about them, since some of them still can speak, and if you won't kill Izlom, he can tell you stories about his life, and the Zone. Well, if you take his arm, the scientists will pay you a lot, if you can bring them one in good condition!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Karlik">
		<text>Dwarf</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_karlik_general">
		<text>A new species of mutants about which nothing definitive is known. The prominent theory is that a Dwarf is the result of a human's genes that underwent severe degeneration because of unidentified toxins. Despite being considerably short, the strength of a Dwarf can rival that of a young Bloodsucker.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="mutant_karlik_ear_name">
		<text>Dwarf ear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_karlik_ear_descr">
		<text>Mutant's part of unknown properties. There are rumors if left to dry up and then grounded into a fine powder, it can be used to treat baldness. However, most of the times, that story is only heard very late at night around those campfires with a lot of scattered empty vodka bottles left laying nearby. </text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Swampbeast">
		<text>Swampbeast</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_swampbeast_general">
		<text>A strange beast that lurks in swampy areas of the Zone. It's a grotesque creature that prowls around on its hands, its lower body a stump without any legs. Due to their lack of humanoid stature and height, they rely on surprise attacks to knock stalkers off their feat and quickly bash in a stalker's skull. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_swampbeast_nose_name">
		<text>Swampbeast nose</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_swampbeast_nose_descr">
		<text>The olfactory organ of the clumsy Swampbeast is nothing to scoff at. According to the eggheads at Lake Yantar, the swampbeast nose has more olfactory receptors than a dog.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Zombie">
		<text>Zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_zombie_general">
		<text>The Brain Scorcher strips its victim of mind and reason, leaving only an empty, mindless shell. The brainless bodies then turn into zombies, following only the most basic instincts, wandering aimlessly around the Zone without weapons or clothing. Zombies are little more than sluggish walking corpses, caring only about food and sleep. They eat and drink just about anything they can get their claws on, hence they are virtually soaked in radiation and toxic waste. Usually they roam the Zone without any apparent purpose or just lie corpse-like in abandoned buildings. However, as soon as they sense the presence of a human being, they attack immediately. Experienced stalkers have learned to avoid them if they can.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_zombie_hand">
		<text>Zombie hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_zombie_hand_description">
		<text>The characteristics of zombie flesh are currently unknown. You can do your part for the scientific community by selling them to scientists for study. Rumors say that the Brain Scorcher affected not only the minds of those caught in it, but also their bodies, to a point. That could explain why zombies and zombified stalkers shrug off extremely high levels of radiation as if it was nothing.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Rat">
		<text>Rat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_rat_general">
		<text>Ordinary rats can be found anywhere in the Zone. They are usually hiding in old buildings, basements and abandoned undergrounds. They fear of humans, but in large packs they are more brave and agressive as they move fast, it's real hard to shoot them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="RatWolf">
		<text>Ratwolf</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Tark">
		<text>Tark</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_extinct_description">
		<text>Mutated horse species now extinct. They were systematically hunted down by Duty as Freedom used them in the early days of the Zone as cavalry. No more data available.</text>
	</string>	
	
	<string id="mutant_karlito_hand_name">
		<text>Karlito hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_karlito_hand_descr">
		<text>Hand severed from one of the rarest encounters in the Zone - a braun Karlito. One can feel the hardness of the skin, as if it's made from steel.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>