<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="anom_detector_advanced">
		<text>Advanced anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_detector_advanced_descr">
		<text>Advanced anomaly detector needs to be attached to the belt and turned on to operate correctly. Compared with the simple anomaly detector, it can locate different anomalies, and the range of detection is much higher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_detector_elite">
		<text>Elite anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_detector_elite_descr">
		<text>Device intended for detection of anomalous zones as well as hotbeds of radioactive pollution. Needs to be attached to the belt and turned on to operate correctly. The range of detection is very high. Combining the simple and advanced detectors in one package, this one is the best way to stay alive in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_detector_simple">
		<text>Simple anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_detector_simple_descr">
		<text>Device for detecting anomaly fields and disturbances; notifies about anomalous presence with a sound. Needs to be attached to the belt and turned on to operate correctly. This is the cheapest type among all detectors thus the range of detection is poor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="antchemical_booster">
		<text>Antidote</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anti_psy_booster">
		<text>Psi-block</text>
	</string>
	<string id="antirad_booster">
		<text>Radioprotectant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-heavy">
		<text>Heavy stalker gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-light">
		<text>Light stalker gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-medium">
		<text>Medium stalker gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="beer_chmielnitskoe_name">
		<text>"Chmielnitskoe" beer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Binocul">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular_electron_descr">
		<text>Japanese binoculars. Light, has high magnification lenses, mechanical zoom, and can be retrofitted with electronic components. Its main drawback is the price being extremely high.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular_electron_name">
		<text>Binoculars "Vitacom" 6-12x35</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular_electron_nm">
		<text>Binoculars "Vitacom"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular_modif_descr">
		<text>Enhanced version of common military binoculars. Its main advantage over foreign competition is increased service life and lower price. The main drawbacks are its weight and poor ergonomics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular_modif_name">
		<text>Army binoculars BKFTs 6-12x35</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular_reg_descr">
		<text>Military binoculars made in USSR. It is equipped with stadiametric rangefinder and an independent focus-adjusting mechanism. Its main advantage over foreign competition is the price. The main drawback is the weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular_reg_name">
		<text>Army binoculars BKFTs 4-8x35</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular_reg_nm">
		<text>Binoculars BKFTs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_deadcity_maps_desc">
		<text>Detailed map of the Dead City including Mercs' positions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_deadcity_maps_name">
		<text>Dead City map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctors_key_desc">
		<text>Doctor's key to a secret stash in Pripyat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctors_key_short_desc">
		<text>Doc's key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="coagulant_booster">
		<text>Vinca</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Detect1">
		<text>Anomaly detector (DA-2)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Devic">
		<text>Instruments and Devices</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-PDA">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-torch">
		<text>Flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-torch-adv">
		<text>Advanced flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-torch-eco">
		<text>Low-voltage flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_af_merger_name">
		<text>Artifact merger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_af_merger_descr">
		<text>Latest achievement in scientific experiments allowing to combine artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_antidote_descr">
		<text>Antidote for the X-Virus. It was developed in the X-18 Labs in 1989. This is highly valuable and rare item in the Zone. It also boosts immunities during blowouts which can be very handy if you find yourself far from a shelter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_antidote_name">
		<text>X-Virus antidote</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_antirad_descr">
		<text>Reduces the effects of radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_antirad_name">
		<text>Antiradiation drugs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bandage_descr">
		<text>Bandages which are mostly used to stop bleeding.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bandage_name">
		<text>Bandages</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bandage2_descr">
		<text>Bandages used by the Duty faction. Contain special chemicals to help stop bleeding better than normal ones.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bandage2_name">
		<text>Duty bandages</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bread_descr">
		<text>Hard to say who manages to bake these loaves in the Zone, but the bread isn't contaminated and is perfectly edible. Well, at least none of the Stalkers have complained about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bread_name">
		<text>Bread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_conserva_descr">
		<text>Canned food from an army warehouse raided by stalkers. The best-before period hasn't expired yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_conserva_name">
		<text>"Tourist's Delight"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_antchemical_booster">
		<text>The IP2 antitoxin is a complex drug comprising several antidotes, including metoclopramidum, pyridoxine, thiamine, riboxin and other pharmaceuticals. The drug is used to inject a range of antibiotics to neutralize natural poisons, together with synthetic poison absorbers, into the bloodstream. IP2 is not particularly popular in the Zone, as most stalkers rely on a gas mask and a protective suit, there are still those who have a pack of this antidote stashed away. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_anti_psy_booster">
		<text>Drug that blocks avalanche-like nerve impulses. Consumption induces short-term loss of all emotion. Used exclusively in the Zone to counteract the effects of anomalous psy-fields. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_antirad_booster">
		<text>B190 Indraline radioprotectant, included in medkits, issued to nuclear power plant personnel. Used in the Zone instead of the excessively toxic PC1 cystamine hydrochloride, repeated use of which often caused death. Reduces the effects of gamma radiation on live tissue. Best consumed before exposure, as effects are not instant. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-heavy">
		<text>Protective suit. Weight: 18kg. Details: Protects the body from "Jelly", "Burnt Fuzz" and physical damage. The torso and back are protected by built-in bio-metallic plates. The suit is equipped with an airtight, reinforced plastic helmet and two oxygen bottles. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-light">
		<text>Protective suit. Weight: 8kg. Details: Protects the body from weak anomalies and physical damage. Equipped with an oxygen mask. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-medium">
		<text>Protective suit. Weight: 12 kg. Details: Protects the user from "Jelly", "Burnt Fuzz" and physical damage. Equipped with an airtight helmet and an oxygen bottle. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_sci2">
		<text>Red S.C.A.P.E suit with an airtight helmet. Weight: 11kg. Description: Protects the body from fire, acid, toxic gas, various anomalies, "Burnt Fuzz" and physical damage. Equipped with two oxygen bottles. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_beer_chmielnitskoe">
		<text>Since 1907 this popular mark fills the stomachs of all citizens of the Ukraine alike. Grown on fields of Storosinavsky and Chmielnisky, these hops and barley are cleaned to the highest standard to grant you the most pleasure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_coagulant_booster">
		<text>Ukrainian Vikasolum - an artificial equivalent of vitamin K. The main purpose of this drug is to increase blood coagulation speed. In great demand among stalkers who want slow-healing wounds and lacerations inflicted by mutants to close up faster. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_binocul1">
		<text>Military field binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect1">
		<text>Device for detecting anomaly fields and disturbances. Notifies of their presence with a sound. Needs to be attached to the belt and turned on to operate correctly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-pda_rosf_task">
		<text>PDA previously owned by a Duty member.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-pda_secret_task">
		<text>PDA previously owned by a scientist.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-PDA1">
		<text>Personal Digital Assistant - indispensable in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-PDA2">
		<text>This PDA contains some info regarding a customer who ordered an expedition to this lab and his contact details through GPS encrypted mobile; however, it's quite hard to trace the owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1">
		<text>Powerful flashlight. Quite useful in areas with insufficient lighting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1_m1">
		<text>Powerful flashlight. Battery recharge time has been reduced thanks to a modernized transformer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch2">
		<text>Military grade flashlight, with and a much wider and brighter beam, at the expense of a greater battery drain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch3">
		<text>Flashlight made by the Zone's native technicians in response to the deficiency of batteries. By lowering the voltage, the power consumption dropped dramaticaly, at the obvious expense of light intensity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_energydrink">
		<text>Excellent energy drink consisting of caffeine, taurine and a mixture of rejuvenating vitamins. Just the ticket when you're too tired to push forward!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_vodka1">
		<text>Vodka made by the GSC company. Goes down easily and tastes very good, but for obvious reasons should be enjoyed in moderation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_vodka2">
		<text>Vodka used by Loxotron to deaden his senses. Highly dangerous, has equal parts alcohol and ammonia.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit1">
		<text>All-purpose medkit. Used to treat injuries of various types and severities - wounds, burns, poisonings, etc.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit2">
		<text>Specialized medical set to fight against physical damage and blood loss. In it is included a component for blood coagulation, antibiotics, immunal stimulators, and painkillers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit3">
		<text>Medical set designed for the Zone. The set includes means of healing wounds as well as means of eliminating radionucleodes from the body. Prevents the development of radiowave sickness and lowers the dose of accumulated radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_pripiat_beer">
		<text>Barkeep always knew the day would come that he would see his special family prescription adorning a magnificent product. It is a highly concentrated beer made from the best of local vegetation and some secret ingredients.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_weight_booster">
		<text>The main component of this product is an anabolic androgen, an artificial steroid, the chemical composition of which resembles testosterone. Often used by stalkers during long raids to reduce muscle fatigue. Significantly increases weight-carrying capacity. The effects of the drug are long-lasting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_gasmask_descr">
		<text>Gas mask is worn over the face to protect the wearer from inhaling airborne pollutants and toxic materials. The mask forms a sealed cover over the nose and mouth, but may also cover the eyes and other vulnerable soft tissues of the face. During the blowouts, the air becomes polluted, and you need to wear gasmasks, otherwise you will get radiation infection, and you will die in a few minutes. It can be useful in underground areas too, since they were locked down a long time ago.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_gasmask_name">
		<text>Gas mask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_guitar_descr">
		<text>Stringed musical instrument resembling the lute or the violin, but larger with six strings. Used by stalkers all over the Zone while sitting around campfires.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_guitar_name">
		<text>Classic guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_harmonica_descr">
		<text>From the "Blues" to the Soviet Union anthem, this humble reedwind instrument will funnel any melody that comes to you, and, unlike your audience, the harmonica does not mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_harmonica_name">
		<text>Harmonica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_battery_descr">
		<text>Ordinary alkaline batteries. Exactly what you need when your flashlight is not shining.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_battery_name">
		<text>Alkaline batteries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_hand_radio_descr">
		<text>Regular military hand radio, a transmitter/receiver device used by Stalkers to communicate with their friends</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_hand_radio_name">
		<text>Hand radio</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_kolbasa_descr">
		<text>Made from a mix of chicken and soya, the "diet" sausage is often, due to the lack of other options, a stalker's breakfast, lunch, and dinner at the same time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_kolbasa_name">
		<text>Diet sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_korn_conserva_descr">
		<text>Because of it's high protein and carbohydrate content, corn has been an important nutritional resource for thousands of years. Today, corn has less starch and is sweeter. A good thing about corn is that frozen and canned corn has about the same nutritional value as fresh corn.\n If the corn is not cooked shortly after it is purchased, then it should be stored in refrigerator. Refrigeration helps the corn retain its sugar and vitamin C content. Canned corn can be stored unopened for up to 10 years!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_korn_conserva_name">
		<text>Canned corn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mineral_water_descr">
		<text>Nothing much to say about it. It's imported clean water from the out lands. If you are not an alcoholic, then you will probably like it, even if its taste is stale. It won't reduce radiation, but will restore your stamina, health, and reduce hunger much more than any vodka.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mineral_water_name">
		<text>Mineral water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_nonstop_energy_drink_descr">
		<text>The label reads: "This drink will instantly rejuvenate your mind and body". This drink is similar to the common energy drink, but also heals you, reduces radiation somewhat, reduces hunger, and gives you more endurance. Of course it's a bit expensive, but the price is worth it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_nonstop_energy_drink_name">
		<text>"NonStop" Energy Drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_olives_conserva_descr">
		<text>Generous serving of canned goodness for a starving stalker. It contains beef stew, olives with aspic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_olives_conserva_name">
		<text>Beef stew</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_peanut_conserva_descr">
		<text>The peanut or groundnut (Arachis hypogaea) is a species in the pea family Fabaceae native to South America. Perfect snack when coupled with a bottle of beer or vodka in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_peanut_conserva_name">
		<text>Peanut snack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_pheremones_descr">
		<text>Mutant pheromones: said to calm various species for short periods of time when doused over one's body.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_pheremones_name">
		<text>Pheromones</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_10_descr">
		<text>Ordinary 10 Rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_10_name">
		<text>10 Ru</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_100_descr">
		<text>Ordinary 100 Rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_100_name">
		<text>100 Ru</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_1000_descr">
		<text>Ordinary 1000 Rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_1000_name">
		<text>1000 Ru</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_50_descr">
		<text>Ordinary 50 Rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_50_name">
		<text>50 Ru</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_500_descr">
		<text>Ordinary 500 Rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_500_name">
		<text>500 Ru</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_5000_descr">
		<text>Ordinary 5000 Rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rubles_5000_name">
		<text>5000 Ru</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_sardinia_conserva_descr">
		<text>Generic term applied broadly to any of various small, soft-boned, salt-water fish such as Sprats and young Pilchards and Herrings. These tiny fish are iridescent and silvery and swim in huge pools, usually near the water's surface. Fresh sardines are available on a limited basis during the summer months, usually only along the coast where they're caught. In general, their fatty flesh is best when grilled, broiled or fried. In the United States, sardines are more commonly found salted, smoked or canned, either in oil, tomato sauce or mustard sauce. Some are packed as is, while others are skinned, boned and sold as fillets. The name is thought to have come from the young pilchards caught off the coast of Sardinia, which were one of the first fish packed in oil.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_sardinia_conserva_name">
		<text>Sardines</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_sleeping_bag_descr">
		<text>Ordinary sleeping bag. It won't replace a warm bed and a mother's cuddle, but at least it's impermeable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_sleeping_bag_name">
		<text>Sleeping bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_tushenka_conserva_descr">
		<text>Full of proteins and fat, this is really juicy stuff. Exactly what a hungry stalker needs. It's not the tastiest thing, because it's made out of of rats. However, if you closed your eyes and thought about chicken, you wouldn't know the difference.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_tushenka_conserva_name">
		<text>Meat stew</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vodka_absolut_descr">
		<text>Imported vodka. Clean and crisp with aromas of faint lemon pie. A taste of baked bread adds an extra dimension to the martini-quality six-parts-to-one dry vermouth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vodka_absolut_name">
		<text>"Absolut" Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vodka_cmuphob_descr">
		<text>Imported vodka from Finland. Was a championship winner of "Best taste of year".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vodka_cmuphob_name">
		<text>"Cmuphob" Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vodka_hemupob_descr">
		<text>Special vodka from a well known trader in Switzerland. 40 percent proof and high clarity made it a leader in the worldwide market. The label reads - "We live only once, fill your time with pleasure."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vodka_hemupob_name">
		<text>"Hemupob" Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vodka_nemiroff_descr">
		<text>Imported vodka with a refined subtle taste. It is active, strong, and at the same time, a smooth beverage with a long pleasant aftertaste.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vodka_nemiroff_name">
		<text>"Nemiroff" Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vodka_smirnoff_descr">
		<text>Imported vodka. It was awarded 90 points from a beverage tasting institute, so it must be good! The moderately bodied Smirnoff vodka is reminiscent of lemon, white pepper, charcoal, bold textures and smoky sensations that are followed by a burst of rich flavors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vodka_smirnoff_name">
		<text>"Smirnoff" Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_wine_descr">
		<text>Ukrainian table wine of highest quality and taste which has been stored for almost 2 years in special conditions. Old tradition of the Crimean always made it the best choice on the market.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_wine_name">
		<text>"Mossandra" wine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_yantar_food_descr">
		<text>Beef stew served with vegetables. Perfectly preserved and delicious. You can store it for up to 3 months after purchase. If you are tired of canned foods, this one was made for you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_yantar_food_name">
		<text>Permanent meal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_drink_name">
		<text>Energy drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Equipment">
		<text>Gear and Food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Food">
		<text>Food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medi">
		<text>Medicaments</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medkit">
		<text>Medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medkit_army">
		<text>Army medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medkit_scientific">
		<text>Scientific medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_bug_desc">
		<text>Voice recorder disguised as a useless thermometer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="out_bug_name">
		<text>Bugging device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pripiat_beer_name">
		<text>"Pripyat" beer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="repair_kit_descr">
		<text>Screwdrivers, pincers, screws, grindstone... all you need in a small and compact repair kit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="repair_kit_name">
		<text>Repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Sci2">
		<text>Scientific EXP-4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector">
		<text>Anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector_descr">
		<text>Intended for the detection of anomalous zones as well as hotbeds of radioactive pollution.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector0">
		<text>Homemade detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector0_descr">
		<text>The simplest device of handcraft there is. Stalkers craft these using the most widespread components, most of which are found in any old radio. Powered by the integrated battery; reacts to found artifacts with turbulent sound interference. Unfortunately, the ability of receiving signal from frequencies available in the Zone has been lost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1">
		<text>Detector "Echo"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1_descr">
		<text>The latest experimental device which, according to the constructors, should identify artifacts. Many mistakes have been made in its design, therefore the device is not really popular. The list of artifacts available for detection is very limited.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1a">
		<text>Detector "Ocher"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector1a_descr">
		<text>Special, custom-made variant of the "Echo" detector. It features most of the possible upgrades from the base model, and has been given a nice ocher color, hence its name.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2">
		<text>Detector "Bear"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2_descr">
		<text>This last generation anomalous activity detector can be used to locate anomalous formations and has a panel, which not only indicates the direction of artifacts, but also measures the distance to them. To switch to artifact search mode, open the device's front cover. Unfortunately, the device is programmed with a somewhat outdated list of detectable artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3">
		<text>Detector "Veles"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3_descr">
		<text>Next generation scientific detection scanner. Thanks to three modernized detection chambers, the position of artifacts is shown on a special display screen. When closed, the device registers only radiation and anomalies. To switch to artifact search mode, open the front LED display. When in search mode, the detector is capable of locating all artifacts known to science.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector4">
		<text>Detector "Svarog" prototype</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector4_descr">
		<text>Prototype of an expanded functionality anomalous formations (artefacts) scanner. The artifact search mode, which can be activated by opening the front LED display, has been modified to detect anomalous formations currently unknown to science.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_gd5">
		<text>Smoke grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nightvis_0">
		<text>NVD "Blindness"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nightvis_0_descr">
		<text>Night vision device with no sign of quality. The fact there's a blurred black-and-white label of a fairly known manufacturer on the device pretty much means it was illegally assembled inside of some Chinese basement. "Blindness" is called so by stalkers due to the lack of any other marking. Though the definition of quality is not applied to this NVD in any way, it's quite popular in the Zone because of its low price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nightvis_1">
		<text>NVD-01 "Vampire"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nightvis_1_descr">
		<text>Entry-level, cheap, Chinese personal 'Gen1' night vision device. It offers some basic help in the dark, but the picture quality leaves a lot to be desired. Supposedly named after a WW2 German 'Gen0' night vision device, it quickly acquired an ironic meaning - that you'll be as blind as a bat anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nightvis_2">
		<text>1PN42 "Blue Moon"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nightvis_2_descr">
		<text>Advanced, 'Gen2', domestic personal night vision device that probably 'fell off of a military truck'. It provides a good picture quality and moderately good brightness. A true must-have for any Stalker on a night expedition, as you'll have to have a 'once in a blue moon' luck to survive without a pair of these!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nightvis_3">
		<text>ANV-01 "North Star"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_nightvis_3_descr">
		<text>Advanced modification of a military night vision device, performed by the scientists stationed in the Lake Yantar bunker. By adding a sliver from the 'Flash' artefact, the goggles gaines an unrivaled picture quality, along with an eerily bright, white picture. The nickname it was given was supposed to be poetic, describing how these goggles are supposed to guide their wearers just like the North Star, but rumors are that the one that came up with it was a fan of 'girly chinese cartoons'.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Vodka">
		<text>"Cossacks" Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weight_booster">
		<text>Hercules</text>
	</string>
</string_table>