<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<!--Springboard-->
	<string id="st_af_medusa_name">
		<text>"Jellyfish"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_medusa_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Springboard" anomaly. This gravitational artifact attracts and absorbs radioactive particles, reducing the effects of radiation on the body. Very common in the Zone and is unofficially used outside the Zone for treating acute radiation sickness in exceptional circumstances.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_name">
		<text>"Crystal Flower"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Springboard" anomaly. This artifact is made up of a granite-like stone deformed by an extreme gravitational force, resulting in a crystallized formation that has not been explained by science to date. Can provide moderate protection against psi-emissions. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_stone_flower_name">
		<text>"Stone Flower"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_stone_flower_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Springboard" anomaly. It is a stone that is close in its characteristics to granites, with inclusions of metallic compounds that give a beautiful play of light. Stalkers say that viewing this artifact is remarkably reassuring, but in fact the artifact has a field that stabilizes the mental processes of the one holding it. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_hedgehog_name">
		<text>"Hedgehog"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_hedgehog_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Springboard" anomaly. Artifact made out of soft-to-touch spines. It is able to generate around itself a gravitational field, which locally reduces the effect of the force of gravity. Widely used stalkers to reduce the weight of the load carried in the backpack. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_night_star_name">
		<text>"Night Star"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_night_star_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Springboard" anomaly. It is the result of gravitational influence on ordinary dust. The artifact literally glows from the overwhelming energy. When in contact with a living organism, it significantly strengthens his tissues. It is extremely interesting for scientists and other researchers of the Zone's activity. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_name">
		<text>"Shell"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Springboard" anomaly. When wearing this artifact, the chance of radiation damage is dramatically reduced, because the artifact directly repels about a quarter of all radioactive particles around it.  It is an expensive and rare thing in itself. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_spring_name">
		<text>"Spring"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_spring_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Springboard" anomaly. A rare artifact possessing a powerful field. Gravitational processes occur in the artifact field constantly, lowering, then increasing the pressure in its center. When in contact with a living organism, it partially transfers this property to it. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
<!--Vortex-->
	<string id="st_af_vyvert_name">
		<text>"Wrenched"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_vyvert_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Vortex" anomaly. Incomprehensibly, it generates a magnetic field around itself, which reduces the force of the impact to the person. The artifact itself is quite heavy. It occurs frequently, and therefore does not have a high price among stalkers. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gravi_name">
		<text>"Gravi"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gravi_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Vortex" anomaly. Unknown to science rock, which has the property of repelling radionuclides at a great distance. In other words, it does not help from the radiation accumulated in the body, but it will prevent further irradiation. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_knot_name">
		<text>"Knot"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_knot_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Vortex" anomaly. This bizarrely-shaped artifact appears in places with increased gravitational activity. Acting as a kind of sponge that absorbs radioactive elements, this artifact doesn't provide protection from outside radiation but protects from radioactive particles that have already made their way into the body.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_chert_name">
		<text>"Chert"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_chert_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Vortex" anomaly. "Chert" is formed from metallic substances exposed to prolonged gravitation. This makes it capable of sustaining an anti-gravitational field, and many stalkers use it to reduce the weight of their backpacks. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_name">
		<text>"Goldfish"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Vortex" anomaly. A true paradox. At even the weakest application of heat, the artifact has a strong radiation emisssion. At the same time, the artifact itself prevents the penetration of radiation from outside. Popular among stalkers and scientists. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_soother_name">
		<text>"Soother"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_soother_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Vortex" anomaly. The result of an interaction between a large number of gravitational fields, Goldfish produces its own powerful internally directed gravitational field, which renders items within its range almost weightless. This artifact is most effective for reducing carried weight, which explains why it is always in great demand. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_brown_beads_name">
		<text>"Brown Beads"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_brown_beads_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Vortex" anomaly. One of the many artifacts of the "beads" type. Has a powerful gravitational field, as well as directly affects living organisms on contact, locally accelerating metabolism. When worn on the belt, it greatly accelerates the digestion of food, causing the wearer to have a brutal appetite. However, it helps to carry a huge amount of things. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
<!--Whirligig-->
	<string id="st_af_stone_blood_name">
		<text>"Stone Blood"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_stone_blood_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Whirligig" anomaly. It is a rather ugly reddish formation from compacted and curved polymerized remains of plants, soil and bones. Pretty common and weakly effective. Initially, it did not show properties. Later it turned out that the artifact interacts with the wearer's skin and absorbs some of the shockwaves during explosions. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_meat_chunk_name">
		<text>"Meat Chunk"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_meat_chunk_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Whirligig" anomaly. Has a very ugly shape. It is formed from the muscle tissue of bodies that have fallen into the anomaly. Its effect is similar to the effect of the artifact Stone Blood: it also absorbs a portion of the shockwaves during explosions, but it does it much more effectively. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_giblets_name">
		<text>"Giblets"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_giblets_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Whirligig" anomaly. It is often of small size, of a bizarre shape, and its properties are of great interest to stalkers. After all, the artifact directly protects against radiation, creating a protective field around itself and the wearer. Has no negative properties. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cuttlefish_name">
		<text>"Cuttlefish"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_cuttlefish_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Whirligig" anomaly. Far from being aesthetic, it prevents outside radiation from permeating the body. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_heart_name">
		<text>"Heart"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_heart_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Whirligig" anomaly. It radiates pleasant warmth and soothes. This property is caused by a special field that the artifact generates around itself. Inside this field, all neural impulses slightly change their structure. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_beads_name">
		<text>"Gold Beads"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_beads_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Whirligig" anomaly. One of the many artifacts of the "beads" type. Stimulates very rapid recovery of cells after their damage. Heals even the most serious wounds, because of what is very popular among stalkers of all groups. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pupil_name">
		<text>"Pupil"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pupil_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Whirligig" anomaly, in areas of increased thermal activity. In addition to the strange name, it has other interesting properties. The artifact is capable of absorbing a huge amount of radiation. After finding it, there is a difficult choice - to sell for a lot of money, or to keep it.</text>
	</string>
<!--Burner-->
	<string id="st_af_drops_name">
		<text>"Droplets"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_drops_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burner" anomaly at high temperatures. Outwardly it looks like a blackened teardrop formation with a glossy surface, covered with cracks. Makes living organisms more resistant against bullets. It is not expensive. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_quartz_name">
		<text>"Quartz"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_quartz_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burner" anomaly. This artifact is formed in anomalous zones with intense thermal activity. Actively consumes excessive heat, remaining cool to the touch throughout. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_red_beads_name">
		<text>"Red Beads"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_red_beads_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burner" anomaly. Much about this artifact remains a complete mystery to scientists. At the same time, it is known for certain that emissions produced by pulses in its thicker sections force blood in open wounds to clot quicker, forming a protective scab. One of the most noticeable effects of this artifact is the increased speed of bleeding control. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fireball_name">
		<text>"Fireball"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fireball_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burner" anomaly. Even though Fireball is a thermal artifact, it can be handled without fear of being burned. This artifact is valued for its ability to maintain a temperature of 75 degrees Fahrenheit within a small radius, virtually regardless of its surroundings. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_eye_name">
		<text>"Eye"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_eye_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burner" anomaly. This artifact, which resembles the human eye, considerably increases the body's metabolism, helping wounds heal quicker. Experienced stalkers say that the Eye also brings luck. Emits radiation. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_name">
		<text>"Flame"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burner" anomaly. This artifact forms in areas of high thermal activity. Produces powerful infra-red emissions, which intensify metabolic processes, healing wounds before its bearer's very eyes. As this artifact is very rare, it is extremely valuable. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mercury_ball_name">
		<text>"Mercuryball"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mercury_ball_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burner" anomaly. The second name is Mercury. Named after the planet and the element. The outgoing glow is really like the burning hell of the planet Mercury, and the liquid in the inner chamber is a unique, more toxic and heavy type of mercury that occurs only in the Zone. Despite the toxicity, the artifact is able to heal the disease or damage. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_crystal_name">
		<text>"Crystal"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_crystal_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burner" anomaly. Artifact occurs infrequently, and the finder is considered a lucky one. Greatly rebuilds neuroprocesses of the nervous system after a powerful psi-attack. It has the form of crystals, from which it was given the name. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
<!--Electro-->
	<string id="st_af_sparkler_name">
		<text>"Sparkler"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sparkler_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Electro" anomaly. A fairly common and inexpensive artifact. However, this does not make it useless. This artifact is valuable primarily for ecologists, since it provides additional protection against small discharges of electricity. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_accumulator_name">
		<text>"Accumulator"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_accumulator_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Electro" anomaly. The composition of this artifact includes electrostatic elements, but scientists have yet to identify the exact physical conditions required for its formation. The artifact is popular in the Zone and valued by its residents and visitors for its energizing properties, although it can tire the body out through prolonged use. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_twinkle_name">
		<text>"Twinkle"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_twinkle_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Electro" anomaly. A bright representative of the electrostatic family of artifacts, this artifact can smooth fluctuations in electric field density. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_flash_name">
		<text>"Flash"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_flash_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Electro" anomaly. This electrostatic artifact is a powerful absorbent of electricity, which it later discharges. Flash is capable of protecting its bearer from electric shocks of up to 5,000 volts. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_jewel_name">
		<text>"Jewel"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_jewel_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Electro" anomaly. This artifact used to be considered trash, devoid of any useful properties. However, scientists recently discovered that if kept in constant contact with the body, it has an excellent stimulating effect on the nervous system. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_lightning_name">
		<text>"Lightning"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_lightning_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Electro" anomaly. The artifact is able to absorb a large number of discharges of electricity, electrifying the air around itself, thereby protecting the wearer. Very valuable among the seekers of artifacts and researchers. Has a great price. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_moonlight_name">
		<text>"Moonlight"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_moonlight_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Electro" anomaly. This unique electrostatic artifact can resonate under the influence of psi-waves. Stalkers have learned to fine-tune the artifact so that it resonates in opposite phase to the main source of emissions, thus fully or significantly neutralizing their effects. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ice_name">
		<text>"Snowflake"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ice_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Electro" anomaly. At first glance, this artifact resembles Kolobok. Some claim that it actually is Kolobok, its properties reinforced by exposure to a powerful electric field. Thanks to its unique properties, the artifact can significantly increase the bearer's muscle tone. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_discharge_name">
		<text>"Discharge"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_discharge_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Electro" anomaly. At first glance it resembles a frozen discharge of electricity, which is why it got its name and how strange it is - its effect is just as similar. Has a great price and is very much appreciated among stalkers. When placed on the waist, it stimulates the muscles of the body with small discharges of electricity, thereby enabling them to run for long distances with minimal loss of energy. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
<!--Witches' Jelly-->
	<string id="st_af_slime_name">
		<text>"Slime"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slime_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. The anomaly forms under itself a protective layer, which prevents it from dissolving the surface on which it is located. With a small accumulation of this layer, it is transformed into an artifact. Has a nasty, slimy texture. Slightly reduces the incidence of cuts and bites. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_bile_name">
		<text>"Stone Bile"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_bile_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. A yellow-green formation of compressed and fossilized plants, soil and animal bones. Can partially neutralize chemical poisons. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_soul_name">
		<text>"Soul"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_soul_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. A unique organic artifact with properties just as unique. Somehow it increases the body's overall recovery rate from damage of any kind, without accelerating the accumulation of toxins. Thanks to its effects and attractive appearance, this artifact is a valuable collector's item. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slug_name">
		<text>"Slug"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_slug_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. It emits stabilizing waves capable of reducing the effectiveness of mental attacks of mutants and anomalies, for which it is valued amongst stalkers. Cool and slimy in touch. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_flesh_chunk_name">
		<text>"Flesh Chunk"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_flesh_chunk_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. This organic artifact consists of deformed, mutated animal tissue. When placed in a chemically contaminated area, Meat Chunk transforms the airborne chemicals into a mucous fluid. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mica_name">
		<text>"Mica"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_mica_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly with the rarest, extreme set of physical conditions. It represents a few squashed "Slugs". The result is a semi-transparent solid object. Absorbs toxins from the environment, which helps stalkers in clusters of acid anomalies. Artifact expensive and rare. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_name">
		<text>"Bubble"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. A compound of several hollow organic formations, this artifact emits a gaseous substance that can neutralize radioactive particles inside the body without harming it. Because of its effectiveness, this artifact is in great demand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pellicle_name">
		<text>"Pellicle"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_pellicle_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Witches' Jelly" anomaly. The artifact is so rare that many researchers do not even realize that such a substance can exist under natural conditions. Maintains a constant temperature in a radius of a couple of meters, while the skin becomes less sensitive to high temperatures, and the body is less susceptible to pain from burns. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
<!--Rusty Hair, Ameba-->
	<string id="st_af_thorn_name">
		<text>"Thorn"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_thorn_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Rusty Hair" and "Ameba" anomalies. Quite common and cheap, but, nevertheless, a very interesting artifact for both scientists and ordinary stalkers. Its main feature is to create a small field with a radius of up to a meter, which hinders the movement of alpha and gamma particles. For a person, this is not dangerous, but the need for food is reduced. Has no negative properties.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_crystal_thorn_name">
		<text>"Crystal Thorn"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_crystal_thorn_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Rusty Hair" and "Ameba" anomalies. It is infrequent and rather effective, thus it deserves a stable price in the artifact market. When worn on the waist, it acts on the skin of the wearer, making it less vulnerable to bites and cuts. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sea_urchin_name">
		<text>"Sea Urchin"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sea_urchin_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Rusty Hair" and "Ameba" anomalies. Even until now, how this artifact works is a mystery, but it slows the movement of any radioactive particles in the air, including large ones, like dust. Has no negative properties.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_battery_name">
		<text>"Battery"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_battery_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Rusty Hair" and "Ameba" anomalies. When and how it appeared - it's unknown. Initially, it was considered a trinket, suitable only for sale. But later it became known that when placed on the belt, it creates an electromagnetic field on top of the human skin, thereby absorbing a huge part of the impact force. Rare, expensive and useful - the perfect combination for the artifact. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_green_beads_name">
		<text>"Green Beads"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_green_beads_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Rusty Hair" and "Ameba" anomalies. One of the many artifacts of the "beads" type. The internal mechanics of the artifact are unknown. It is rare and very valuable amongst stalkers, collectors and scientists, therefore it has a great price. Creates an invisible, dense field that delays a significant part of penetrating psi-waves around the user. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fungus_name">
		<text>"Toadstool"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_fungus_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Rusty Hair" and "Ameba" anomalies. This oddly colored artifact may seem dangerous. It emits a disgusting smell, and because of that it got that name. Interacts with the skin of large living organisms, making it less vulnerable to blunt and cutting wounds, such as mutant bites. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
<!--Burnt Fuzz-->
	<string id="st_af_horn_name">
		<text>"Horn"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_horn_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. Weakly studied artifact. When worn on the waist, it has a positive effect on brain function, namely suspicious calmness occurs. Allows you to recover after intense psi-emissions. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_kolobok_name">
		<text>"Kolobok"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_kolobok_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. A relatively rare artifact which forms in areas contaminated with chemicals, Kolobok is highly valued for its ability to heal wounds of any kind in mere minutes. For unknown reasons, scientists are spreading rumours among stalkers that the artifact interacts with the bearer's genetic code. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ivory_name">
		<text>"Ivory"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_ivory_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. Quite a strange artifact, even considering the origin. It looks almost like ivory - except that you can observe the unexplained apparent energy on the inner walls of the artifact. When it is worn on the belt, it positively affects the bones of a person, making them more resistant to shocks. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sphere_name">
		<text>"Sphere"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_sphere_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. It emits a pleasant, toning warmth, the skin of the wearer of this artifact becoming more coarse and stronger with time. It doesn't protect from bullets, but the protection from explosions will be much higher. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_glass_name">
		<text>"Firefly"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_glass_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. "Firefly" interacts with fields unknown to science, considerably speeding up regeneration of tissue and organs in living beings, as well as normalizing metabolic processes. This artifact can literally get a badly wounded stalker back on his feet in seconds. Unfortunately, "Firefly" is extremely rare. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_spine_name">
		<text>"Spine"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_spine_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. Pretty viscous. However, it hardens on contact with some chemical reagents. It has the property of periodically lowering the temperature of the surrounding air around itself. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blue_beads_name">
		<text>"Blue Beads"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blue_beads_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. One of the many artifacts of the "beads" type. The principle of operation has not been fully studied. In fact, it is a kind of filter: any poisonous particles, falling into the zone of action of the artifact, are immediately absorbed by it. Rare and expensive. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_chestnut_name">
		<text>"Chestnut"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_chestnut_descr">
		<text>Born in the "Burnt Fuzz" anomaly. Scientific laboratories are ready to pay huge sums to those who will gain such an artifact and give them to study. According to preliminary analysis, the artifact somehow interacts with tendons and bones, thereby preventing the dangerous consequences of explosions. Has a great price and rare. Emits radiation.</text>
	</string>
<!--Other-->
	<string id="st_af_green_parasite_name">
		<text>"Green Parasite"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_green_parasite_descr">
		<text>This is a "half-product" of an artifact transmutation. Scientists believe that this type of artifact can be used as an ingredient for artifact transmutations but there is no way to confirm that. Further research is needed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blue_parasite_name">
		<text>"Blue Parasite"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_blue_parasite_descr">
		<text>This is a "half-product" of an artifact transmutation. Apparently the blue color comes from microbes which interfered with the transmutation process. Scientists believe that this type of artifact can be used as an ingredient for artifact transmutations but there is no way to confirm that. Further research is needed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_compass_name">
		<text>"Compass"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_compass_descr">
		<text>A rare artifact - it's been several years since one was found. The artifact can locate gaps in anomaly fields. It is believed that it can help one traverse the most complex anomaly fields completely unharmed. However, very few know how to handle it properly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_purple_beads_name">
		<text>Purple Beads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_purple_beads_descr">
		<text>Some kind of "Gold beads". Nobody knows how this artifact works. It allows stalkers run faster and jump higher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psy_zone_heart1_name">
        <text>"Psi-zone Heart"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psy_zone_heart1_descr">
        <text>The artifact lying in the middle of a large psi-zone may generate around itself the psi-field as a defense mechanism, and possibly works in symbiosis with the psi-zone, feeding it energy. Upon contact with the artifact the psi-zone instantly disappears. It may interest scientists or buyers of expensive artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_hell_name">
        <text>"Hell"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_hell_descr">
        <text>An unique artifact found at the bottom of the huge gravitational anomalies. It has strong healing properties and can appear only at the confluence of variety of circumstances and with a very small probability, which makes it very expensive, but very useful. It will interest scientists or buyers of expensive artifacts, although you can afford to leave.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_nogravity_name">
        <text>"Levitron"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_nogravity_descr">
        <text>An unique artifact has strong gravitational properties. In the selection have formed a number of gravity anomalies. The conditions for the birth of an artifact are not known. It may interest scientists or buyers of expensive artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_compass_full_name">
		<text>Charged "Compass"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_compass_full_descr">
		<text>Unlike the usual ones the stalkers find, this "Compass" is charged and has the useful properties. It may help find the way out of any trap in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-supernova_name">
		<text>"Supernova"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-supernova_descr">
		<text>The brightest artifact in the Zone. It's easily seen from afar, but hard to get. It's contact drives owner insane.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-psy_fish">
		<text>Charged "Goldfish"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-psy_fish_descr">
		<text>After the long stay in the area of high psi-emissions artifact got new properties and became a psi-emitter itself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_tp_gen_name">
		<text>"Generator"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_tp_gen_descr">
		<text>An unique artifact. Has a strong gravitational properties and protective mechanism. Upon contact with a living organism creates a "chain" of spatial distortion, endless teleports the one who picked up the artifact. The stoping of teleportation is possible only by throwing the artifact.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>